<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://library.gwu.edu/ead/lac0006.xml">lac0006.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Anne T. Lawrence Mine Workers Oral History collection, <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1972-1973</date>
 <num>LAC0006</num></titleproper><author>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</publisher><address><addressline>2130 H Street NW</addressline><addressline>Washington 20052</addressline><addressline>speccoll@gelman.gwu.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-01-18 11:51:00 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid written in <language encodinganalog="language">English</language></langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Anne T. Lawrence Mine Workers Oral History Collection</unittitle>
    <unitid>LAC0006</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">1 Document Box, 2 Boxes containing 60 Audio Cassettes, 1 Bound Volume</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1973" type="inclusive">1972 March - 1973 January</unitdate>
    <physloc id="aspace_f888d69348871fb525465c62d5e591dd">Materials may be stored off-site, and may require additional retrieval time.  Please contact the Special Collections Research Center for more information.</physloc>
    <abstract id="aspace_f13e61ad60754452da0824c6a4ecd4e9">This collection contains the oral history cassette tapes from Anne T. Lawrence's Mine Workers Oral History Project.</abstract>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <prefercite id="aspace_c57785cc3c17e59e819229678c6a75bd">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Please cite unpublished materials in the following way:</p><p>Please provide the title and date of item, catalog number (if applicable it will be found written on the folder), name of the collection, name of the repository, and location of the repository. </p><p>Example:
James Oglethorpe to the Trustees, 13 January 1876, RG0001 Series 1, Box 4, Folder 3.  Records of the Board of Trustees, Special Collections Research Center, Gelman Library, The George Washington University, Washington, D.C.</p>  </prefercite>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_d59fcec33b42f9347bb92e1dfcf4c625">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Anne T. Lawrence Mine Workers Oral History Collection was a "Youthgrant" project from the National Endowment for the Humanities to the Miner's Voice, an independent newspaper for rank and file miners published in Charleston, WV.  This collection contains the audio cassette oral histories carried out by Anne Lawrence, transcriptions, and the bound and printed final report.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_136abd7a395f9574b75310c1b48d7ac4">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>In the 1920s-1930s, the central Appalachian coal fields were the scene of heavy industrial warfare. The coal operators believed that maintaining the open shop while under pricing their competitors would preserve their share of a dwindling market. The United Mine Workers (U.M.W.A.) needed to solidify the coal fields or face potential losses of previously unionized mines and operators. After World War I, union membership was at an all time high but the companies began implementing open shop techniques: labor injunctions, "yellow-dog" contracts, company spies, imported strikebreakers, company unions, and bribing local authorities. The union had always been strong in the hard coal fields in eastern Pennsylvania and the "Central Competitive" soft coal fields of Illinois, Ohio, Indiana, and western Pennsylvania. Due to lack of rail facilities and infrastructure, the southern fields of West Virginia, Virginia, Kentucky, and Tennessee, were late to develop and the union did not have a historical presence. As the demand for coal leveled off, the industry became plagued with chronic overproduction. Wages not protected by the union fell with the price of coal.
In that economic market, the operators paying non-union wages maintained a competitive advantage over the union mines. </p><p>As more of the union mines were either bankrupting or repudiating their contracts, the U.M.W.A. decided that consolidating the Appalachian coal fields was of primary concern. Coal operators in that region, backed by private detective organizations, such as the Baldwin-Felts Agency, intimidated union organizers, blacklisted, fired, or physically assaulted miners, and maintained a strict control of the working conditions. In addition, operators typically paid the salaries of local sheriff offices, typically in the tonnage rate. With travel difficult, miners were very isolated from other mines and other labor movements. </p><p>Violence between the coal operators and miners during that time was extreme. Countless union organizers and sympathetic miners were murdered and beaten and eventually retaliated. The Matewan Massacre in Mingo County, West Virginia; the Battle of Blair Mountain in Logan County West Virginia; and the Battle of Evarts in Harlan County, West Virginia are all examples of this working class violence. The skirmishes mostly ended with the National Industrial Recovery Act of 1933 and the efforts of then U.M.W.A. president John L. Lewis. </p>  </bioghist>
  <userestrict id="aspace_df4fe6e99fdf5896bf25c5f05706b9a5">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Some material may be copyrighted or restricted. It is the patron's obligation to determine and satisfy copyright or other case restrictions when publishing or otherwise distributing materials found in the collections.</p>  </userestrict>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_f7d54eb2d8efa02f4bbc930f2f2274ab">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <arrangement id="aspace_d7116c140adb0bfd78a5a3ff07120844">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Organized into 1 series: Oral History Audio Cassettes.</p>  </arrangement>
  <odd id="aspace_43b2499662b0924f75ae84d3ea78d47e">
    <head>General</head>
  </odd>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh2005003151" source="lcsh">West Virginia Mine Wars, W. Va., 1897-1921</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh2005003304" source="lcsh">Labor disputes--West Virginia</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh2005004319" source="lcsh">Blair Mountain, Battle of, W. Va., 1921</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref1_irm" level="series"><did><unittitle>Oral History Audio Cassettes</unittitle><unitid>Series 1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 March 5-October 3</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0aef013e18077f6c7bfbf3f007a12154"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The Oral History Audio Cassettes include topics of mine operations during a period of heavy labor unrest. Topics include "Yellow-dog" contracts, blacklisting, wage gouging, strikes, corruption, and protests. There are discussions of union organizing with the United Mine Workers of America, the American Federation of Labor, the Congress of Industrial Organizations and the effects of the National Industrial Recovery Act of 1933 and the efforst of John L. Lewis. There are discussions of violence from the local sheriffs, strike busters, private detectives such as the Baldwin-Felts Agency, coal miners and coal operators. Counties discussed are Harlan and Letcher Counties in Kentucky, and Logan, Boone, McDowell, and Mingo Counties in West Virginia.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_86d500043d9e9c8f76528a654fcd815b"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Series is arranged alphabetically by last name.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref2_oyp" level="file"><did><unittitle>Henry Clay Pettry Interview
</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 September 13</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_995e9738cae3f5c144e2d7dbece2f911" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_c6b523bc962a974bd56a7caab0b93231" parent="aspace_995e9738cae3f5c144e2d7dbece2f911" type="cassette">44</container><container id="aspace_732226dc61da9ad7f68a8638bfca20d3" label="Audio" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_a9ce04e6492070c249030279bf8a56c2" parent="aspace_732226dc61da9ad7f68a8638bfca20d3" type="cassette">43</container></did><odd id="aspace_021eda7bf261bbd8c79f3b68d72cba6b"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 13 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_a5ea27c5d3ef19d94778d3889878c6bc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Henry Clay Pettry lived in Lawson, West Virginia. Brother of Bill Pettry, U.M.W.A. District 17 Vice President, who shot Logan County Sheriff Don Chafin in 1919. Mr. Pettry discussed the lead up to and the events after the March on Logan and the Battle of Blair Mountain, living conditions in mining towns, and the efforts to organize union activity.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref3_gn2" level="file"><did><unittitle>John Wilburn Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 September 2</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_e9cbab1d160c522436bf6b9727e08b44" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_348e4c25b00a0ab64e933ec0d79ebf38" parent="aspace_e9cbab1d160c522436bf6b9727e08b44" type="cassette">56</container></did><odd id="aspace_8ff4fc7f02303f18d63d9f62b51f01bd"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 19 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_f1925f3f00b8cb7341dd084850c31ac4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>John Wilburn lived in Julian, West Virginia. He was convicted in Charles Town, West Virginia, along with Bill Blizzard, and several other union organizers, of murdering Deputy Sheriff John Gore during the Battle of Blair Mountain. Mr. Wilburn discussed the entire situation from the beginning, including the Matewan Massacre involving Sid Hatfield, the Baldwin-Felts Agency, and Ed Chambers, and the resulting violence in Logan County.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref5_e1t" level="file"><did><unittitle>Grace Jackson Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 July 25</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_c514c62e87b42dd913437b4290f597b4" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_cc7f8e0d865004d59492222b693061fb" parent="aspace_c514c62e87b42dd913437b4290f597b4" type="cassette">33</container></did><odd id="aspace_49b94655f8e99a2c0daa70fada9b2d7a"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 23 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_d12eb372200880c2c7133d98360538ce"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Grace Jackson lived in Eskdale, West Virginia. A very self sufficient woman, Ms. Jackson participated in all union organization in Logan County. She discussed the highly prosperous days of the coal operators, and what economic opportunities were available to the women at that time. She talked of the Battle of Blair Mountain from a supporter's standpoint.</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_6aced78c277dd660aa17cf0ef0ece388"><head>Link to transcript</head><p>A transcript of the audio file may be found here: https://archive.org/details/LAC0006_s1_PooleHoward_transcript <p> <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:title="PDF document" ns2:href="https://archive.org/details/LAC0006_s1_PooleHoward_transcript">https://archive.org/details/LAC0006_s1_PooleHoward_transcript</extref></p></p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref7_wlo" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lena Blizzard Harlow Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 August 9</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_b62a13b80392158379f0796f6898fde2" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_a1485c6a439dfd325995d33979e2bdb3" parent="aspace_b62a13b80392158379f0796f6898fde2" type="cassette">25</container></did><odd id="aspace_d5e8cdd24d0262ba7795ca63bbd4c3dd"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 31 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_5eee9709daed0052686b6ae8a9a875bf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Lena Blizzard Harlow lived in Ohley, West Virginia. Sister of Bill Blizzard, organizer of the Battle of Blair Mountain. She discussed her family's involvement and the point of view that union organization did not take hold due to the miner's selling out.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref11_8z5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Frank Blizzard Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">circa 1972</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_bb438f6f9717249bd881dcd817edcdcd" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_30b9c552ba414453728829f1d2a15e6f" parent="aspace_bb438f6f9717249bd881dcd817edcdcd" type="cassette">2</container></did><odd id="aspace_2fc31349d15abe77c7a4a084d6bc398d"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 34 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_10f013147b4661ecf23e71bdbfe103dd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Frank Blizzard lived in Ohley, West Virginia. He was the youngest brother of Bill Blizzard. He was too young to participate, but retold the story of the Battle of Blair Mountain.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref13_ank" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mary Payne Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 August 9</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_0be3c21dd57e6a9f449ac2348bd3ea44" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_474d89e9904dbe872f0ed34c62e09af1" parent="aspace_0be3c21dd57e6a9f449ac2348bd3ea44" type="cassette">30</container></did><odd id="aspace_4181f9ea19b6057afe23fdce23ee73a2"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 37 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_2277a9ad81d52daf75a843dc5a5e91a8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Mary Payne lived in Eskdale, West Virinia. Her husband and brother in law were involved in the Battle of Blair Mountain. Ms. Payne felt her place was in the home and did not get involved.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref15_gj8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Camden McDornan Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 October 3</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_4a20da354914d03a7812289ea01489cc" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_0487b325b0ad091ce2d5555fbcc700c0" parent="aspace_4a20da354914d03a7812289ea01489cc" type="cassette">40</container><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_298376d9e5dcf5fe352d4cd1eab553f6" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_9bbf80f0732e1e3020f569b052476696" parent="aspace_298376d9e5dcf5fe352d4cd1eab553f6" type="cassette">39</container></did><odd id="aspace_5ba846dce5faf34445463e9e04df1fdb"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 39 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_41a1fc6a662b4f095acc69a6934fa4fd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Camden McDornan lived in Brushton, West Virginia. He worked in Boone County in union mine territory but was part of the Battle of Blair Mountain. He discussed the organization of the battle and the resulting surrender to the National Guard.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref17_z6b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Willie Epps Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">circa 1972</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_c7f0d8dee1d5a04ceb06a8f41af9df5c" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_48bf5905ade290ef1c1b4f255f14375f" parent="aspace_c7f0d8dee1d5a04ceb06a8f41af9df5c" type="cassette">15</container></did><odd id="aspace_5b23574212649f399241af4cc9c4be45"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Bob Hauptman and the report can be found on page 39 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_6dae5400d0d2fb482f98fb9ec64bc723"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Willie Epps lived in Fireco, West Virginia. He discussed living conditions in mining towns as a black man.  He recalled the hardships of all miners, regardless of race, and the change in technology over the years. He worked in union mines and received his pension and is a strong union man.</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_b2a7ec72122b817a216acfab829a7023"><head>Link to transcript</head><p>A transcript of the audio file may be found here: https://archive.org/details/LAC0006_S1_Epps_transcript <p> <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:title="PDF document" ns2:href="https://archive.org/details/LAC0006_S1_Epps_transcript">https://archive.org/details/LAC0006_S1_Epps_transcript</extref></p></p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref19_8yx" level="file"><did><unittitle>Agnew Thomas Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 October 3</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_11817c9329b073f33ecb1dcde1d32098" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_63688dfde31fee429f60e96a7cb4ead5" parent="aspace_11817c9329b073f33ecb1dcde1d32098" type="cassette">52</container></did><odd id="aspace_490a2842005c4ce4b1b700ad1f1bd0e7"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Bob Hauptman and the report can be found on page 45 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_b6461debaf8ceb1a0ac353b909f016d7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Agnew Thomas lived in Sylvester, West Virginia. He is married to Artie Thomas. When Agnew was 18, he joined in the Battle of Blair Mountain. He discussed the controversy surrounding the ending of the battle, and expressed a feeling that everyone has sold out. He was secretary of his local when he retired from a mine in Boone County.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref21_bqu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Artie Thomas Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">circa 1972</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_e6d7a768a2f40b44dfaa263a48bd1d14" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_8bda4882958c70f4af49bbb22a7a1c33" parent="aspace_e6d7a768a2f40b44dfaa263a48bd1d14" type="cassette">53</container></did><odd id="aspace_c2b9be04feb1f27824ca2b537ebdb05d"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Bob Hauptman and the report can be found on page 48 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_e5bd15af1f0c175124b5eec9640388ed"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Artie Thomas lived in Sylvester, West Virginia. She is the wife of Agnew Thomas. She adds to Mr. Thomas's stories during the interview.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref23_6b3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Brice Hunter Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 September 14</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_03687ce94f4d2f857034928a16444f9f" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_f901f6a3b788d62e9488d2a0702695cd" parent="aspace_03687ce94f4d2f857034928a16444f9f" type="cassette">26</container></did><odd id="aspace_0b4aff3cf1abcc263a77cab3ae71d7d6"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 49 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_1b912961521692c4e27868d070177cde"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Brice Hunter lived in Racine, West Virginia. Mr. Hunter discussed the killing of Deputy Sheriff John Gore. As an outsider working in the nearby glass plant, he recalled the plight of his working brethren.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref28_sdd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Elbert Gore Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 August 8</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_e8d7f7943fa373963197dcb30da1a4a2" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_9899e057260c7f0261e2cf7073a1e6b3" parent="aspace_e8d7f7943fa373963197dcb30da1a4a2" type="cassette">22</container></did><odd id="aspace_87e2877e4873940192cbab16d886ac81"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 53 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_0770898ecddd2d9ae8b6a64d1b83a1c2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Elbert Gore lived in Holden, WV. His father was deputy sheriff John Gore, who was shot by a group of miners during the Battle of Blair Mountain. Mr. Gore was a school teacher and was not involved with the law, but was taken hostage by miners regardless. He discussed the Battle of Blair Mountain, including the many times he felt his life was in danger. He eventually became a sheriff in spite of his previous experiences.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref30_hrf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dewey Browning Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 July 3</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_f3216fad27a7364b791e20a330f7f9c2" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_3d473e13f479526c401a5b019472f166" parent="aspace_f3216fad27a7364b791e20a330f7f9c2" type="cassette">6</container></did><odd id="aspace_491c4cbdd872945270810d542f19ed8f"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 61 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_372f0f7bc7ef7eccb418a12dc38eea02"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Dewey Browning lived in Switzer, West Virginia. Mr. Browning discussed the life of a union miner that played both sides. He had worked for Sheriff Don Chafin in the past which gave him the ability to avoid violence. He discussed the Battle of Blair Mountain as a nonparticipant and the aftermath of union organization.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref32_7g6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mrs. Howard Young Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 September 15</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_e12eed62e422d68ba9f9fce389232705" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_252f5dea929017f1a3a76af6585251c1" parent="aspace_e12eed62e422d68ba9f9fce389232705" type="cassette">60</container></did><odd id="aspace_4aa164716cbc6d0c0e09454a3aa12fa2"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 66 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_51ef797a461839005118259b2d9cfce1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Mrs. Howard Young lived in Holden, West Virginia. She was pregnant and giving birth during the Battle of Blair Mountain. Her husband Howard Young was involved in the march.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref34_0d5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Josh Chafin Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 September 20</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_053ee135b8166e9c5034611487f17bd0" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_6aa03179b4b630e04608a8890d906c6e" parent="aspace_053ee135b8166e9c5034611487f17bd0" type="cassette">8</container></did><odd id="aspace_2a49a2f6d076a7e8c196e2e225a6b394"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 68 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_28c8b206bea9e0e8d5c8c113a4eda112"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Josh Chafin lived in Cora, West Virginia. Mr. Chafin worked in mines but was forced to join the sides of the coal operators and the deputies. He stated that he did not want to fight, or get fired, so he went up to the Battle of Blair Mountain and did not participate. A veteran of World War I, he realized what he needed to do to stay alive.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref36_giz" level="file"><did><unittitle>George T. Swain Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 September 1</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_d51c2e1475094b03572e270e21d48afc" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_1e192baa7fdf6599bc3028f51cb3c986" parent="aspace_d51c2e1475094b03572e270e21d48afc" type="cassette">51</container><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_609fc77d77a7998fff7e786c3c359d35" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_64178b7e105671f2769e862aec9a79c6" parent="aspace_609fc77d77a7998fff7e786c3c359d35" type="cassette">50</container></did><odd id="aspace_fdef7e50d96284ebe9bb24bf89be4553"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 71 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_47d6a8381299bfda02410e74f37df960"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>George Swain lived in Charleston, West Virginia. A retired miner that sided with Sheriff Don Chafin, Mr. Swain became a reporter for the Logan Banner. He discussed in great detail the Battle of Blair Mountain. He also discussed living conditions and the power of the coal operators.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref38_zlh" level="file"><did><unittitle>William D. Gothard Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 September 16</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_cf0f45dc70c8c77068b902c2d52e75f8" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_577d7d2d28cbce765b67729b6c6c61dd" parent="aspace_cf0f45dc70c8c77068b902c2d52e75f8" type="cassette">23</container></did><odd id="aspace_60418132129536a237bd1c4965b4158b"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 82 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_86c735054d5c23a536da94b3c4493306"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>William Gothard lived in Cora, West Virginia. Mr. Gothard worked in the Logan County mines for over 50 years. He claimed to be a neutral and used his ability as a bootlegger to remain so.  He discussed his interactions with his fellow miners and Sheriff Don Chafin.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref40_js7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Charles Literal Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 July 10</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_a3febcc4f97e58b6dba34de9e38a6684" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_79223d8162ca13e60e04b30ee507142c" parent="aspace_a3febcc4f97e58b6dba34de9e38a6684" type="cassette">45</container><container id="aspace_fc6ab817cb2b3fc48c320f266493b523" parent="aspace_79223d8162ca13e60e04b30ee507142c" type="cassette">Side A</container><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_1238d9d6656a0a8369c527f4ada97010" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_d3497213b7efd0203d5afd016286b811" parent="aspace_1238d9d6656a0a8369c527f4ada97010" type="cassette">37</container><container id="aspace_0a31391d99a664d726fa9c4d6260f455" parent="aspace_d3497213b7efd0203d5afd016286b811" type="cassette">Side B</container></did><odd id="aspace_2c318e4206e6695f186cb00ae6cc8edc"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 87 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_c504c3944c5ab48faa96a8a1779dead3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Charles Literal lived in Logan, West Virginia. A retired miner, Mr. Literal was known as the local history buff. He retold the story of the Matewan Massacre and the Battle of Blair Mountain.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref42_c4c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pinhead Jones Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 July 10</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_76f0a30b36131efb2316f5ed3216d94f" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_4d9e12ad6c9daa44b1371f67aa594577" parent="aspace_76f0a30b36131efb2316f5ed3216d94f" type="cassette">45</container><container id="aspace_01ce18cbf418662c11957d06f56d4e9e" parent="aspace_4d9e12ad6c9daa44b1371f67aa594577" type="cassette">Side B</container></did><odd id="aspace_bad258f7d40cd6ea286fe5835d70304e"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 91 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_fffef7484bf4674ee51c8ffa3889f774"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Pinhead Jones lived in Logan, West Virginia. Mr. Jones moved from Alabama and worked for the Island Creek Coal Company for nearly 40 years. He stated that Sheriff Don Chafin offered to pay him to fight against the miners, but refused and hid out throughout the Battle of Blair Mountain. He gave President Roosevelt all the credit for the miners' right to organize.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref44_p52" level="file"><did><unittitle>Spencer D. Brinegar Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 March 5</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_1a59d98c51df3d6d16686e64640ab09e" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_1202a3ae2720998ff660c83f63c5db32" parent="aspace_1a59d98c51df3d6d16686e64640ab09e" type="cassette">4</container></did><odd id="aspace_831cc1c205e1e565929031935000aa41"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 93 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref46_1xc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mary Ghiz Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_4b580c24cc3200ad7a3b2a7d09c38dcb" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_1574c062ece98198b46163bcd56e336b" parent="aspace_4b580c24cc3200ad7a3b2a7d09c38dcb" type="cassette">19</container><container id="aspace_63c112b9268e549d8abeb3b7f9e2c91d" parent="aspace_1574c062ece98198b46163bcd56e336b" type="cassette">Side A</container></did><odd id="aspace_dc3213e734cb0a5e729fa448da73985b"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 96 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_a009c93c3b214c55f8e1c999eaaddc50"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Mary Ghiz lived in Logan, West Virginia. Her father, John Ghiz, immigrated to the United States in 1904 from Hungary. Her father was peddling clothes and eventually became Logan's first confectioner. Ms. Ghiz recalled the time of the Battle of Blair Mountain from a neutral viewpoint.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref48_4r5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Georgie McCloud Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 August 16</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_2c1cb4a9c35c3e35898510a852dceb95" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_d73f338e7d7f713ba4e5cd6295cf720f" parent="aspace_2c1cb4a9c35c3e35898510a852dceb95" type="cassette">28</container><container id="aspace_14f8fb26b955615b3010324f6a74d77c" parent="aspace_d73f338e7d7f713ba4e5cd6295cf720f" type="cassette">Side B</container></did><odd id="aspace_55066f50e1900387441a1d704859bc13"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 98 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_b6572d3300f40e7a5b5f41059a94ad8b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Georgie McCloud lived in Harts, WV. She wrote down her thoughts (included in the report) and most of the interview consists of her discussing her family's involvement in the Battle of Blair Mountain. Ms. McCloud's brother Wayne sided with the miners and her brother Gordon side with the coal operators and served as personal bodyguard to Sheriff Don Chafin.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref50_ksh" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ira P. Hager Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 September 8</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_dc72fd3ff41d13def018450b6ba900ba" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_b91a980e08e29fa15cbecc7cee753163" parent="aspace_dc72fd3ff41d13def018450b6ba900ba" type="cassette">24</container></did><odd id="aspace_e5175049684a1f8e427c2afd4b119d62"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 100 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_5e81ed9d9f94fd3ad6cccaf3f4db07ef"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Ira Hager lived in Meadowbrook Hills, West Virginia. Mr. Hager was a lawyer in Logan and handled murder cases in addition to preparing affidavits that detailed the violation of miners civil rights. He was part of a Republican coalition organized to break the strength of the coal industry Democratic dominated regime in the county.</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_2cecbe487353f8ef4827467ab45deda5"><head>Link to transcript</head><p>A transcript of the audio file may be found here: https://archive.org/details/LAC0006_S1_Hager_transcript <p> <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:title="PDF document" ns2:href="https://archive.org/details/LAC0006_S1_Hager_transcript">https://archive.org/details/LAC0006_S1_Hager_transcript</extref></p></p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref52_hvv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Harry Dingess Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 September 6</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_4518ec75550ae1b3939a764551ba8bb9" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_b782770bee9c70d2c4cfe79cce5032db" parent="aspace_4518ec75550ae1b3939a764551ba8bb9" type="cassette">13</container></did><odd id="aspace_f9d2fb2483c158d241347c3bac40cadb"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 103 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_a520cd0f42a03d2be699507cab951202"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Harry Dingess lived in Barnabus, West Virginia. He was a Sheriff under Don Chafin, but too young to participate in the Battle of Blair Mountain. Mr. Dingess then went on to work in the coal mines and discussed his life since.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref54_qfk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Richard Burgett Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 September 15</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_5e6e3096c7abb71a0a1eb29638d5e75f" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_6336ac8e657d9fa6a5b6bbe8bb6dddba" parent="aspace_5e6e3096c7abb71a0a1eb29638d5e75f" type="cassette">7</container></did><odd id="aspace_fe56bff195f120a7420dd27664fabb86"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 105 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_5fa65bc507e3ee80b9960fd2b37843a9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Richard Burgett lived in Monaville, West Virginia. He worked in the mines in Mingo County and was threatened with a yellow dog contract. Although the miners in Mingo would heavily involved in striking and union organizing, they could not participate in the Battle of Blair Mountain as they would have had to pass through Logan and the route was blocked by private detectives. Mr. Burgett moved to Logan County in the 1920s and joined the union when the U.M.W.A. finally gained ground after the passage of the National Industrial Recovery Act of 1933.</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_c7e5e060cfb05f3f3b456a717ad3df6a"><head>Link to transcript</head>A transcript of the audio file may be found here: https://archive.org/details/LAC0006_S1_Burgett_transcript

<p> <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:title="PDF document" ns2:href="https://archive.org/details/LAC0006_S1_Burgett_transcript">https://archive.org/details/LAC0006_S1_Burgett_transcript</extref></p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref56_2tv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bea Curtis Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">circa 1972</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_eb3815a5c5367096401e49a25b841e3e" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_7492c55cc8cb62237fac35d419aa48fa" parent="aspace_eb3815a5c5367096401e49a25b841e3e" type="cassette">10</container><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_c706a042bda46769c19467434db11cd1" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_8d87ba53a0185a15964be39446fea11f" parent="aspace_c706a042bda46769c19467434db11cd1" type="cassette">11</container></did><odd id="aspace_2e03a5c49e04c187be377fc0c7abfab1"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Bob Hauptman and the report can be found on page 117 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_b048fdfe0a062a20d7afe061a9869771"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Bea Curtis lived in Williamson, West Virginia. Her father and husband both worked in the mines. Ms. Curtis was involved, along with a portion of the black miners, with the Matewan Massacre by assisting in guerilla like activity in Wise County Virginia. She discussed living conditions with government assistance.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref58_6du" level="file"><did><unittitle>James Washington Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">circa 1972</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_9227d5dc3ac058fa8e7abd2dc2ef0eb5" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_87f30189697a5e69fbb3b0971160649e" parent="aspace_9227d5dc3ac058fa8e7abd2dc2ef0eb5" type="cassette">3</container><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_8d6f1b60062feca38d66fdab0d5a7648" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_0a5fa03ceff4006d3e98383e3b8967b0" parent="aspace_8d6f1b60062feca38d66fdab0d5a7648" type="cassette">54</container></did><odd id="aspace_4b55f306957e4279027a80e7546873b6"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Bob Hauptman and the report can be found on page 119 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_45bc706308c99ea213b158ec25486df9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>James Washington lived in Williamson, West Virginia. He was too young to remember any violence and did not start mining until after unions were established. Mr. Washington was a District Director for the Mingo County Economic Opportunity Council, and discusses living conditions in the area.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref60_6jj" level="file"><did><unittitle>Louis Bradford Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">circa 1972</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_6b5e09006cd63bc0ae3422136bab9dfc" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_46e1a29062d02b76e0a5f9f7c0af8864" parent="aspace_6b5e09006cd63bc0ae3422136bab9dfc" type="cassette">3</container></did><odd id="aspace_29b5eaa16589d154a8001d54ee56739d"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Bob Hauptman and the report can be found on page 121 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_d9306c7d1d6c3c5173d69f9e15763469"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Louis Bradford lived in Williamson, West Virginia.  He outlined details from the Blair Mountain struggle as well as living conditions in the mines. He was present during James Washington's interview and quickly interrupted with stories.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref62_t3o" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bascombe Hyatt Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">circa 1972</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_22a8a91b868d9ccb6b8b27f37651fc34" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_23f8e4b9435da3c6942ae999643eee4e" parent="aspace_22a8a91b868d9ccb6b8b27f37651fc34" type="cassette">27</container></did><odd id="aspace_97094d9e78d9eb4e686ae007d0c8687d"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by an unidentified interviewer and the report can be found on page 123 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_81756eb51ad87acce4a479e310eb2411"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Bascombe Hyatt lived in Williamson, West Virginia. Mr. Hyatt worked in all sorts of mines, both union and nonunion, and earned a reputation as a scab. He claimed that a man has to provide for his family and does not see the need for unions if the men get paid regardless.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref64_bdt" level="file"><did><unittitle>Luther Keen Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 September 21</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_9945eb14c3501c27e21d0a9d788327e4" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_4791c87f6b487385a2adeefe60c85748" parent="aspace_9945eb14c3501c27e21d0a9d788327e4" type="cassette">35</container></did><odd id="aspace_49f8fba79ac8b86a9bf6b888fe5784bf"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 125 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_72439b6f91d2c1974a77dff8a6141a93"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Luther Keen lived in Holden, West Virginia. Mr. Keen worked in the mines for over 40 years and was president of the first local union, #5813, at the Holden #7 mine. He discussed living conditions before the union and the opportunities the union provided after it was established.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref66_0ij" level="file"><did><unittitle>Edward Perry Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 September 16</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_92f60e7520120ea6bbe8538471dfc406" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_3b9107ce9a3070e1ec021299ece450b0" parent="aspace_92f60e7520120ea6bbe8538471dfc406" type="cassette">42</container></did><odd id="aspace_5d0d7acd4fbf4c5e603d87998a8ac68f"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 128 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_4aabfbcae2cb6ec642b28c37460d388f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Edward Perry lived in Holden, West Virginia. Mr. Perry discussed living conditions in the mines under the Island Creek Coal Company and the #22 Holden mine explosion.  He gave his perspective on the organization of unions and the scabs/union busters that came into town creating violent times. He also discussed the Battle of Blair Mountain, Matewan Massacre, and March on Logan incidents.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref68_991" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sid Conley Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 September 20</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_8b9220e837a3c4e72ee5a715694a1a29" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_4f8564707e30f406fd8d9e3468c1a12a" parent="aspace_8b9220e837a3c4e72ee5a715694a1a29" type="cassette">9</container></did><odd id="aspace_1fa2967f2261fb1a07b644542ebfcff3"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 133 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_99128a85d5e7c1f043571a4727e21b6d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Sid Conley lived in Mud Fork, West Virginia. He worked for the Island Creek Coal Company and discussed the union organization struggles. He attributed the lack of organization to the authorities and their unrightfully persecution. Mr. Conley was a proud supporter of unions.</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_43f955cf4b433c16274a40894002e19e"><head>Link to transcript</head>A transcript of the audio file may be found here: https://archive.org/details/LAC0006_S1_Conley_Transcript/mode/2up

<p> <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:title="PDF document" ns2:href="https://archive.org/details/LAC0006_S1_Conley_Transcript/mode/2up">https://archive.org/details/LAC0006_S1_Conley_Transcript/mode/2up</extref></p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref70_azq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mandy "Grandma" Porter Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 September 27</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_222df5f1c6704d18ce35d3ab6ee7bc76" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_04b23b509bd308e70bcb31d05c784c55" parent="aspace_222df5f1c6704d18ce35d3ab6ee7bc76" type="cassette">46</container></did><odd id="aspace_be6c9065135c02ae8772fdb19f51e3ed"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 135 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_58e2fa2a7594bff506f1ce39c2d0bb24"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Mandy "Grandma" Porter lived in Verdunville, West Virginia. She discussed the living conditions in McDowell and Mingo Counties and the organization of union activity. She moved to Logan County in 1923 and says it was much worse until the National Industrial Recovery Act of 1933.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref72_qb3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mrs. L. Dow Browning Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 September 27</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_70ee0b404480467b0c8f486b06af8aee" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_cc08270479ccd6ee26ba8f94fac8a27f" parent="aspace_70ee0b404480467b0c8f486b06af8aee" type="cassette">55</container><container id="aspace_c86d0385b3caea8a0796853bbb80e362" parent="aspace_cc08270479ccd6ee26ba8f94fac8a27f" type="cassette">Side B</container></did><odd id="aspace_f424e4b3141c0056f1302b00c8de7132"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 143 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_379a26b42f239f0cf6a8ba96bfa453fe"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Mrs. L. Dow Browning lived in Verduneville, West Virginia. She discussed conditions during  the early years of the union, specifically on the Gay Coal Company – where her husband worked for over 60 years. The mine was not a union mine and the coal operators were against it, but she recollected that both the miners and the operators respected each other.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref74_fuq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Otis Kinser Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">circa 1972</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_48bf4e7e539a1df6467e505d453a6337" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_8e3baeb7606af6d6cf35dc70226ae354" parent="aspace_48bf4e7e539a1df6467e505d453a6337" type="cassette">19</container><container id="aspace_12948a3f1db7e7ece749d3e4afc1b9ad" parent="aspace_8e3baeb7606af6d6cf35dc70226ae354" type="cassette">Side B</container></did><odd id="aspace_e763de3d36892e0afea2e1329e3680c8"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 145 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_dcb9d02e94a57850490fbcf920aa9aff"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Otis Kinser lived in Logan, West Virginia. Mr. Kinser discussed the living conditions in Logan and the fear of the authorities and the force they used to deter union activity.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref76_73v" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lee Johnson Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 September 28</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_a487ffd9468c3da4c0a6b9184584c0b0" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_6f9596915f292a98cbb26fee3042fb27" parent="aspace_a487ffd9468c3da4c0a6b9184584c0b0" type="cassette">34</container></did><odd id="aspace_f1cd308e3c53a12ee3329f1c4e8a8e89"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 147 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_260497b0e098f32405ce52c5bff6015a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Lee Johnson lived in Monaville, West Virginia. Mr. Johnson discussed life in the mines of Logan County without a union, and how most miners did not have knowledge of organized labor. He talked about Sheriff Don Chafin and detailed the use of "shadow unions" until the National Industrial Recovery Act of 1933.  He stated that thousands turned out for the first organizing meeting in Logan.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref78_gs4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Elijah Mays Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 September 16</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_7040ca3765901777730677c58cfde3bd" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_9cfda621e11dd8aeaaca34a7c4425c80" parent="aspace_7040ca3765901777730677c58cfde3bd" type="cassette">38</container></did><odd id="aspace_510df82f5fb29c9a2e5706d4c9ef231a"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 151 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_7214feb8cf4b9f57bd473b331bf0cb48"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Elijah Mays lived in Holden, West Virginia. After starting out in the lumber business, Mr. Mays spent the majority of his life working in the mines of Logan County. A lifelong union man, he did not participate in the Battle at Blair Mountain as he would not raise arms against a fellow union miner. He suspects that most men were union men at heart, but the overbearing presence of Sheriff Don Chafin's deputies and the fear of arrest kept most men silent.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref80_xl7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Frank Deen Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 September 21</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_48260dc3192349c10730b3912ff1e88f" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_47e13480182df2d3a362f96c34a12863" parent="aspace_48260dc3192349c10730b3912ff1e88f" type="cassette">12</container></did><odd id="aspace_da381e6e7146c2365b50f47e97ca609b"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 154 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_63e85c198e6c92ab89ed0559d42a8d15"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Frank Deen lived in Holden, West Virginia. After emigrating from Italy, Mr. Deen spent the majority of his life working the mines of the Island Creek Coal Company. A supporter of unions, he discussed living conditions and working conditions in the mines during the Depression, as well as life as an immigrant.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref82_qjd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Spencer Mullins and Laura Adkins Mullins Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 September 27</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_205c45d372088df553f0b77375f9436f" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_e8ca7334e9a4e4b6b621c56599729237" parent="aspace_205c45d372088df553f0b77375f9436f" type="cassette">41</container></did><odd id="aspace_d33abc005ff89b543d5edb8016be9455"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 156 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_2f720b5ff79f761a4dc7f0d9fa0426da"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Spencer and Laura Mullins lived in Verdunville, West Virginia. A lifelong miner around Omar, Mr. Mullins did not hear of union ideas until after returning from World War I. He states that the union sentiment really built up during the Depression. Mrs. Mullins discussed the life in the mining camps raising children.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref84_plh" level="file"><did><unittitle>Shirley Workman Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">circa 1972</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_90395b3cdba3c278323fe0d7d36a7aa4" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_adec5885c69daef5eb7eee3e7d80c4c5" parent="aspace_90395b3cdba3c278323fe0d7d36a7aa4" type="cassette">59</container></did><odd id="aspace_2f64e60c5c40f62c68ce462eec91f7a2"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 158 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_4a38c72ff71096952aa7a8a6d52bac11"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Shirley Workman lived in Mud Fork, West Virginia. Mrs. Workman's husband Issac worked over forty years for the Island Creek Coal Company. Mr. Workman joined the union prior to the Battle of Blair Mountain, but kept that information private for fear of persecution. Both Mr. Workman and two of his sons acquired black lung, and another was killed in a mine explosion at the #22 Holden mine. The Workman's see the coal companies as heartless bottom liners.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref86_vy1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Albert Williamson Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 September 27</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_c5109d580b9a8f32dc6e3c72cf42f320" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_197d2c1b8de44f1ee903622e2edfa9d6" parent="aspace_c5109d580b9a8f32dc6e3c72cf42f320" type="cassette">55</container></did><odd id="aspace_44df0b1647ec15242c2e0d892a0c9367"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 159 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_fc04ee2136d6a2aa8effaeda8262bb4a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Albert Williamson lived in Verdunville, West Virginia. Mr. Williamson worked in virtually all of the mines in Logan County until an accident forced early retirement in 1956. He discussed working conditions in non-union mines and how most miners could not wait for union organization that eventually came in 1933.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref88_g5z" level="file"><did><unittitle>Nathan England Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 September 28</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_4287fd1c86dd449acee001a196c356fe" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_af04c5216c4a86d5703442030233879d" parent="aspace_4287fd1c86dd449acee001a196c356fe" type="cassette">14</container></did><odd id="aspace_2c1d93fb09c631e665b52c4cd1e7ce02"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 160 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_bb74fed43e70e108c0afc7c7384f1789"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Nathan England lived in Monaville, West Virginia. Mr. England discussed living and working conditions of the mines in Tennessee.  Similar to other miners, he was afraid to discuss union sentiment for fear of being fired and blacklisted. He recalled stories of union organizing in Tennessee which were similar to the stories of union organizing in West Virginia. He moved to the county in the late 1930's and worked in the mines for over 30 years.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref90_ghn" level="file"><did><unittitle>John Lee "Jack" Wilson Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">circa 1972</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_0f2451da4aeb5597894b7df0396bb89f" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_6446f2ea2ebc28c4723f3b1b4ee627ca" parent="aspace_0f2451da4aeb5597894b7df0396bb89f" type="cassette">57</container><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_1127dbe341d99ebf8e31add2537e9046" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_29961a4273c221f0a116b54db62a4d87" parent="aspace_1127dbe341d99ebf8e31add2537e9046" type="cassette">58</container></did><odd id="aspace_9d3807ec737241648aec901f767ba4f9"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 166 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_7fd9aeea968cb698deadbb6c142fbd7a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>John Lee "Jack" Wilson lived in Roda, Virginia. Mr. Wilson was an organizer for the Hazard County, Kentucky mines and was sent in by the U.M.W.A. into Harlan County, Kentucky. Mr. Wilson was faced with major violence upon arrival, and did not appreciate the union structure and their inactivity during that time. He was then blacklisted and moved to Roda, VA, where he worked under a different name.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref92_j3e" level="file"><did><unittitle>William Glover Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 August 6</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_a62e7ee06e5b3176412fac9d810f6d5d" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_30628bedde5f576d3401ecf6a69b6f5e" parent="aspace_a62e7ee06e5b3176412fac9d810f6d5d" type="cassette">21</container></did><odd id="aspace_ac2e425fa12ea2438a8882516aa875e9"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 171 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_3fc6376baeb0e0f79f99ea3dc72c9c09"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>William Glover lived in St. Paul, Virginia. An unofficial organizer, Mr. Glover acted the part of contact from the unions to the working men in the mines in several areas of Virginia and Kentucky.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref94_8uf" level="file"><did><unittitle>O. Litchfield Richardson Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">circa 1972</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_1e3fcce9ccc615bcf0c447abbf41f085" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_d07ac6758041135fac96df35221bf1df" parent="aspace_1e3fcce9ccc615bcf0c447abbf41f085" type="cassette">58</container></did><odd id="aspace_4954dcfda1446f2aa66d9a0bff41120e"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 176 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_180b084f252c9c45cdea6aeea882f40b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>O. Litchfield Richardson lived in Norton, Virginia. Mr. Richardson was not interested in discussing his history, but he was involved with the first local union in Tom's Creek, VA in 1935.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref96_7qu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bill Gibson Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">circa 1972</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_910eb04e19a08e579aa0fd1d91fe9a76" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_b86c60a58040612a3016b3e665225ce7" parent="aspace_910eb04e19a08e579aa0fd1d91fe9a76" type="cassette">20</container></did><odd id="aspace_b0a69bb4b180daaa6cd395cd03dc6c7b"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 178 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_80639621a4b1adc5c6393ebb38899321"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Bill Gibson lived in Norton, Virginia. He was a former president of the local union in Tom's Creek, VA. Mr. Gibson discussed the situation after the National Industrial Recovery Act of 1933 and how the men organized.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref98_inz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Grant Howard Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 July 19</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_129810dd6c75497ced8183d1ab7d013f" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_bab39adadc48de3e712a5039d2944637" parent="aspace_129810dd6c75497ced8183d1ab7d013f" type="cassette">32</container></did><odd id="aspace_62b19b08bfdb8812bd9b0007ea3105ba"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 179 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground". This was a joint oral history with Grant Howard and Chester "Red" Poore.</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_666296af2d18a3b0bf4afccaef3ae563"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Grant Howard lived in Evarts, Kentucky. Both Grant Howard and Red Poore were veterans of the union movement in Harlan County, Kentucky and the Battle of Evarts. One of the skirmishes in 1931 resulted in two men killed, and Mr. Poore was sentenced to life imprisonment but only served a 10 year sentence. Mr. Poore discussed the lack of a union presence in 1972, even though men fought and died for the right to organize.  Mr. Howard moved on from the coal mines to the steel mines, where he has a longer commute but a higher standard of living.</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_d66937d5c5982d999b2032c4e570338c"><head>Link to transcript</head><p>A transcript of the audio file may be found here: https://archive.org/details/LAC0006_S1_Jackson_TRanscript <p> <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:title="PDF document" ns2:href="https://archive.org/details/LAC0006_S1_Jackson_TRanscript">https://archive.org/details/LAC0006_S1_Jackson_TRanscript</extref></p></p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref100_yyk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chester "Red" Poore Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 July 19</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_7cd3229d4aed92ecffc5c8d6a55ffeeb" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_d298434f47d1bf866fac00369eb3f3ae" parent="aspace_7cd3229d4aed92ecffc5c8d6a55ffeeb" type="cassette">32</container></did><odd id="aspace_e05faa625cc679ccceef33d276122974"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 179 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground". This was a joint oral history with Grant Howard and Chester "Red" Poore.</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_0a32e4160af1ff0f7022433643e4c738"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Chester "Red" Poore lived in Evarts, Kentucky. Both Grant Howard and Red Poore were veterans of the union movement in Harlan County, Kentucky and the Battle of Evarts. One of the skirmishes in 1931 resulted in two men killed, and Mr. Poore was sentenced to life imprisonment but only served a 10 year sentence. Mr. Poore discussed the lack of a union presence in 1972, even though men fought and died for the right to organize.  Mr. Howard moved on from the coal mines to the steel mines, where he has a longer commute but a higher standard of living.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref102_4ku" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ben Foster Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">circa 1972</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_0c70eeaca16d18ce503b6de08791fcf0" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_ce19a0f9a90d4e1003086a5cb5ca202c" parent="aspace_0c70eeaca16d18ce503b6de08791fcf0" type="cassette">17</container><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_703f1a319817e8186958b3d6e77084e9" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_d03feaa042e38059f305a70b08b46cfb" parent="aspace_703f1a319817e8186958b3d6e77084e9" type="cassette">16</container></did><odd id="aspace_d1cf720dfc62cb8f2cfdaddd1218d18f"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 185 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_8d3f4f4009ba9bcc1871067157cba1f5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Ben Foster lived in Evarts, Kentucky. Mr. Foster discussed the efforts of organizing unions in Harlan County, Kentucky, as well as living and working conditions in the mines.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref104_w2a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bill Gibson Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 July 20</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_394406edb1048acc91e2db180f585749" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_220ce820a8c828f9bfc4af2e9aa70b30" parent="aspace_394406edb1048acc91e2db180f585749" type="cassette">29</container></did><odd id="aspace_a2a371a4481e53795a876e46ba8814c6"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Bob Hauptman and the report can be found on page 210 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_6c1912095d1be154977ff1621556a023"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Bill Gibson lived in Evarts, Kentucky. Mr. Gibson claims to be a union man and was present during the bad times of the early 1930s in Harlan County, Kentucky. He discussed living conditions in the towns and the mine conditions under operators that did not approve of union activity.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref106_01p" level="file"><did><unittitle>George W. Fritts Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 July 20</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_ae947dde9c563357bea7f466f2950d35" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_24aaf85fc4f65762d5d4e490b05bc9bb" parent="aspace_ae947dde9c563357bea7f466f2950d35" type="cassette">17</container><container id="aspace_1aff19921d2a14bb6d2d2f2fd240a4f9" parent="aspace_24aaf85fc4f65762d5d4e490b05bc9bb" type="cassette">Side B</container></did><odd id="aspace_1f72ceb9015e3ac6fa86b98618318f9a"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 212 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_03323d236d779e37dc989229dbd9f2ce"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>George Fritts lived in Evarts, Kentucky. Mr. Fritts was a taxi driver for both sides during the trial in Mt. Sterling as a result of the Battle of Evarts. He discussed the situations surrounding the trial and the treatment of both the miners and the coal operators.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref108_tkb" level="file"><did><unittitle>John Bates Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 June 17</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_ca11821ebd70357f9766654fe1fb1038" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_5c0e4bdd81b78d6b2ccd0fe7bd4389db" parent="aspace_ca11821ebd70357f9766654fe1fb1038" type="cassette">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_2779dcadc89fd5e822e7131c0ff45d5e"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 215 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_cebe64b79e8e8182d698c459c4f6965a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>John Bates lived in Whitesburg, Kentucky. Mr. Bates worked as an organizer for Letcher County in 1933 and was a strong union supporter. He discussed living conditions during very violent times and outlined the measures took by union organizers.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref110_9ee" level="file"><did><unittitle>Luther King Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 June 18</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_a214dda50e908f1f83a474800ca55671" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_ea3ec0137679fef1049a193b627b0037" parent="aspace_a214dda50e908f1f83a474800ca55671" type="cassette">36</container></did><odd id="aspace_c1919a83ab956ef586d713b75f177054"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 218 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_4a73ceac767798b8e752b249b2969050"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Luther King lived in Whitesburg, Kentucky. As an organizer for the U.M.W.A. from 1931-33, Mr. King handled most of southeastern Kentucky. He discussed the difficulty in organizing and the operation of feeding striking miners and their families.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref112_m9m" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dewey Brown Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 June 17</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_a954fc04e8ed2981b8ee187ae150b83c" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_9841ac69c2fcf759a78a1e8a3be42fc1" parent="aspace_a954fc04e8ed2981b8ee187ae150b83c" type="cassette">5</container></did><odd id="aspace_aff2a6352e4cb8824292c81f9715e554"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 221 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_bab79420aa39c1ab149bc946eb94d92a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Dewey Brown lived in Whitesburg, Kentucky. Mr. Brown worked as a volunteer organizer for the union in 1933 in Letcher County. He discussed the conditions of the mines prior to the union and the resulting conditions after the union was organized. He stated that only one union mine remained in 1972.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref114_rxq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Joe Ramsay Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 June 17</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_0200344770962f77f662265a33814519" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_729caf636ecbbd061aaed6d46baa9000" parent="aspace_0200344770962f77f662265a33814519" type="cassette">47</container><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_f9ca7683d25368be2d67abcdb83cc45a" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_827f5ce87d4fda843ed0a4405a2bfb38" parent="aspace_f9ca7683d25368be2d67abcdb83cc45a" type="cassette">48</container></did><odd id="aspace_f890acf1e7a2eec0a5ba9fb5a6c43d39"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and the report can be found on page 223 of "On Dark and Bloody Ground".</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_28b55a1347aa0048af0b1b4dcbe7607e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Joe Ramsay lived in Monaville, West Virginia. He originally worked in the mines with his father in Letcher County, but moved Jenkins, Kentucky in 1933 where he was first exposed to the U.M.W.A. He eventually moved to Logan County, West Virginia, where he lived at the time of the interview.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref116_e25" level="file"><did><unittitle>WJ Martin Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 June 12</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_16792717f3108998e6b29614597e2598" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_87cc51d46ee0e1a38ed399d3c80c8416" parent="aspace_16792717f3108998e6b29614597e2598" type="cassette">37</container><container id="aspace_3fa0d25fc30566f283c49911ca5653bb" parent="aspace_87cc51d46ee0e1a38ed399d3c80c8416" type="cassette">Side A</container></did><odd id="aspace_8ba066eabc10b2a60cdc19952963cc73"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and was not included in the report "On Dark and Bloody Ground."</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref118_cwi" level="file"><did><unittitle>Charles Hampton Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 July 20</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_d264e2aacf73f67acaa77a3e91e56ea9" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_94a6d075fe4250ca4725e9ff1fcb0cfb" parent="aspace_d264e2aacf73f67acaa77a3e91e56ea9" type="cassette">29</container><container id="aspace_4210ca937e0c4249344b9fea7fdc96af" parent="aspace_94a6d075fe4250ca4725e9ff1fcb0cfb" type="cassette">Side B</container></did><odd id="aspace_35ad62295e8b02e61b65dfc113a2abdd"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and was not included in the report "On Dark and Bloody Ground."</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref120_ipi" level="file"><did><unittitle>Charles &amp; Mae Hampton Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 July 20</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_ee0099557997674548d4f4acb3a88371" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_9f8b6160a181fa02f0a38a904366a426" parent="aspace_ee0099557997674548d4f4acb3a88371" type="cassette">31</container></did><odd id="aspace_a6a94c5eb9c57c12704b52738368d767"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and was not included in the report "On Dark and Bloody Ground."</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref122_s4m" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pat Fuller Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 August 4</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_334054e8ce8abea9636d47d0fc3f42d3" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_6843e2f2385fa97c0a5359be5886b67a" parent="aspace_334054e8ce8abea9636d47d0fc3f42d3" type="cassette">18</container><container id="aspace_768c3763c99f3f8b5d472bccbe051107" parent="aspace_6843e2f2385fa97c0a5359be5886b67a" type="cassette">Side A</container></did><odd id="aspace_579b62e617b82552d86f450281a378d5"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by an unidentified interviewer and was not included in the report "On Dark and Bloody Ground."</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref124_xnm" level="file"><did><unittitle>George Jackson Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972 August 16</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_48abf31b6a8080917abbd2c8ef36e03d" label="Audio [32882021643583]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_b52b0c32ff7018ba2a2a02534189624a" parent="aspace_48abf31b6a8080917abbd2c8ef36e03d" type="cassette">28</container><container id="aspace_67409a13b8a59de5faba6462ae520d39" parent="aspace_b52b0c32ff7018ba2a2a02534189624a" type="cassette">Side A</container></did><odd id="aspace_9d24ce7bc91b7062cae6b61511bf631d"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and was not included in the report "On Dark and Bloody Ground."</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref126_kl4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Josephine Roche Interview</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">circa 1972</unitdate><container altrender="Audio Cassette Box Holds 36" id="aspace_c9ab58e1ec70aa2e340401ba0feecb74" label="Audio [32882021643575]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_4edfd9d2746f3663110918a7ed1cf361" parent="aspace_c9ab58e1ec70aa2e340401ba0feecb74" type="cassette">49</container></did><odd id="aspace_11bc0b8313690353e64dc117edd0a2c6"><head>General</head><p>Interview was conducted by Anne T. Lawrence and was not included in the report "On Dark and Bloody Ground."</p></odd></c></c><c id="aspace_ref136_x0o" level="series"><did><unittitle>Oral History Transcripts</unittitle><unitid>Series 2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">circa 1972</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial></did></c><c id="aspace_ref137_p3m" level="series"><did><unittitle>NEH Report - "On Dark and Bloody Ground - An Oral History of the UMWA in Central Appalachia, 1920-1935"</unittitle><unitid>LAC0006</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">1973 January</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial><container id="aspace_8c6fb51b2ce51bff5c035871476bbc2b" label="Books [32882022389871]" type="Box">Shared Box 32</container><container id="aspace_2acd5c7822a208771418d8c9b0d34b4d" parent="aspace_8c6fb51b2ce51bff5c035871476bbc2b" type="Folder">2</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
