<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://library.gwu.edu/ead/ms0776.xml">ms0776.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Edward W. "Skip" Gnehm, Jr. papers, <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1965-1966</date>
 <num>MS0776.UA</num></titleproper>
        <author>University Archives, Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2006</date>
        </p>
        <address>
          <addressline>2130 H Street NW</addressline>
          <addressline>Washington 20052</addressline>
          <addressline>speccoll@gelman.gwu.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-01-18 11:52:13 -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language encodinganalog="language">English</language></langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Edward W. "Skip" Gnehm, Jr. papers</unittitle>
      <unitid>MS0776.UA</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate datechar="creation">1965-1966</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_b21d61da0a9f9fb6bbb338416ad9e5f2">Collection includes photocopies of two scrapbooks containing clippings, letters, photos, etc., of Edward W. Gnehm, Jr., GW student body president. They range in date from 1965-66.</abstract>
      <langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
      <container id="aspace_5e2e0c8904d75c843d32f6464141f3a7" label="Mixed Materials [GW: 32882018320450]" type="flat_box">1</container>
    </did>
    <prefercite id="aspace_babafd284358a0d4f8a2b4c1443c1a35">
      <head>Preferred citation</head>
      <p>Edward W. "Skip" Gnehm, Jr. papers, University Archives, Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_f2b5c5330135a800a64db6296cabf8ea">
      <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
      <p>Some records may be restricted.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_269546b31487dc0e74743f8b7f1c257b">
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>The collection was donated to the University Archives by Edward W. Gnehm, Jr. in 1999.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <userestrict id="aspace_20e4c315c99d708abf17bf93759d1c4f">
      <head>Restrictions on Use</head>
      <p>Some material may be copyrighted or restricted. It is the patron's obligation to determine and satisfy copyright or other case restrictions when publishing or otherwise distributing materials found in the collections.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <bioghist id="aspace_f6ba53e5fd31cca0affb4973af5debf8">
      <head>Biographical Note</head>
      <p>Edward William "Skip" Gnehm, Jr. (c.1944- ) has had a distinguished career in government, as Ambassador to Kuwait (1991-94), Australia (2000-01), and Jordan (2001-04). He also served as Director General of the Foreign Service from 1997-2000, and was Deputy Permanent Representative of the United States to the United Nations with the rank of Ambassador from 1994-1997. </p>
      <p>Ambassador Gnehm was born in Carrolton, Georgia. He graduated from The George Washington University with a B.A. in 1966 and an M.A. in 1968. From 1966-1967, he attended the American University in Cairo, Egypt, under a post-graduate Rotary International Fellowship, and completed a year of graduate study at the American University in Cairo, Egypt in 1968.</p>
      <p>Ambassador Gnehm joined the U.S. Department of State in 1969 and has forged a long and distinguished diplomatic career. His positions included: Director General of the Foreign Service and Director of Personnel for the Department of State; Deputy Assistant Secretary of State, Bureau of Near East and South Asian Affairs; Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Near East and South Asia; Deputy Chief of Mission, American Embassy, Amman, Jordan, and Embassy Sanaa, Yemen; head of the U.S. Liaison Office, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia; and Deputy Principal Officer, U.S. Interests Section, Damascus, Syria. </p>
      <p>Ambassador Gnehm received two Presidential Meritorious Service Awards, in 1990 for his public service as Assistant Secretary of Defense, and in 1991 for his service as Deputy Assistant Secretary of State. He is also the recipient of several State Department awards, including Superior Honor Awards for his service in Kuwait and Riyadh, in Washington as Deputy Assistant Secretary of State and in Taif, Saudi Arabia as Special Envoy to the Kuwaiti Government and Meritorious Honor Awards for his work in Damascus and Beirut. He was awarded two Secretary of Defense Medals for Meritorious Civilian Service: one by Secretary of Defense Carlucci for his service in the office of the Secretary of Defense and a second by Secretary of Defense Perry for his support to U.S. forces during and after Desert Storm. </p>
      <p>In 1992, Ambassador Gnehm received The George Washington University's Distinguished Alumni Achievement Award. He served seven years as a member of The George Washington University Board of Trustees and was a member of the board's Executive Committee and chairman of the Student Affairs Committee. He also served as Vice President of the General Alumni Association.</p>
      <p>Ambassador Gnehm joined the faculty of the Elliott School of International Affairs at The George Washington University in August 2004 as the J.B. and Maurice C. Shapiro Visiting Professor of International Affairs. He was appointed to his present position as Kuwait Professor of Gulf and Arabian Peninsula Affairs in August 2006. He also serves as Director of the Middle East Policy Forum. He is married to Margaret Scott of Macon, Georgia, and has two children. </p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_3a8ee6be2048c3eaf00cb71f0aa7eeb5">
      <head>Collection Scope and Content</head>
      <p>Materials in this collection include photocopies of two scrapbooks containing clippings, letters, photos, etc., of Edward W. Gnehm, Jr., GW student body president. They range in date from 1965-66, and were donated to the University Archives by Edward W. Gnehm, Jr. in 1999.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <odd id="aspace_ba76951736aee3d69c085dfc299510d1">
      <head>Bib#</head>
      <p>8442019</p>
    </odd>
    <controlaccess>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Washington (D.C.)</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">Awards</subject>
      <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
      <subject source="lcsh">Students</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Ambassadors</subject>
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Carlucci, Frank Charles</persname>
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">George Washington University--Alumni and alumnae</corpname>
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">George Washington University</corpname>
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Gnehm, Edward W. (Edward William)</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_ref10_dfn" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Photocopies of scrapbook materials</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation">1965-1966</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_c98cee4bced9862fc24777c7a18a9767" label="Mixed Materials [GW: 32882018320450]" type="flat_box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_d7f84109195f9bce91a884d6ed72b426" parent="aspace_c98cee4bced9862fc24777c7a18a9767" type="Folder">1</container>
        </did>
        <odd id="aspace_a4dd504ddbc609d39cbf4399e7dcfc7c">
          <head>General note</head>
          <p>The folder contains photocopies of correspondence, newspaper clippings and photographs pertaining to Gnehm's activities as President of the Student Body, including letters of protest sent to GWU Trustees.</p>
        </odd>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref12_qt8" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Photocopies of scrapbook materials</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation">1965-1966</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_61f9757c5a490745e46650d3e266e66f" label="Mixed Materials [GW: 32882018320450]" type="flat_box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_a7f6b4af9dd02de32ab01a01017bb33c" parent="aspace_61f9757c5a490745e46650d3e266e66f" type="Folder">2</container>
        </did>
        <odd id="aspace_6e0e7e7331799e07c8b44c62fcf5353a">
          <head>General note</head>
          <p>The folder contains photocopies of correspondence, newspaper clippings and photographs related to Gnehm's tenure as President of the Student Body.</p>
        </odd>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
