<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://library.gwu.edu/ead/ms2354.xml">ms2354.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Records related to neighborhood overlay and development from the Woodland Normanstone Neighborhood Association, <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1988-1996</date>
 <num>MS2354</num></titleproper>
        <author>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>2130 H Street NW</addressline>
          <addressline>Washington 20052</addressline>
          <addressline>speccoll@gelman.gwu.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-01-18 12:03:17 -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language encodinganalog="language">English</language></langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Records related to neighborhood overlay and development from the Woodland Normanstone Neighborhood Association</unittitle>
      <origination label="source">
        <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Sher, Linda</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>MS2354</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1988/1996" type="inclusive">1988-1996</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_bc0f16c3ba0b312476dd37faf539b375">Woodland Normanstone is a small residential neighborhood in Northwest Washington, D.C., adjoining the larger neighborhoods of Woodley Park, Massachusetts Avenue Heights, and Observatory Circle. On March 23, 1989, the Woodland Normanstone Neighborhood Association was certified as a nonprofit corporation composed of residents of Massachusetts Avenue Heights, an area bounded by Rock Creek Park to the east, Massachusetts Avenue to the south and west, and Calvert Street, Cleveland Avenue and Woodley Road to the north. This collection contains correspondence, hearing records, testimony, civil complaints, and other documents related to the efforts of the Woodlawn Normanstone Neighborhood Association to protect the character of their neighborhood from development they identified as detrimental. These records cover 1988-1996.</abstract>
      <physloc id="aspace_d9f8886189fc4d46ac12696c01adb5ba">Materials are stored off-site, and will require additional retrieval time.  Please contact the Special Collections Research Center for more information.</physloc>
      <langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_7b698e1a6665941ae112efc446224a87">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>This collection contains correspondence, hearing records, testimony, civil complaints, and other documents related to the efforts of the Woodlawn Normanstone Neighborhood Association to protect the character of their neighborhood from development they identified as detrimental. The records concern lawsuits and appeals before District agencies including the Fine Arts Commission, Zoning Commission and the Office of Planning. There is also information related to the Tree and Slope Overlay that the Association was instrumental in getting the District Government to enact and then enforce in their neighborhood. These records date from 1988-1996.</p>
      <p>The Brandt project files concern complaints and eventual lawsuits issued by residents of homes that abutted construction undertaken by developer Lawrence Brandt to build houses along Woodland, Rock Creek and Normanstone Drs. The complaints involved The Commission of Fine Arts and the DC Government agencies includeing the Board of Zoning Adjustments.</p>
      <p>Folder 4 includes the Bylaws of the Association</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <bioghist id="aspace_f10a6a9756335a584bc3c14176285891">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>Woodland Normanstone is a small residential neighborhood in Northwest Washington, D.C., adjoining the larger neighborhoods of Woodley Park, Massachusetts Avenue Heights, and Observatory Circle. On March 23, 1989, the Woodland Normanstone Neighborhood Association was certified as a nonprofit corporation composed of residents of Massachusetts Avenue Heights, an area bounded by Rock Creek Park to the east, Massachusetts Avenue to the south and west, and Calvert Street, Cleveland Avenue and Woodley Road to the north. The purpose of the Association is to preserve and enhance physical and aesthetic characteristics of the Heights by encourging widely spaced residential development and the maintenance of an attractive parkline setting. </p>
      <p>In 1990 the Association was instrumental in the creation of the Tree and Slope Protection (TSP) Overlay District. The TSP was established to preserve and enhance the park-like setting of designated neighborhoods adjacent to streams or parks by regulating alteration or disturbance of terrain, destruction of trees, and ground coverage of permitted buildings and other impervious surfaces. The TSP District is designed for residential neighborhoods that are located at the edge of stream beds or public open spaces and that have a significant quantity of steep slopes, stands of mature trees, and undeveloped lots and parcels subject to potential terrain alteration and tree removal. </p>
      <p>In 1992 the Commission mapped the neighborhood represented by the Woodland Normanstone Neighborhood Association. </p>
    </bioghist>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_a5ea81779cb4bf39297f6ea45d9e208c">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
      <p>Gift of Linda Sher, 2016 May 3 (2016.065)</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <userestrict id="aspace_45f6d4ebd8b5feff114430e71d9824d1">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
      <p>Some material may be copyrighted or restricted. It is the patron's obligation to determine and satisfy copyright or other case restrictions when publishing or otherwise distributing materials found in the collections.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_115a86ee735d36dfdb82ab2201d7b26a">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>This collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <arrangement id="aspace_78ad163b631441f4a75145d765d3f10a">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>Arranged in chronological order. The materials came in bundles that had been identified by the donor. The archivist generated folder titles from the brief description provided on each bundle.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite id="aspace_51342f10ff8456fcef86ab0f356466e3">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Please cite unpublished materials in the following way:</p>
      <p>Please provide the title and date of item, catalog number (if applicable it will be found written on the folder), name of the collection, name of the repository, and location of the repository. </p>
      <p>Example:
James Oglethorpe to the Trustees, 13 January 1876, RG0001 Series 1, Box 4, Folder 3.  Records of the Board of Trustees, Special Collections Research Center, Gelman Library, The George Washington University, Washington, D.C.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_02eaccedb3c391064acb01d20e8814ae">
      <head>Related Materials</head>
      <p>The records of the Woodland Normanstone Neighborhood Association are held by the Historical Society of Washington, D.C. Collection MS 0751Woodland Normanstone Neighborhood Association collection. <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://historydc.pastperfect-online.com/32595cgi/mweb.exe?request=record;id=C47A5A8B-0D19-4DEA-BDC9-887054644059;type=301" xlink:show="new">http://historydc.pastperfect-online.com/32595cgi/mweb.exe?request=record;id=C47A5A8B-0D19-4DEA-BDC9-887054644059;type=301</extref></p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Neighborhood planning -- United States -- Citizen participation. </subject>
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Woodland Normanstone Neighborhood Association</corpname>
      <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Sher, Linda</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_ref9_d1b" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>[Brandt development on Rock Creek and Normanstone Drs.] [1/2] </unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1988/1989" type="inclusive">1988-1989</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_ffd8a10ded0005236fdcbadf8ed52e67" label="Text [32882021240497]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_a7e90b2cbdf2844a23dc99866f1a4bfd" parent="aspace_ffd8a10ded0005236fdcbadf8ed52e67" type="Folder">1</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref10_emg" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>[Brandt development on Rock Creek and Normanstone Drs.] [2/2]</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1988/1989" type="inclusive">1988-1989</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_aa20640c184b53a96cdc76b239db0433" label="Text [32882021240497]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_e693c6e25977ca1e0d2b9d72b4b89e7d" parent="aspace_aa20640c184b53a96cdc76b239db0433" type="Folder">2</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref11_kis" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>[Brandt project]</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1992/1992" type="inclusive">1992-1993</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_924763d87496df90d8d10acbdcee144e" label="Text [32882021240497]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_2e4abda6b4a335e5f24a6366c8898c15" parent="aspace_924763d87496df90d8d10acbdcee144e" type="Folder">3</container>
        </did>
        <odd id="aspace_085f6b7fafd72337cf01fa313c1d2f2b">
          <head>General</head>
          <p>This folder contains an appeal submitted by the Woodland Normanstone Neighborhood Association to the DC Board of Zoning Adjustment that includes a detailed timeline of legal actions and final adjudication of the Brandt development project and the Associations attempts to stop the original development plans.</p>
        </odd>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref12_sqx" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>[Tree and slope overlay]</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1992/1998" type="inclusive">1992-1998</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_ebd7e5da8f344edb79bc50b93ab56f6d" label="Text [32882021240497]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_583b1ff05b1c5f6ca47dbe9d2a66e27b" parent="aspace_ebd7e5da8f344edb79bc50b93ab56f6d" type="Folder">4</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_a6182ea6729c52f6701cf492517c97b3">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This folder holds the Bylaws of the Association. The document is undated, but was part of records from the late 1980s and early 1990s.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref13_270" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>[Overlay and Brandt project]</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1989/1990" type="inclusive">1989-1990</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_a0cfbf3d4370c9bfda31c07d689366da" label="Text [32882021240497]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_9911e9492dc03fb54f0d1b790bf8752f" parent="aspace_a0cfbf3d4370c9bfda31c07d689366da" type="Folder">5</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref14_oz0" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Overlay chron file [1/2]</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1989/1990" type="inclusive">1989-1990</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_4a2a2fd2a1dba8395fdbab9810f44866" label="Text [32882021240497]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_b3497ff935c82f22a3100ff6f76dd617" parent="aspace_4a2a2fd2a1dba8395fdbab9810f44866" type="Folder">6</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref15_7z1" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Overlay chron file [2/2]</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1989/1990" type="inclusive">1989-1990</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_53205ceec54dc6163c1997f61f85c9ed" label="Text [32882021240497]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_02b6eaf99b4327ca8166d5dd8cb7aaa9" parent="aspace_53205ceec54dc6163c1997f61f85c9ed" type="Folder">7</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref16_bs3" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>2817 Woodland Drive</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1996" type="inclusive">1995-1996</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_535e7f68834b60e85fd4f7bd2bcee9c0" label="Text [32882021240497]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_465b4448540e693073117aafb7ae4b55" parent="aspace_535e7f68834b60e85fd4f7bd2bcee9c0" type="Folder">8</container>
        </did>
        <odd id="aspace_573933098d09cb840d2002c8198e0ea9">
          <head>General</head>
          <p>This file concerns the construction of a garage and second-story residence at 2817 Woodland Drive (home of Mandel Ourisman) and the Associations attempt to ensure that it met land use, zoning, and environmental requirements according to District laws and regulations.</p>
        </odd>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
