<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="https://searcharchives.library.gwu.edu/repositories/2/resources/848">ms2388.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Lessons of the Sixties: A history of local Washington, DC activism for peace and justice from 1960-1975: Interviews, <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">2010-2019</date> <num>MS2388</num></titleproper><author>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</publisher><address><addressline>2130 H Street NW</addressline><addressline>Washington 20052</addressline><addressline>speccoll@gelman.gwu.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-01-18 12:13:07 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid written in <language encodinganalog="language">English</language></langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Lessons of the Sixties: A history of local Washington, DC activism for peace and justice from 1960-1975: Oral history interviews</unittitle>
    <unitid>MS2388</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">59 digital object(s)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2010/2019" type="inclusive">2010-2019</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_0df22e4e59df32d95b40e0dc97950581">Lessons of the Sixties is an organization dedicated to documenting the efforts and lessons learned by local DC Metropolitan Area activists, students, organizers and those who dreamed of building a better world through new ideas, political advocacy, local organization building, and other means in the years 1960-1975. Since 2010 the Institute for Policy Studies has served as the organizational home for the Lessons of the 60s providing office space and infrastructural support. This collection contains the 59 oral history interviews conducted from 2010-2019. The orginals, raw footage and display versions are housed on the Special Collections preservation server. The digital object links for each interview are to the Youtube channel maintained by the organization.</abstract>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_7bb2d410f07016d567540fadc4a3a802">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_1d5a0edbe0d2b0d0bc579221ce9de919">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Lessons of the Sixties, 2019 November 20 (2019.101).</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_d919edc33d9d217bc2677ac305c1cba3">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Arranged alphabetically by interviewee last name.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_f03e5314338d76186c7729d72e9d0725">
    <head>Historical note</head>
<p>Lessons of the Sixties is an organization dedicated to documenting the efforts and lessons learned by local DC Metropolitan Area activists, students, organizers and those who dreamed of building a better world through new ideas, political advocacy, local organization building, and other means in the years 1960-1975. The organization's goal is to make materials easily available for future activists, historians, students, writers, and media producers. Members have given presentations on their findings in order to facilitate direct dialogue between generations of social justice activists. One of the most significant contributions are the oral histories it conducted between 2010-2019 with local activists. 
 
Lessons of the Sixties has the objective of focusing on key local and national movements and events of this period in which D.C-area-based residents were involved. These topics include, but are not limited to, 1963 March on Washington, anti-Vietnam War organizing, Black power movement, civil rights movement, DC statehood movement, early battles against gentrification, fair housing, international solidarity, May Day 1971, peace movement, Stop the North Central Freeway/3 Sisters Bridge, student activism for peace and civil rights, and the Women's movement.</p><p>
Since 2010 the Institute for Policy Studies has served as the organizational home for the Lessons of the 60s providing office space and infrastructural support. </p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_33032f8f637570cb106f69c7330f55f0">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Please cite unpublished materials in the following way:</p><p>Please provide the title and date of item, catalog number (if applicable it will be found written on the folder), name of the collection, name of the repository, and location of the repository. </p><p>Example:
James Oglethorpe to the Trustees, 13 January 1876, RG0001 Series 1, Box 4, Folder 3.  Records of the Board of Trustees, Special Collections Research Center, Gelman Library, The George Washington University, Washington, D.C.</p>  </prefercite>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_78e51ac8a993905eb0acb63a4a016574">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains the 59 oral history interviews conducted from 2010-2019. All donated orginals, raw footage and mp4 versions are housed on the Special Collections preservation server. The digital object links for each interview direct users to the Youtube channel maintained by the organization.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_e5f6f079f38faf4e3a83f934cf56e117">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The Lessons of the Sixties owns copyright to these interviews and they have licensed these interviews to be used according to the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License.</p>  </userestrict>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_47814c52ddd7c697a7a766ec3016ce06">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
Lessons of the Sixties donated materials that are found in several GW collections. The links to the related collection's finding aids are below. 


<extref xlink:href= "https://searcharchives.library.gwu.edu/repositories/2/resources/801" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onrequest"> Lessons of the Sixties: A history of local Washington, DC activism for peace and justice from 1960-1975: James G. Stockard papers finding aid </extref>

<extref xlink:href= "https://searcharchives.library.gwu.edu/repositories/2/resources/853" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onrequest"> Lessons of the Sixties: A history of local Washington, DC activism for peace and justice from 1960-1975: Personal papers finding aid </extref>

<extref xlink:href= "https://searcharchives.library.gwu.edu/repositories/2/resources/802" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onrequest"> Lessons of the Sixties: A history of local Washington, DC activism for peace and justice from 1963-1990: Joann Malone papers finding aid </extref>


To go directly to the assistance provided by the Lessons of the 60s from their website: 
To watch all the video interviews conducted by the Lessons of the Sixties project, go to the <extref xlink:href= "https://lessonsofthesixties.wixsite.com/lessonsofthesixties/interviews-conducted-to-date"show="new" xlink:actuate="onrequest"> Lessons of the Sixties conducted interviews page
</extref> If your focus is word searching interviews and document collections use  <extref xlink:href="https://lessonsofthesixties.wixsite.com/lessonsofthesixties/interview-keywords"show="new" xlink:actuate="onrequest"> Lessons of the Sixties keyword lists
</extref>.  </relatedmaterial>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_b52056e22853fd5be661150ffc66897f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Aaronson, Larry</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2018/2018">2018 January 26</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_7956dadc286dc12e0dacb81c8aae909f"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Larry Aaronson grew up in Washington DC, where he began a teaching career after college. He cut his political teeth in the local civil rights movement, moving later to Cambridge, MA to teach in public schools for over forty years. Larry maintains that he has learned more from his hundreds of students than they ever learned from him.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_3649363dbcc1f3697a1a985ed5c9014f"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Larry Aaronson inteview: Segregated Washington DC in 1940s - 1950s - 1960s, Spingarn High School: the true condition of DC public education, SNCC leader Marion Barry as mentor, Black history and Jim Crow and Reconstruction information as spur for high school activists, DC Bus Boycott, Bill Simon and Charlie Cheng and DC Teachers Union, Institute for Policy Studies (IPS) as important meeting place, Senator Ernest Gruening, The Cardozo Project: empowering students and teachers, Liberation Pedagogy, 1968 riots/uprising - impact on city, Emergency Committee on the Transportation Crisis (ECTC) as response to crisis, Montgomery County Public Schools (MCPS), Coleman Report, 1969 Moratorium, Harvard School of Education, Social Studies as crucible of education, Personal realization that questioning authority is essential part of education for students and teachers.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_035f71a2f88b9c1d7ee9d1325e379c35" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Alperovitz, Gar</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2014/2014">2014 June 13</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_4e2732712705af65683fd0775db09e87"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Gar Alperovitz has had a distinguished career as a historian, political economist, university professor, activist, writer, and government official.</p><p>He is the author of critically acclaimed books on the atomic bomb and diplomacy. The books, written in the 1960s and the 1990s, convincingly challenged long-held claims by President Truman and other defenders of early U.S. atomic policy that the dropping of atomic bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki was necessary to save thousands of American troops' lives. Rather he wrote, citing newly declassified evidence, U.S. policymakers based their strategy toward the Soviet Union on the judgment that the atomic bomb, once demonstrated, would provide leverage in negotiating the postwar world order.</p><p>From 1966 to 1968, while a Fellow at the Harvard Institute of Politics, Alperovitz developed the "Vietnam Summer" campaign centered on canvassing and teaching to motivate undecideds and non-activists into taking action against the war. Although his role only became known more than 45 years later, Alperovitz in 1971 worked with Daniel Ellsberg to keep the publication of the Pentagon Papers going -- after the initial publication by The New York Times was halted by a court challenge by the Nixon administration -- by secretly arranging to hand off portions of the report to one news outlet at a time, beginning with The Washington Post.</p><p>In the decades since then, the D.C.-based Alperovitz has worked on issues relating to inequality and participatory democracy. In that regard, he is the president of the National Center for Economic and Security Alternatives and is a founding principal of the Democracy Collaborative, a research institution developing "practical, policy-focused, and systematic paths toward ecologically sustainable, community-oriented change and the democratization of wealth."</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_531043bf717d602bb9d172349e8ac3e9"><head>General</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Gar Alperovitz interview: Racine Wisconsin, Parents Democrats, Cancer Society, Football high school, University of Wisconsin, History Department, William Appleman Williams, Scholarships, Harvard, Yale, NYU Law School, Didn't go, Fred Harvey Harrington, Fellowship to Berkeley, Student Union president (U. Wisconsin), Saul Landau, Student Life and Interest Committee, Labor Youth League, Communist Party, Pete Seeger, George Mosse historian, Berkeley, Masters in economics, Hyman Minsky, Marshall Scholarship, England, Bob Kassettiere, HUAC (House Unamerican Activities Committee), American expansionism, American imperialism, Rosa Luxembourg, Joan Robinson, Left Post-Keynesian economics, Cambridge, Kings, PhD with Joan Robinson, Marcus Raskin, Dick Barnet, Arthur Waskow, Bill Proxmire, Henry Reuss, Legislative assistant to Kastenmeier, Kennedy years, John F. Kennedy was cold warrior, Richard Nixon, Missile Gap, Cold War, Cambridge England), PhD. thesis, Gaylord Nelson, Gulf of Tonkin, Atlantic City, Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, Community Development Corporations (CDC), Kari (daughter), Peace Research Institute, Arthur Waskow, Christopher Jencks, New Republic, Richard Barnet, Disarmament, Atomic bomb, Cuban Missile Crisis, Todd Gitlin, Kastenmeier, Cambridge (MA), Cuban Missile Crisis, Erich Fromm, Hans Morgenthau, Hannah Arendt, David Riesman, Paul Goodman, Civil rights movement, Peace movement, Women's movement, SNCC (Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee), Ivanhoe Donaldson, Tina Smith, Frankfurt Institute, Anarcho-communal vision (Raskin), Civil rights, Vietnam War, Call to Resist, Antiwar movement, Gulf of Tonkin, Karl Hess, Cambridge Institute, Christopher Jencks, Kalorama , Belmont Place, Adams Morgan, Racine Wisconsin, Labor town, Industrial town, Israel, Kibbutz, Community Development Corporations, State socialism, David Morris , Karl Hess, Fish farming, Corporate capitalism, Neighborhood technology, Jeff Faux, Office of Economic Opportunity (OEO), Bedford-Stuyvesant Corporation, Community Development Corporations, New Communities Inc., Micro-socialism, John McClaughry, Community Self-Determination Act, CORE (Congress on Racial Equality), Floyd McKissick, Roy Innis, Public banks, "Notes Toward a Pluralist Commonwealth", Staughton Lynd, Neighborhood corporations, Worker-owned, State banks, Regional — Tennessee Valley Authority, Atomic bombing of Hiroshima book, Martin Luther King, Mississippi, Bob Moses, Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, Vietnam War, Carter administration, Paul Krugman, Dean Baker, Charlie Rose, Cambridge Institute, Jeff Faux, National Center for Economic Alternatives, Youngstown Steel , University of Maryland, Benjamin Barber, "Strong Cities Strong Democracy", Jessica Gordon Nembhard, Marcus Raskin, Economic stalemate stagnation decay, New economy movement , Co-ops, Land trusts, James Gustav (Gus) Speth, Academy of Management (conference topic), "Is Capitalism Over — and What Do We Do About it?", Davos, Ellen Brown, California state banking, Joe McCarthy era, Conservatives in the 1940s, European social democracy, Weak U.S. labor movement.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_8c10c67adebf1cb2680f540354a82a86" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Aronica, Lou</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2014/2014">2014 April 25</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_20879d49b39f2acd37c9d844f2dd5843"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Long-time activist Lou Aronica is one of the Founding Fathers of the continuing D.C. statehood movement. Back in the early 1970s, Lou was one of the co-founders of the D.C. Statehood Party (now Statehood Green), along with such veterans of local civil rights and social justice struggles as Julius Hobson, Hilda Mason, Josephine Butler and Charles Cassell. More than any other Washingtonian, Lou has served as a leading tactician and the institutional memory for the statehood movement and as an historian of the District's long struggle to have the same rights as all Americans in the 50 states.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_bac5147d674a51b1248d4c1fe935491b"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Lou Aronica interview: Sam Smith, Progressive Review, D.C. Gazette, Tower City, PA, anthracite region, University of Maryland, graduate studies, International House, Americans for Democratic Action (ADA), staff director, ADA, 1961, non-communist Left, Julius Hobson, Congress on Racial Equality (CORE), Mid-Atlantic chapter, Associated Community Teams (ACT), Julius Hobson, Safeway, Hahn's Shoe Store, picket lines daily, D.C. Transit, secretarial schools, rats, Hobson ploys, police spying, Roy Chalk, D.C. Transit, fare increase, Julius Hobson, refused to pay fare, METRO, Lyndon Johnson, appointed DC Council, CORE, ADA, Hubert Humphrey, D.C. Fair Housing Council, International Self-Help Housing Association, Rural America, Sharecroppers Fund, Marion Barry, home rule, "home fool", Walter Fauntroy, Constitutional amendment, voting rights, statehood, Congress, Julius Hobson, Sam Smith, freeways, proposed 6 major interstate highways, appointed City Council, Rep. Joel Broyhill, Virginia, federal payment, independent City of Georgetown, District of Columbia smaller, Alexandria, pre-Civil War, D.C. governor, legislature, freed slaves, Boss Shepherd, Florida Avenue original boundary, 3-person commission, Army Corps of Engineers, commission form, 1865-1967, John F. Kennedy, home rule bill, Lyndon Johnson, Barry Goldwater, House of Representatives, District of Columbia Committee, House District Committee, Chairman , Rep. (John) McMillan (D-South Carolina), home rule bill, Rep. B.F. (Bernie) Sisk (D-California), Joseph Rauh, Senator Wayne Morse (D-Oregon), Rep. Adam Clayton Powell (D-N.Y.), Rep. Edith Green (D-Oregon), House Education and Labor Committee, Elementary and Secondary Education Act, Bernie Sisk, Lyndon Johnson, executive order, appointed mayor/commissioner, city council, Walter Washington, freeways, Broyhill threats on freeways, police riot, D.C. council chambers, arrests, Julius Hobson, on school board, arrested, Bruce Terris, chairman DC Democrats, arrested, Harriet Hubbard, Dupont Circle, right to vote for president, elected school board, elected non-voting delegate, Julius Hobson, non-voting delegate, Rev. Walter Fauntroy, Martin Luther King, Jr., SCLC (Southern Christian Leadership Council), Channing Phillips, Joseph Yeldell, "Coalition of Conscience", Sam Smith, Norman Mailer, Jimmy Breslin, DC Gazette, statehood article, Rep. Ron Dellums (D-California), introduced statehood bill, Hawaii, Alaska, Ernest Gruening, Alaska territorial governor, Compact Commission, Statehood Commission, federal city, police jurisdictions, U.S. Constitution, no minimum size federal District of Columbia, Maryland, Virginia, National Airport, Aronica wrote original Dellums bill, reciprocal income tax, Pentagon, Bill #1776, Ed Guinan, CCNV (Community for Creative Nonviolence), Statehood initiative, November 1980, Statehood Constitutional convention, D.C. Constitution adopted, basic mistake, prominent people omitted, Joe Rauh, Gilbert Hahn, John Hechinger, Washington Post, Constitution passed by voters, Sam Smith, progressive D.C. Constitution, House of Representatives , statehood vote in House, Rep. Bernie Sisk, D.C. Statehood Party, Norville Perkins, head, Board of Elections, Julius Hobson, D.C. Statehood Party ballot status</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_e31e0791758324d19e52985944b67c5c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Becker, Eddie</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2016/2016">2016 April 07</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_4491d494e68e1ba487e5d2e6359392b9"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Lifelong activist who has used his technical and research skills in the service of movements for social change in the U.S. and around the globe.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_d6c9d6f256b0578df1b6dcb915ea6b41"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Eddie Becker inteview: Eddie Becker, 1970 Alternative Media Conference, underground newspapers, radio, Videofreex, Tom Weinberg, Radical Software, Sony PortaPaks, a revolution, Eddie's youth, old radios, shortwave, Rockaway NY, "the list", parents, NYC Teacher's Union, after high school, travels, Washington DC, group houses, Quicksilver Times, bomb-making issue, SOURCE Catalog 1970, Federal City College Video Center, Roberto Barzini, May Day 1971, National Student Association, video coverage, edited at Videofreex NYC, goes to Italy, worker's councils, tenant organizations, student organizations, do it yourself video, playback in the community, Italian communists, return to NY, the draft, indicted, guilty, 2 yrs probation, anti-war movement in disarray, Italians send him to National Archives, society changes, Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), WWII records open at NARA, CIA and the Vatican, book AMERICA IN ITALY, same techniques in Vietnam, Fields of Plenty, 1982 technology changes, CNN, Nicaragua, Peru, Eritrea, 1975 Perpetual Research Group, local housing activist, group house, red lining, Adams-Morgan Organization, Seaton Street, coops, community reinvestment, INDIE MEDIA, 1989 Seattle, WTO, Washington DC BREAKING THE BANK, action against the World Bank, Blagden Alley media hub, partnership for civil justice, footage as evidence, entrapment tactic, lessons learned?, every generation must learn its own lessons, paranoia, how to spot an infiltrator, COINTELPRO, War On Drugs, intergenerational divide.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_7a6dfa63457240257955096989994ac5" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Benson, Sally</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2017/2017">2017 May 12</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_929af00f8ccb2691b581da608c17d8fe"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Sally Benson is a long-time antiwar activist who determined, after college, to live "a meaningful and independent life." Originally from Western Massachusetts, she found herself drawn to Asia, and in 1966 secured a teaching position in Vietnam through the International Volunteer Service. She lived and worked in Saigon and experienced the 1968 Tet Offensive up close, with her landlady warning her to cancel a planned visit to a friend the very night that the National Liberation Front troops moved in. Returning to the US in 1969, she and her partner Steve Nichols purchased a house in Washington, DC and became stalwarts of the local anti-war movement there, as well as well as working with national anti-war organizations through the end of the war. Today Sally still works on issues of reconstruction and reconciliation, travelling frequently to Southeast Asia. </p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_680f4ec0beb8496f90e3ce9f648ce043"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Sally Benson interview: International Volunteer Service (IVS), Tet Offensive, Fred Branfman, Steve Nichols - draft refuser, Indochina Resource Center (IRC), Fred Branfman and Project Air War, Indochina Mobile Education Project (IMEP), IMEP staffers: Sally Benson, Jacqui Chagnon, Don Luce, Jean-Pierre Dubuis, Roger Rumpf, Bob Minnick, Issues addressed by IMEP, Other organizations Sally worked with: Clergy and Laity Concerned CALC), Women Strike for Peace (WSP), Medical Aid to Indochina (MAI), Indochina Peace Campaign (IPC), 1977 American women's trip to Vietnam</p><p>​</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_271c30523d035ff40f3e9b552c6a0fac" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Blum, William</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2015/2015">2015 October 30</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_711a32b1b5811b95e591e3f59a6133b5"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>(1933-2018) - William Blum left the State Department in 1967, abandoning his aspiration of becoming a Foreign Service Officer because of his opposition to the U.S. war in Vietnam. He then became one of the founders and editors of the Washington Free Press, the first "alternative" newspaper in the capital. Beginning in the early 1970s, Bill was a freelance journalist in the United States, Europe and South America.  His stay in Chile in 1972-1973, writing about the Allende government's "socialist experiment" and its overthrow in a CIA-designed coup, led him to a heightened interest in what his government was doing in various parts of the world. In the mid-1970's, he worked in London with former CIA officer Philip Agee and his associates on their project of exposing CIA personnel and their misdeeds. His book on U.S. foreign policy, Killing Hope: U.S. Military and CIA Interventions Since World War II, first published in 1995 and updated since, received international acclaim.  Noam Chomsky called it "far and away the best book on the topic." Blum, who died in late 2018, was also the author of four other books, the last one being America's Deadliest Export: Democracy — The Truth About U.S. Foreign Policy and Everything Else (2013). His books have been translated into more than 15 languages. Bill's lifelong work was to educate the American public about the reality of US foreign policy and its global impacts.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_196d94e54797264735cd53064474bb54"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for William Blum interview: Vietnam, U.S. State Department, Brooklyn, Washington Free Press, Chile, Allende government, Philip Agee, CIA, "Killing Hope: U.S. Military and CIA Intervention Since World War II", Iraq, "America's Deadliest Export: Democracy", "Rogue State", Osama bin Laden, RT network, Brooklyn, City College of New York, computer programmer, IBM, State Department, foreign service exam, Vietnam War, Adlai Stevenson, Washington Peace Center, Marxist study group, State Department, Washington, D.C. Committee to End the War in Vietnam, Washington Free Press (WFP), "My Life at the State Department", Co-founders, Frank Speltz, Ann Speltz, Art Grosman, Mike Grossman, Q Street, 17th and 18th offices, hippies, typical WFP issue, anti-war, dope, marijuana, acid, civil liberties, civil rights, film, theater reviews, calendar of events, fire in hallway, FBI, disruption/spying, vendors fined, Columbia records, FBI, printers, Long Island printer, Seymour Hersh, FBI break-in, CIA, Quicksilver Times, Salvatore (Sal) Ferrera, CIA headquarters, taking down license plate numbers, tape recorder, Pentagon, Blum's CIA file, Quicksilver Times, Washington Free Press, politicos/hippie factions, Carl Bernstein, abortion counseling, Washington Free Press, Dr. (Milan) Vuitch (abortion doctor), Silver Spring, MD, Vuitch arrested, march on Pentagon 1967, Dr. Benjamin Spock, Marcus Raskin, Norman Mailer, levitate Pentagon, Quicksilver Times, Sal Ferrera, CIA, DMV offices -- Maryland, Virginia, D.C., Sal Ferrera, CIA informant, Philip Agee, Agee's book, Ferrera and CIA, Ferrera spying on Agee, typewriter bugged, Institute for Policy Studies (IPS), Karl Hess, informants/agents, Jan Tangen , Irwin Bock, Max Philip Friedman, House committee, Jerry Rubin, Rennie Davis, maharishi person, Art  Grosman, Frank Speltz, anti-war movement, protest fatigue, 2003 -- protests against upcoming Iraq War, U.S. invaded Iraq, U.S. ignored tens of millions protesters, Syria, Bernie Sanders, Hugo Chavez, Jill Stein, Barack Obama, Bernie Sanders, Hillary Clinton, war hawk, Bobby Kennedy, Barack Obama, "Killing Hope", Moscow, No internet, library research, London, Australia, Liberation News Service, 1 Thomas Circle movement building, Students for a Democratic Society (SDS), Marshall Bloom, Ray Mungo, Pacifica radio, Chilean refugees, San Francisco, Santiago, Chile, Panama, Salvador Allende, Chilean coup, Charles Horman, Frank Teruggi , Berkeley Barb, Quicksilver Times, Terry Becker, Sal Ferrera, Quicksilver Times office, 17th Street NW</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_2c57783578c6bae1e90cc33f9fb73b7f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Boylston, Hope and Lynda Tredway,</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2016/2016">2016 September 22</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_d8a85708b6f54abfcb6dd26a0f08b835"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Lynda Tredway and Hope Boylston met in the middle 60s when both enrolled as undergraduates at George Washington University. Both had a strong interest in politics, Lynda influenced by John Kennedy's call to action and Hope planning to study anthropology and see the world to "escape her privileged life." A life-long friendship developed from their shared experience as roommates, activists, mothers and educators, with Hope's human rights work around Chile informing her later teaching career in Pennsylvania, and Lynda's teaching experience and expertise making her a national authority on public secondary education, training and professional development. Hope authored a book, "Hoy Locos," about her time in Chile. Lynda, now retired from teaching at Berkeley and back in DC, is an accomplished artist and is currently working on an art project that addresses lynching.</p><p>Biographies provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_796a330a256f3d387118ebd84398222d"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Hope Boylston and Lynda Tredway interview: DC in the mid-60s: what it was like, Activism on campus: charismatic anthropology professor fired , Lynda starts tutoring, begins "new life" as an educator, Hope in South America: Ecuador &amp; Chile, Hope gains "revolutionary consciousness" from Ecuador experience, Lynda begins habitually "thinking against mainstream", Early women's movement, the Pill and abortion, Hope moves to Chile, translates "Our Bodies, Ourselves", Lynda observes poverty, racism as educational problems while teaching in DC schools, Anti-war activities step up, Lynda and Hope "on the streets", Difficulties of coalition work in 70s, Hope's and Lynda's "Lessons of the 60s"</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_c17c16e569d94606f183bcc92bfd7878" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Brecher, Jeremy</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2013/2013">2013 October 12</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_01c8dd071d945875d3e7ab806dc14d90"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Historian of labor struggles who was an antiwar activist, a regional organizer for SDS, an Associate Fellow at IPJeremy Brecher was a student activist living in Washington DC from 1965-70. He later became a labor historian, a documentary filmmaker and a writer on social change. He has authored more than a dozen books, including Strike, a history of American labor.S, and an active community organizer in the DC suburbs in the late 60s and early 70s.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_f55389963cedf9bc7ba2b7a08197af7e"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Jeremy Brecher interview: Institute for Policy Studies in 1960s, Emergency Committee on the Transportation Crisis (ECTC), Women Strike for Peace (WSP) pioneered direct action, model for Code Pink, Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee (SNCC), DC Statehood Party, Southern Christian Leadership Conference (SCLC), 1960s characterized by big national movements, Role of Students for a Democratic Society (SDS) and Weatherman , Black uprisings of 1967-68, Mistakes made by anti-war movement.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_378f4a22230c363a14f0f6c864104256" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Brown, Dale</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2015/2015">2015 October 22</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_58bb905ebcd2addbc4b00e9530aa5186"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>High school activist who was arrested distributing anti-Vietnam War material at a military base. Also headed up a students' committee against the war in 1971 for May Day, an attempted shut-down of the US government by the peace movement.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_c8cbdd80b6007ad4473d70d8f8bb37af"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by donor for Dale Brown interview: Dale Brown, High school activism around constitutional rights, Vietnam War, The Mobilization for Survival ("The Mobe"), Mobe promoted separate student event for April 1971 national demonstration, Brown recruited students for anti-war events at Winston Churchill HS, other schools, Most schools gave High School students a hard time, threatened them with expulsion, Risks that students faced in expressing opposition, Getting arrested at Fort Meade by military police in 1971, for leafletting the military, Successful mass leafletting by Maryland and DC HS students for April-May 1971 demonstrations.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_d386bdba1c678033b0e7604364a8dd7b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Cassell, Charles</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2013/2013">2013 June 07</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_1d12032bbc8e62385a85f684d40ccaa6"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Prominent hometown civil rights activist; active in picketing D.C stores that wouldn't hire blacks, and in the anti-freeway fight; co-founder D.C. Statehood Party, and later D.C. Board of Education member, and chair of the historic D.C. Statehood Constitutional Convention.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_8128b5b44bee3876236d78185f455514"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Charles Cassell interview: Carl Hansen , schools' track system , Julius Hobson, William Kunstler, 1924 – born, 707 Fairmont Street, Albert I. Cassell (Cassell's father), Doc Stratton, Cassell's mother, Howard University, Lansburgh's, Hecht's, James Monroe School, Lucretia Mott School, Miner Teacher's College, Garnet–Patterson Jr. High School, Mr. Savoy, jazz, Louis Armstrong, Duke Ellington, Towson, MD, Charlottesville, VA, Cousin Wilkes, father "Al the Bookworm", Howard University, Hampton Institute, Ithaca, Ithaca High School, Professor George Young, World War I, father enlisted, France, 75 mm and 100mm cannon, Cornell, Bethlehem, PA, Alfred Wiener, George Washington Carver, Tuskegee, Howard University, African American architects , architectural department, School of Architecture, dean of Howard Architecture School, Civil War General Howard, Harold Ickes, Founders Library (Howard U.), father reported corruption (building materials), father fired, father sued Howard U., U.S. Supreme Court, Howard settled, Cornell University, School of Architecture, drafted World War II, Francis Deal, Ed Morton, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute (RPI), professional African–American community in D.C., Federal Government – non-discrimination hiring, housing discrimination, father's proposed 500-acre town (Calvert Town), Chesapeake Bay, Cambridge, MD, Prince Frederick, MD, Senator Carter Glass, Harold Ickes (Secretary of Interior), Bureau of Yards &amp; Docks, Veterans Administration, General Services Administration, Julius Hobson, Birmingham, Alabama, CORE (Congress of Racial Equality), James Farmer, 9th &amp; S Streets NW, Capital Transit Co. , no black motormen/bus drivers, O. Roy Chalk, Bruce Hunt haberdashery - 9th &amp; F, "Don't buy where you can't work", whites, blacks picketed, Washington Hospital Center, Afro American newspaper, The Tribune, Washington Star, Washington Post, Walter Washington, professional black community, arrests, Hobson new organization , after CORE -- Associated Community Teams, D.C. Board of Education, D.C. Statehood Party, D.C. Council of Black Architects, Walter Washington, Albert I. Cassell (Cassell's father), Hahn's shoe store, D.C. Commissioners, Army Engineers Corps, rats removal program Ward 3 Georgetown, Hobson campaign to distribute rats into white communities, seeking rat abatement funds black community, Georgetown, rally - plaza (now Freedom Plaza), honor to be arrested, anti-freeway, ECTC (Emergency Committee on the Transportation Criss), Sammie Abbott, D.C. City Council, Takoma Park, Brookland, ECTC, freeway picketing, 3 Sisters Bridge, surrounded 3 Sisters site, Sammie Abbott's office, Dupont Circle Building, Poster: White Men's Roads through Black Men's Houses, unboarded houses in Brookland, Chief Jerry Wilson, white people aided, stopped freeway, Angela Rooney, Tom Rooney , Washington Post opposed to D.C. Constitution, D.C. Constitutional Convention, Walter Fauntroy, Republican committee member, David Clarke, Gloria Corn, D.C. Statehood Convention, Shadow Senators, Shadow Representative, Michael Brown (Shadow Senator), Albert Cassell, son was a rabble-rouser, School Board, Marion Barry, PRIDE, Inc., minor conflicts with Barry, Verizon Center, WorldCom, D.C. Historic Preservation Review Board (HPRB), Mayor Sharon Pratt Kelly, chairman HPRB, historic district (Verizon Center area), Cassell opposed Verizon Center, Barry didn't reappoint, home rule, "home fool", Josephine Butler, Hilda Mason, Reginald Booker, D.C. Statehood Party, Sammie Abbott, Abbott arrested often, later mayor Takoma Park, Josephine Butler, Paul Robeson Society, Hilda Mason, Hobson legislation for statehood, Walter Washington, Sen. Ted Kennedy, Rep. Fred Schwengel, D.C. Statehood Constitutional Convention, Hilda Mason, Josephine Butler, Hilda Mason, up for chair, Hilda married to Charlie Mason, Hilda seen as not forceful, Cassell, chair convention, Cassell as "go-getter", Betty Ann Kane, 90-days and $250,000 funded , redlining, Federal City College, Washington Technical Institute, Washington Teacher's College, University of the District of Columbia (UDC), Washington Board of Trade, Pennsylvania Avenue Development Corp., Riggs Bank, Perpetual S&amp;L, American Security Bank, jazz, Howard Theater, Charlin Jazz Society, Linda Wernick, Billie Holiday, Ella Fitzgerald, Lowell Thomas, Tom Mix, Fats Waller, Erskine Hawkins, Willie Bryant, Redd Foxx, Ella Fitzgerald, Pearl Bailey, Bill Bailey, Georgie Auld, DC Arts and Humanities Council, Washington Ethical Society, Buck Hill, Tito Puente, Linda Wernick, Dizzy Gillespie, Jazz Centennial, Kennedy Center, Alice Bonner, Duke Ellington, Duke Ellington Centennial, Mercer Ellington, Nicholas Brothers, Louis Armstrong Tribute concert, Wynton Marsalis, Duke Ellington, Wolf Trap, Jazz cruises on Potomac , 1977 – The Jazz Arts Society, John Eaton, Sarah Vaughan, Kirk Stuart, Linda Wernick, Charlin Jazz Society, Cardozo High School, Millennium Stage, Kennedy Center, National Public Radio (NPR), Anne Loikow, Ward 3 4th of July parade, Jazz Cruise on the Potomac, Nap Turner, "Going Down Slow" (song)</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_94f250463b9c50836ac2621c841cf10d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Clark, Steve</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2019/2019">2019 May 10</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_32ac16392e0de4ac612c210c1febb688"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Steve Clark went through many stages of activism. He was a protester, revolutionary, and organizer. Locally he is best known as the driving force behind Stone Soup, a non-profit food store in Adams-Morgan.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_64ef2ed13bce9e6fbc794e539345b0ec"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Steve Clark interview: Military family, Air Force Academy 1965-67, Columbia University, Georgetown University January 1968, LBJ won't run, MLK death, aftermath, teaching math, Kent State, revolutionary, despair, Bobby Seale, GW Law School, No Business As Usual, arrested, GLUT food coop, Stone Soup, volunteers, summer 1973, employees, collectives, alternative community, post-shift meetings, Marxism, Marxist study groups, end of Stone Soup, Baltimore, New Communist Movement, Chinese Communism, Communist Workers Party 1979, KKK versus CWP, Greensboro NC march, Ohio for 7 years, community organizer, back to mainstream, back to Washington DC, teaching, writing, socialism versus corporations, social media.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_eaddbc2eb8dcd08ccd55740d8fe154ce" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Columbia Road Children's Center,</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2017/2017">2017 April</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_64a05b9a01d17ee432f0f0ce4bce3d97"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Three staff members (Paulette Saunders, Susie Solf, Faye Allen) from Columbia Road Children's Center in the early 1970s talk about getting their jobs, the ideology of the school, and the long term effects of this multicultural experience on the lives of the students and staff.</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_99fa878915765b49cce4162b8ed3f8d9"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Columbia Road Children's Center interview: Paulette Saunders, interview, Barbara Chambers, Susie Solf, choosing a school, white opening, Faye Allen, a real teacher, history, 1/3 1/3 1/3, multicultural, food choices, community events, play-based, preparation for Grade 1, music, gathering time, songs from all over, what became of the graduates, internationalists, lawyers, doctors, civic minded, lifetime legacy</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_32160bec4029665216b153fed4fb57e1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Dekker, Onka and Sue Solf (Phillips),</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2016/2016">2016 November 15</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7968e4a3e8a837a4a29c1dc3cad714e3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Onka and Susie discuss some of their experiences with the Earth Onion women's improvisational theater group.</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_90ddba25f879b914f6a56c68a279a597"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Onka Dekker and Susie (Solf) Phillips interview: Susie Solf, Onka Dekker, Earth Onion , December, 1970, All Souls Church, rehearsals, Kathy Hadid, National Liberation Front , play about Vietnam, anti-war and feminist, Improv, 3-4 years, tie-dyed t-shirts, tour, the South, Vermont, in a van, "Woman Potion", Lynn Ditchfield, be a watermelon, Charlotte Bunch.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_10f2c873339660fec95f593cc6794cdd" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Drew, James</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2017/2017">2017 January 30</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_1faacfa6389c3d5a739741e372011a00"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>James (Jim) Drew is a lawyer who embedded himself deeply into the civil rights movement, the anti-war movement, and the city of Washington, DC after moving here in 1968. He served two four-year terms as president of the local chapter of the National Lawyers Guild and was legal counsel for the Black Panthers. Jim remains politically active with NLG.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_852db6afed3f29ef3282d318cb415253"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for James Drew interview: National Lawyers Guild (NLG), Thurgood Marshall, Black Panther defense in DC and VA, NLG role at 1968 Democratic Convention, May Day, other events, Infiltration of NLG in Washington DC, Meeting in Vietnam with 500 Vietnamese lawyers, 1965 visit to SNCC in Mississippi as consciousness-changer, Marriage to human rights lawyer Severina Rivera, NLG target for Counter-Intelligence Program (Cointelpro).</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_3d6e2cde2dcb15e03415faa68465f641" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Dugan, James</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2012/2012">2012 December 21</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_f9f240dbb3a4a2f76faee236dfcf9a5c"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Hyattsville native who was Local 6 president in pressmen's 1975-1977 strike at Washington Post.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_dd97d25a45e9b7ace157826a6f6641a2"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for James Dugan interview: Katherine Graham, Eugene O'Sullivan, Sharon Rose, Fred Solowey, Riverdale, MD, Hyattsville, MD, Greenbelt, MD, Riverdale City Council, Ireland, 3 brothers, 2 sisters, Bricklayers Union, Archbishop John Carroll High School, (Mary) McGregor -- wife, 5 children, Washington Daily News, Labor Press, Washington Star, Wall Street Journal, Washington Post, Eugene Meyer, Larry Wallace, Larry Kennelly, Post reprimand letters to homes, status quo – clause in contract, cost of living, Padilla affair, Mike Padilla, wildcat strike, John Prescott, SWAT team, targeted by Post, school for scabs, Southern Production Program, Inc. (SPPI), a/k/a school for scabs", Newspaper Guild, strike for excellence, Carl Bernstein, Bob Woodward, Walter Pincus, open warfare, contract expired, strike authorization, superficial damage (to presse), former noses (parts of the presses), Goss Printing Press Company, scabs, helicopters, White House, Russian Embassy, Teamsters, Channel 5, Roy Meachum, Earl Silbert, indictments, grand jury, 5th amendment, Post anti-union propaganda , grand jury, John Klauss, suicide, workman's compensation, blacklist, Baltimore, grand jury – 100 strikers subpoenaed, David Rein, Joe Forer, no "grand conspiracy", final offer, working conditions, manning restrictions, Katharine Graham: "slit my throat", Charlie Davis, Stereotypers Union, scabs, Plan X (to break strikes), Newspaper Guild, Mailers Union, Charley Scott, Paperhandlers Union, Stereotypers, printers' union, Hubert Humphrey, George McGovern, Roy Meachum, Monsignor George G. Higgins ("labor priest"), D.C. City Council, Davy Marlin-Jones, George Meany, AFL-CIO, Electricians Union, Donald Graham, Mark Meagher, Larry Wallace, Jack McIntosh, Rep. John Conyers, Channel 5 News, Village Voice, "All the President's Men", Kennedy Center, "We Shall Overcome", Dustin Hoffman, Ray Foreman, Ray Collins, Jimmy Ingraham, Charlie Davis, Raffo, wife – Mary Dugan, Fred Solowey, "the left", Irv Riskin, Paul Baker, communists, "good communists", "bad communists", Brint Dillingham, Sam Pizzigati, John Hanrahan, Hari Krishna, Chip Berlet, National Council of Churches, D.C. Council, Fred Solowey, strike play - Chip Berlet, People's Grand Jury, Josephine Butler, Pressman's International, Sol Fishko, strike benefits, Post lawsuit, Jimmy Hoover, $15 million damage suit, Irv Riskin, boycotts, mortgaged house, Dugan liquor store - New Carrollton, Other Dugan liquor store (Capitol Hill), moved to Florida, auto body shop, towing business, Mary Dugan, Local 6 Defense Committee, Chile solidarity, Letelier-Moffitt memorial march, Labor Alliance, Ralph Nader, health/safety tests, Washington Star, Local 6 (Pressmen's), Brint Dillingham, union card, strike situations - Miami, Detroit, high school graduates, Teamsters, Progressive Magazine, (Metropolitan) Labor Council, Newspaper Guild, Labor Film Festival, Dan Dugan, PATCO, liberals, the Reagans, big money for CEOs, Michigan – right-to-work state, Local 6, government unions, Firefighter's Union, emergency medical technicians, complete controls, manning clauses, speed-ups, well-planned assault (on unions), not automation, printers.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_9ab29e555338fe4aafaaa56843fd5b1c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Eisner, David</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2013/2013">2013 June 28</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_104f92c676b9fd509a6ae7591bca02b1"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>U. of Maryland activist during antiwar blockade of Route 1; then owner of head shop Maggie's Farm and boutique until the early 1970s; and owner House of Musical Traditions in Takoma Park since the early 1970s.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_749cd2740a4a06b26b4a8443c3783638"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords for David Eisner interview provided by the donor: House of Musical Traditions, Institute of Musical Traditions, University of Maryland, Maggie's Farm, West Orange, N.J., New York City, Competitive swimmer, University of Maryland, 1966, Swim Coach (Bill) Campbell, Cole Field house, Anne Arundel Hall, Students supported pro-war position, U. Md. conservative campus 1966, U. Md. transformed politically by 1970, Women's dorms, men's dorms 1966, By 1970 co-ed dorms, Denise Levertov, Allen Ginsberg, Speakers against the war, racism, Workers' rights, Students for Democratic Society, Democratic Radical Union of Maryland (DRUM), Narcs, Maryland large military industrial complex, Maryland campuses — Germany, Vietnam, ROTC, McKeldin Library, Route 1, Closing off Route 1, SWAT team, Halftracks, jeeps, teargas, Pepper spray , Shotguns with rock salt, National Guard, Midnight curfew, Dunkin' Donuts, Prince Georges County police, Inter Fraternity Council, Booked concerts Cole Fieldhouse, Sly and the Family Stone, The Dells, "Stay", Armory, Skinner Building, "The Skinner 87", ROTC Building Burned, Maggie's Farm, 1 Columbia Avenue, Takoma Park, military draft ping-pong ball lottery, Beatles #9, Anti-draft centers, Asthma, Hay fever, 1-Y classification, Canada, McGill University, Candlemaking business, Ex-Wax, Maggie's Farm, Pipes, Rolling papers, The Still Point, Incense, Unisex fashions, The Hind Quarter leather shop, Holsters, water beds, Yes bookstore, Meditation, Vegetarian cooking, New Jersey Symphony, Liz Meyer &amp; Friends, J.B. Morrison, Saggita SP??, Childe Harold, Emmylou Harris, House of Musical Traditions, 7040 Carroll Avenue, Takoma Park, Vegetarians, 7th Day Adventists, Arts community, House of Musical Traditions, New York, Appalachian lap dulcimers, Jean Ritchie, L. Ron Hubbard, Scientologists, African thumb piano, Irish bodhran, Greenwich Village, Clubs' no-alcohol sections, John Coltrane, Pharaoh Sanders, Ornette Coleman, East-West fusion sounds, Takoma Cafe, Takoma Park-Silver Spring Food Cooperative, 1981 concerts began, Old Takoma Business Association, Voting rights 16-year-olds, Nuclear-free zone, Drug-free chickens, Takoma Park folk festival, Sammie Abbott, Pete Seeger, Metro, Clarksville, Md., Big Bad Wolf, Soupergirl, Busboys and Poets, Dave Van Ronk.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_5510c30f1988c93b7848d97eb46bf165" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Fenty, Jan Pergol and Susie Solf (Phillips)</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2016/2016">2016 November 15</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f60bb3951effd5b32efb648f1ab18984"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Jan and Susie discuss their experiences in the Women's Movement during 1968-1971.</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_9c2edcdac87edf6cb4025084d3a74626"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Jan Pergot Fenty and Susie (Solf) Phillips interview: Susie Solf, Jan Pergot Fenty, 1968-1971, consciousness raising, married, having children, office on Biltmore Street NW, witty, acting up at Garfinkles, hexed the cosmetics, spells in front of the Capitol, Susie civil rights background, Leftist, Communist, SNCC, None had jobs, Food stamps, Unemployment insurance, Women's welfare rights, Healthcare, Abortion, Marxist Leninist Study Group, Both Susie and Jan were pregnant, Boy babies banned from party, Lesbian take-over, Marriages break up, Susie and Jan leave group, Group withers, Susie starts women's theater, Jan has another baby.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_12f2ca2d6ea8ec4296a75fc39699a175" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Freeway Forum</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2013/2013">2013 September 12</unitdate></did><odd id="aspace_b62a9157c09707015b2d51efa691ef96"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Freeway Forum interview: Angela Rooney, Brookland neighborhood leader in Emergency Committee on Transportation Crisis, Arturo Griffiths, DC Jobs with Justice, Parisa Narouzi, Empower DC, Andria Swanson, Ivy City Civic Association, Derrick Nabors, Amalgamated Transit Union, Local 689, Moderator: John Hanrahan, writer and former executive director of The Fund for Investigative Journalism.</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_88c866d1a0f6c5ae5b5738aace00a1cb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Angela Rooney, Brookland neighborhood leader in Emergency Committee on Transportation Crisis, Arturo Griffiths, DC Jobs with Justice, Parisa Narouzi, Empower DC, Andria Swanson, Ivy City Civic Association, Derrick Nabors, Amalgamated Transit Union, Local 689, Moderator: John Hanrahan, writer and former executive director of The Fund for Investigative Journalism.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3857cb3b48b710441b01c1d40dae3c5e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Golde, Madeleine</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2015/2015">2015 Janury 23</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_0a8126889bea5c8ccfa83d6e34effcc4"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Came to Washington, DC in 1967  in the era of President Johnson's Great Society programs to try to make a difference in terms of social programs for the poor.   During her seven years in HEW, she was an outspoken activist against the war in Vietnam within the federal bureaucracy, including helping to form  government-wide anti-war organizations; launched an underground newspaper that circulated widely throughout the Dept for 5 years, tackling issues ranging from treatment of minorities in HEW, to effectiveness of HEW programs and free speech rights for employees; and helped and played an important role in activating a moribund union local in her Department. For the past 40 years, she has continued to be an active participant in advocating for the rights of workers and the protection of our communities.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_c2b795cff7db19aeb37ad3c8345899d8"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Madeleine Golde interview: Madeleine Golde, 1967, President Johnson, Great Society Program, U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare, HEW, outspoken activist against the war in Vietnam, federal bureaucracy, The Advocate, effectiveness of HEW programs, federal employees, social work and community organization, community organizer, working with low-income people, change in national social policy, anti-war organizing, working on poverty issues, young people going into the government, social change, federal service as a way of making a contribution, Thursday Discussion Group, speaking about problems in federal programs, Toby Moffitt, Rennie Davis, Mike Tigar, Mike Tabor, federal employee petition drive against the War in Vietnam in 1967, The Advocate started in 1968, Petition drive throughout the government, speaking out against the War, fear in the federal government, Hatch Act, education federal employees, wearing buttons, Washington Post, Washington Star, April 1968 printed petition against the War in Vietnam, word of mouth passing around the petition, Mike Ambrose, Chuck Moran, Peter Schenck, I.F.Stone, Federal Employees meet to organize, White House, identifying federal employee leaders, unprecedented event in the federal government, difficulty with bosses, reprimands by bosses, reprimands by the government agencies, money going to the war effort, money that should be going to fight poverty, federal underground paper, employee run paper looking at federal programs, need to be more outspoken about programs not working, February 1968 first issue of The Advocate, mimeographed newspaper, upward mobility in the federal government, Secretary Elliott Richardson, racism in the federal government, racism in HEW, Moratorium activities in federal government, federal programs in Appalachia, President Nixon, Welfare reform programs, President Nixon's State of Union, popular paper in the department, agency underground paper, Rainbow Sign at NIH-NIMH, payment for The Advocate, Editorial staff, Local 41American Federation of Government Employees, AFGE, Central Payroll, U.S. Bond drive in HEW, Anti-Bond drive, Golden List of Non-Subscribers, grievances in the federal government, Mary Ellen Sacco, John Saunders, Betsy Erb, Gary Grassl, David Knudsen, Jeffrey Starkweather, Make programs better, Office of Internal Security, FBI, Federal Employees for Peace, demonstration at the Capitol, FOIA, union organizing, young people coming into the government, moribund federal union, Roy Morgan, President of Local 41, activist unions in the federal government, OEO, Library of Congress, Labor Department, workers' rights, Federal Employees for a Democratic Society (FEDS), Organizing around broad social policy issues, Women's Issues, Civil Rights, Federal employees rallies, Lafayette Park, May Day in 1971, federal employees in May Day, Marching to the Capitol, Dr. Spock at NIH in 1970, Dr. Daniel Ellsberg dinner – September 1971, Federal Employees for Peace (FEP), FEP dinner for Dr. Ellsberg, awards dinner, Pentagon Papers, Code of Ethics of Federal Service, Natasha Reatig, Federal Employees for Peace Banner, Press coverage of Daniel Ellsberg, Suing the government over right to speak, Secretary Wilbur Cohen, ACLU, First Amendment issues, changing conditions for federal employees, Expanding consciousness among federal employees, Federal employee discussion groups, Effecting federal programs and policies, Norman Oslik, IPS - Institute for Policy Studies, Workplace organizing, Issues of Health and Safety, Progressive Cheverly, Ferment in the 60's, Government survellience, Commitment to public service.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_8de7bed9f5544b4b246fd3841a17f130" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Gottlieb, Sanford</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2013/2013">2013 April 12</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_b4798bbb6c98de861610bdeeec284361"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Head of SANE (Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy), which was a major organizer of Vietnam antiwar protests; a key lobbyist in support of the partial nuclear test-ban treaty between the United States and the Soviet Union.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_e3b15a89d6aa6fee363782d8a5180143"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Sanford Gottlieb interview: American University School of International Service, National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy, SANE, Brooklyn, Father con-man, federal prison, mail fraud, Great Depression, Abyssinia, Ethiopia, Hitler, Japanse militarism, City College New York, Brooklyn College, Navy, Dartmouth College, Married 1947, Paris 5 years, School of Political Science — Paris, Doctoral Sorbonne, Joe McCarthy, Correspondent French news weekly, Labor movement, Organizer 2 local unions New York, International Typographical Union, Labor's Daily, International Union Electrical Workers, AFSCME sellout, National Committee for A Sane Nuclear Policy, SANE, Nuclear testing — U.S. and Soviet Union, Newspaper ads for SANE/nuclear testing, Washington, D.C. SANE affiliate group, SANE political action director, Grassroots campaign to end all nuclear tests, SANE executive director in 1967, Cold War mindset, Soviet Union, Pacifists, World Federalists, World government, Joe McCarthy, Congressional witch hunts, Working for peace- analogous to traitors in public mind, Friends Committee on National Legislation, United Church of Christ, Unitarians, Nuclear test-ban treaty, Women's Strike for Peace, Direct-action, Peace movement was minority, President Kennedy, Cautious, but open, Democrat, Norman Cousins, Saturday Review of Literature, Cousins influenced Kennedy, Partial test-ban treaty passed, Nuclear tests banned atmosphere, under water, Radioactive fallout, Series ads New York Times, Dr. Benjamin Spock ad, Dangers of fallout, Dr. Homer Jack, Unitarian minister, Kennedy coalition for test-ban treaty, United Auto Workers, National Farmers Union, Public trusted government until Vietnam, Kennedy American University speech June 1963, Called for an end to the Cold War, Soviet Union, Spread of nuclear weapons, Arms race, Lyndon Johnson, Vietnam, Tonkin Gulf incident, escalation, SANE sought negotiated settlement, 1964 SANE petition for neutral North and South Vietnam, Professor Hans Morgenthau, Bernard Fall, Bombing of North Vietnam, Dr. Spock, Professor H. Stuart Hughes, Telegram to LBJ, SANE in moderate wing of antiwar movement, SDS, Students for a Democratic Society, First antiwar rally April 1965, SANE sponsored first non-student, anti-war march on Washington, November 1965, Coalition of SANE and more radical and moderate groups, 35,000 attended, Sylvan Theater, Washington Monument, Norman Thomas, Coretta Scott King, Edwin Dahlberg, American Northern Baptist Convention, Negotiated peace in Vietnam, Immediate pullout of troops, Vietcong flags, Pro-Chinese Communist group, Tried to keep them out, New York Times, Washington Post, Mainstream press focused on middle-class participants, Radical wing increasing in numbers, Street action vs. electoral action, TV covered most flamboyant forms of protest, Flag burnings, 1968 majority against war, 1968 majority also against war protesters, Middle America, patriotism, Youth revolt against authority, "Silent Majority", Richard Nixon, Hubert Humphrey, Norman Cousins, Ghost-writer for Humphrey in 1960, Senate Disarmament Subcommittee chairman, Humphrey became lapdog of LBJ, Humphrey denounced student protestors, November 1965 — Cousins, Homer Jack, Gottlieb met with VP Humphrey, Humphrey attacked students protesters, Reminded him of Commies he used to know in Minneapolis, Not in '50s anymore; not in Minneapolis, anymore, Students aren't commies, Washington Post, Vietnam Day Committee, Dump Johnson Movement, Allard Lowenstein, Endorsed Eugene McCarthy, New Hampshire, Bobby Kennedy, George McGovern, Assassinations of Martin Luther King, Bobby Kennedy, "Peace plank" at Democratic National Convention 1968, Chicago police riot, Public supported police, Hubert Humphrey, Richard Nixon, Dr. Spock split from SANE 1967, Spock wanted to be bolder, less cautious, SANE board division over who to protest with, Spock said demonstrate with anybody, Spock left board in split, Ran for president 1972, Julius Hobson Spock runningmate, Marcus Raskin, William Sloane Coffin, Dr. Spock indicted, Allegedly conseled draft resistance, SANE/Freeze, Indictment chill through antiwar movement, Freedom of Information Act, FBI at SANE's meetings, Informers, Army Intelligence, CIA, Opened one piece of domestic mail, SANE on Nixon's "enemies list", National Liberation Front (NLF), First French Indochina War, Paris lived with Vietnamese students, Vietnamese nationalism, Invasions from China, Japanese invasion, Occupation by French, Bernard Fall, American Friends Service Committee, South Vietnam, Went with clergy on fact-finding trip South Vietnam 1965, Saturday Review, Norman Cousins, Algiers, Paris, Met diplomats National Liberation Front, Vietcong, White House, North and South Vietnamese Communists, Algiers, Prague, Moscow, Warsaw, U.S. botched 1966 peace effort, North Vietnam, Lyndon Johnson, Richard Nixon, Expanded war to Cambodia, Moratorium — 1969, Moderate students in antiwar movement, Sam Brown and others, Organize communities stop work, stop classes, Demonstrations, debates, lectures, Nixon administration, War Powers Act, SANE role in, SANE opposed increased military spending, arms race, Opposed B-1 bomber, anti-ballistic missile system (ABM), Soviet Union, Cuban Missile Crisis 1962, University of Michigan, Marcus Raskin called, Soviet missiles in Cuba, "A dangerous leaker", United Nations, Patriotism, National security, Threats to the United States, Need recognize threats without exaggerating threats, Not automatically resort military force, Left SANE 1977, New Directions organization, Panama Canal treaty, Reagan period, United Campuses Against Nuclear War (UCAN), Stundet/faculty teach-ins, Union of Concerned Scientists, Center for Defense Information, Admiral Eugene LaRocque, America's Defense Monitor — war/peace issues, PBS stations, Vietnam, Radical forms of protest, Movement neutralized, Did not end the war, Prevented some of worst of Johnson administration potential excesses, Didn't bomb dikes in Vietnam, Richard Nixon, Silent Majority, Nuclear testing period, Major goal partially achieved, Small coalition on nuclear treaty, JFK receptive, Feminist movement.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_04e571495aa365f2819b025a9ea93fa5" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Grosman, Art</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2013/2013">2013 January 24</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_a3b48fe9d66fbef10b6e7e451bb189c9"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>A civil rights and antiwar activist while a student at Howard University in the early 1960s, Art Grosman made his biggest mark on local activism beginning in 1966 as one of the co-founders of the Washington Free Press. The WFP was the first and most influential D.C. underground newspaper for almost 4 years, folding after constantly being subjected to police suppression, infiltrators, and FBI pressures against printers. </p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_3aa3c93cfbfbe4f667fb36a2b2f90f40"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Art Grosman interview: Turkey, Mediterranean Sea, Grosman parents immigrants, Ukraine, Japanese, Poland, Nebraska, B'nai B'rith, Orthodox Jewish school, FDR administration, Democrats, voting rights D.C., Hebrew Academy, trees in Israel, Palestinian, Army-McCarthy hearing, Sears (&amp; Roebuck), Howard University, studied physics, voter registration, Mississippi, Texas, 4th and Decatur Streets, blockbusting, Chevy Chase, D.C., Lafayette (Elementary School), Alice Deal (Junior High School), Wilson (High School), Old Soldiers Home, Ben's Chili Bowl, League of Women Voters, Mississippi, Cold War, Russians, conscientious objector, Howard U., ROTC, ACLU, Peace Club (Howard U.), Army, Vietnam, the draft, Washington Free Press, General (Lewis) Hershey, Selective Service System, civil rights, Frank Speltz (WFP co-founder), Tasso's Bar, George Washington University (GWU), intercollegiate newspaper, Catholic University, American University , George Washington University , Georgetown University, University of Maryland , Trinity College, Dick Ochs, Sheila Ryan, Gabe Huck, Tony Gittens, Woody (NO LAST NAME), SDS (Students for a Democratic Society), Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party), Atlantic City (Democratic convention), Howard University, Fairmont Street/Girard Street slumlord, Washington Free Press, communists (of all shades), Coca-Cola, Maoists, Leninists, taxi driver, Washington Free Press first office, 1727 or 1737 Q Street NW, Carla (artist, NO LAST NAME), 10,000 copies at first, 30,000 later, maybe 100,000, John Hagerhorst , Frederick (Md.), (Washington) Free Press, advertisers, hippie shops, head shops, bars, big ads record companies, federal government.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_e05da92739b856c252288573e2420577" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Hanrahan, Debby</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2016/2016">2016 October 28</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_b4df8450c570fd2e31aaa782d2c84dcd"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Debby Hanrahan has a 50-plus-year history of local activism in civil rights, social justice and antiwar campaigns. From the '60s and '70s, these include the continuing decades-long fight for D.C. statehood; the successful citizen campaign to stop destructive freeways through the heart of D.C.; the local organizing around the United Farmworkers Union grape boycott. Since then, her activism has included local public school advocacy; successful petitioning for statehood, nuclear freeze and medical marijuana ballot initiatives; and rallying and marching repeatedly against U.S. wars and for whistleblowers. </p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_5240bfefb34f1b58faea567cfb9a916a"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Debby Hanrahan interview: Bethesda, Maryland, Chevy Chase, Maryland, ambassador, Iran, "Negro problem", Dick Abel, Walt Whitman High School, Skidmore College, Senator Saltonstall, Rep. James Corman, March on Washington, Danville, Virginia, Martin Luther King, mass arrests, Larry Aaronsen, Peace Corps, President Kennedy, John Coyne, Ethiopia, Temuco (Chile), rural mobile birth control project, Dr. Lopez, IUDs, Mapuche Indians, plantation owners, rubella, class system, Peace Corps, Eduardo Frei, mothers' center, sewing machines, AID, (Frank Barger) father ill, Dump Johnson movement, Al Lowenstein, Bella Abzug, Harold Ickes, Curtis Gans, Julius Hobson, Al Lowenstein, Long Island, Eugene McCarthy, Bobby Kennedy, George McGovern, Al Lowenstein, Harold Ickes, Dump Johnson movement, Eugene McCarthy, Julius Hobson, Suzie Solf, Julius Hobson, Hobson v. Hansen lawsuit, equalize school expenditures, track system, Dunbar High School, Julius Hobson, Marxist, atheist, Hobson gimmicks, rat problem, Georgetown, Anacostia, freeway fight, Sammie Abbott, Marion Barry, Reginald Booker, Julius Hobson, Charles Cassell, paddy wagon, North Central Freeway, Brookland, Sammie Abbott, elected school board, non-voting delegate to Congress, D.C. Statehood Party, Lou Aronica, Josephine Butler, labor organizer, D.C. Lung Association, D.C. Statehood Party central committee, Ed Guinan, statehood initiative, constitutional convention, Mitch Snyder, Center for Creative Non-violence (CCNV), Rich Bruning, Ward 1, D.C. constitution, 1968, Brint Dillingham, Compeers, Grape Boycott, Eugene McCarthy, Chicago Democratic Convention, housing , civil rights, John Dillingham, Catholics, National Guard, Grant Park, police riot, Dick Gregory, Clinton Bamberger, Catholic University Law School, "Fuck Mayor Dailey", tear gas, Maryland delegation hospitality suite, Maryland House Speaker Thomas Hunter Lowe, Brint Dillingham, Compeers, Freedom House, Washington Free Press, grape boycott, blood on grapes, Giant supermarket , Michael Tabor, picket lines, Safeway, Brint Dillingham, John Dillingham, Santa Claus suits, International Safeway, Martha Tabor, Dupont Circle, Freedom House, Washington Free Press, Montgomery County police, Circuit Court , grand jury investigation, anti-war movement, St. Thomas Church, Joe Forer, Ober Law, anti-free speech, McCarthy era, Hilda Mason, D.C. public schools, Charlie Mason, Lawrence Guyot, Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, StandUp for Democracy (organization), Lawrence Guyot, Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, Freedom Summer, Lawrence Guyot, All Souls Unitarian Church, Hilda Mason, Charles Mason, Lawrence Guyot, hippie trail, London to Nepal, Rep. Yvonne Braithwaite Burke, Washington Post, Local Pressmen's Union, Washington Post, Josephine Butler, Alaska, grand jury investigation, 5th amendment, Jim Dugan, Joe Forer, David Rein, Jim Dugan, Hilda Mason, University of the District of Columbia Law School, clinical public-interest approach to law, D.C. City Council, David Clarke, Hilda Mason, John Wilson, Wilhelmina Rolark, Howard University Law School, Washington Post, Charlie Mason, UDC Law School, Wayne Turner, Chris Otten, Mark Borbely, nuclear freeze initiative, Susan Abbott, Leonard Bernstein, Hubert Leckie, Washington National Cathedral, Barbara Hendricks, Jessye Norman, Leonard Bernstein.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_7809b1cd2b392d3d9f5ac27c98f95ed2" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Hanrahan, John</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2016/2016">2016 June 02</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_43e55c1dccb43c83558bbcbd8ffa6606"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Former Washington Post reporter/union activist in support of 1975 pressmen's strike at the Post; also a DC community activist on voting rights, other local issues. </p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_2b03404be3b117e46322ca6429ab32da"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for John Hanrahan interview: Childhood, Iowa, unions, progressive, conservative, local newspaper, 1958-1960 university, the draft, Ft. Jackson, Army journalist, Davenport newspaper, Washington DC, plentiful jobs, Montgomery Sentinel, Washington Star, Washington Post, Mike Tabor, 1965, ACCESS, the Dillinghams, Debby, 1968 Democratic Convention, grape boycott, 1970, Honor America Day, "Fuck Billy Graham", tear gas, 1972 Debby &amp; John travel for a year overland to India, Washington Post goes public, "school for scabs", 1971 walkout by pressmen, 1974 withholding of excellence, newspaper guild panics, guild meeting Oct 1, 1975, pressmen damaged machinery ?…NO ! but the presses could not operate, newspaper guild meeting, class conflict, control of the pressroom, picket lines, line crossers, many go back, pressmen suffer, AFL-CIO no help, DC Council supports, life as a free-lancer, books, Lost Frontier, Government by Contract, local activism, Statehood Party, stadium give-aways, McMillan Park, newspaper ad, dinner with Donnie Graham, support in Congress, errors in reporting, Sam Smith, All the President's Men, Esquire 1977 "Last Angry Men", Carl Bernstein, Eugene Debs, Brint Dillingham, funniest man in the world.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_25c171c3c85274a59df907b5b4c10f73" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Harrington, Richard</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2013/2013">2013 February 08</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_cd079bb892d891bc5a3fca55b94a7c8c"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Editor of alternative publications Woodwind and Unicorn Times, chronicler of D.C. music scene for more than 40 years with first the alternative press and then the Washington Post.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_f3d44daf09de0ce48add32e707ea6497"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Richard Harrington interview: Journalist, schooling, dropout, folk singer, Garret Players Susan Sarandon, Lorton, Washington Star, Unicorn Times, Washington Post fulltime 1980, McClean Gardens, Glen Echo, Quicksilver Times, CIA plant, hippies v. activists, Georgetown counter-culture, sex drugs and rock and roll, Washington Free Clinic, Woodwind, arts newspaper, Quicksilver Times editor, Bohemian Caverns, Cellar Door, Childe Harold, local musicians, Emergency.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_9127f5380463c13b08ad4cd0d5b3202c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Hassan, Sandra Barrett</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2013/2013">2013 April 26</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_f932050b4a1f7618bb5d71a2ddce927c"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Third generation Washingtonian who was a Howard University civil rights activist, later an education and community organizer. Met Malcom X at the 1963 March for Jobs and Freedom. Also an artist and maker of quilts that chronicle the civil rights movement.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_69c29633fa5c88ec28ac1a19e0f90eb9"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Sandy Barrett Hassan inteview: Sandra Barrett Hassan, Washington DC, Northeast, Negro, segregated school, petition, Ivy City, swimming at Union Station, black areas, Western High School, activist parents, Howard University, Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee, testing restaurants in Virginia, March on Washington, Malcolm X, African Heritage Dancers and Drummers, 1968 riots, Julius Hobson.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_4b2dfc2815c2bccff262ea1282e693be" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Herz, Lillian Peterson</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019-05-17/2019-05-17">2019 May 17</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_23c7ed934369a1f8860918665f5e72b6"><head>Biography</head><p>Information provided by the donor: Lillian Peterson Herz discusses her pacifist upbringing and beliefs that led to her involvement in the civil rights movement, including SNCC voter registration campaigns in Georgia and Mississippi, and efforts to end the war in Vietnam.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_5530b0d857a94d1c4fe8a56a3b57388c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Information provided by the donor: Lillian Peterson Herz discusses her pacifist upbringing and beliefs that led to her involvement in the civil rights movement, including SNCC voter registration campaigns in Georgia and Mississippi, and efforts to end the war in Vietnam.</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_3024a0f8de956448717e7dcd097bba29"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided the donor: <br/>
Georgetown University School of Foreign Service, arrived 1965, first group of women, pacifist family upbringing, disabled father, Paradise California, high school civics teacher Virginia Franklin taught all forms of government, John Birch society, social justice, civil rights, Georgetown University Community Action Program, tutoring, Albany Georgia, SNCC, voter registration, Bob Jackel – Jesuit priest, Anne Gallivan, bus boycott, O. Roy Chalk, racism, economic divisions, home rule, foreign policy – self interest vs building a better world, Southwest Georgia voting project, SNCC Freedom House, Moultrie Georgia, black fear, white power structure, Sunflower County Mississippi, Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, Fannie Lou Hamer, caring community, mass meetings, constitutional rights, Father McSorley, seminar on just war, alternatives to war, just peace, reaffirmed pacifism and social justice, Healy Hall, anti-Vietnam War, teach-ins, speak-outs, Bill Clinton – student leader at Georgetown, Mobilization Against the War rally 1967 – New York City, Pentagon March 1967, draft burnings, endless wars, movement vs lifestyles, live your lifestyle, construction, home improvement, social worker, AFDC – Aid to Families with Dependent Children, NWRO – National Welfare Rights Organization, institutionalized racism, Vietnam veteran, fixed homes of poor people, profit sharing, Desert Storm, Peace Resource Center, 9/11, Cuba,-1999, Pastors for Peace, Code Pink, ANSWER Coalition, Venezuelan Embassy, U.S. lawlessness.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_2c25ea918ad2a5fa2e77b355aeaba424" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Hilda Mason Remembered,</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2010/2010">2010 May 09</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_736687baffb5b2fe2480b62d1ba32328"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Hilda (1916-2007) and Charles (Charlie) Mason are remembered by Lawrence Guyot and Debbie Hanrahan - donated to the Lessons of the Sixties Project by the D.C. Statehood Green Party. Hilda and Charlie were Washington, D.C.'s most significant activist couple from the early 1960s to the 2000s. From the time they were married until their deaths 40-some years later, Hilda -- the public school teacher and assistant principal and great granddaughter of a slave -- and Charlie -- the government civil servant, later attorney, and heir to a sizable fortune -- were seldom referred to in the singular; to those in the activist and electoral politics communities, they were always one entity -- Hilda and Charlie.</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_88e270caa3a7057493d271c0a69ae971"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Hilda Mason interview: DC Statehood Green Party, Hilda Howland Mason, civil rights movement, environmental movement, anti-nuclear movement, Debby Hanrahan, Lawrence Guyot, Mississippi, Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC), Freedom Summer, Hattiesburg Missisissippi, Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party (MFDP), Guyot chair of MFDP, Democratic National Convention 1964, Atlantic City New Jersey, ANC commissioner, Winona Mississippi, Fanny Lou Hamer, "Pillar of Fire" book, Taylor Branch, SNCC, Marion Barry, Elizabeth Levy, Charlie and Hilda Mason, Fannie Lou Hamer, Charlie Mason, All-Souls Unitarian Church, Mississippi Freedom Democratic Parsty (MFDP), Guyot/MFDP "too radical" for church, Hilda threatens to leave church, Guyot allowed to speak, DC Council, 1964-1968 movement into electoral politics, values of civil rights movement, left depended on Hilda Mason, David Clarke School of Law (University of the District of Columbia), Hilda/Charlie kept it alive, Washington Post opposed, Hilda ran to keep school opened, Ranked 10 of 188 for public interest law, 51% minority student body, U.S. News &amp; World Report rankings, UDC Law School ranked first for progressive students , Attracts community organizers, Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, Fund-raiser at All Souls Uitarian Church, Raised $4000 for bail, Elizabeth Levy, (Rep. Robert) Kastenmeier, ANCs (Advisory Neighborhood Commissions, Hilda Mason, Julius Hobson, Josephine Butler, D.C. Statehood Green Party, D.C. Constitutional Convention, Bottle bill, Nuclear freeze, D.C. School Board, Charlie Mason, Ivanhoe Donaldson, Josephine Butler, Hilda's grandson Nestor, Contributions to organizations, Never expected anything in return, Ella Baker, Saved the UDC law school, Mayor Tony Williams, Models for philanthropy, Moved easily from activism to politics, Book "Hilda", By Caroline Nicholas (daughter), DC City Council, DC Youth Orchestra, Nurses in schools, Howard University Law School, Fannie Lou Hamer, Ella Baker, Septima Clark, Josephine Butler, Maine, Hilda/Charlie partnership, Set ethical standard, Josephine Butler, Russia, Margaret and Al McSurely, Senate Internal Security Subcommittee, Pike County Kentucky, Center for Constitutional Rights, Charlie financed the case, Guyot's religious beliefs, Empower people, Hilda Mason, Ella Baker, Guyot police beatings, SNCC, Community organizing, Racial Reconciliation organization, Oxford Mississipi, Tallahatchie County Mississippi, Taylor Branch, Philadelphia Missisippi, Macomb Mississippi, School bombings, Role of religion, Guyot's ongoing projects, Successful movements, Empowerment, Same-sex marriage, Free and independent Palestine, Comprehensive immigration.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_9579474a77550f4b1765a26cc93fdaa3" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Hobson, Tina (Part 1)</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2013/2013">2013 May 03</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_85dcc9eece5cedf9439812e3145a2caf"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>An environmental and clean energy activist, Tina spent many years in various government posts in which she promoted civil rights, improved equal opportunities for women in the federal government, and worked with employment and training programs to assist the poor. During her interview for the Lessons of the 60s project, Tina spoke extensively about her late husband, Julius Hobson, the famed D.C. civil rights leader (and later D.C. Council member), whose leadership was most responsible for ending discrimination in hiring in local retail stores and in overturning racially discriminatory practices in the city's public schools.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_c9dc524b6097447c50b8dc9831223ab1"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Tina Hobson interview: Julius Hobson, Birmingham, Alabama, World War II, Howard University, Masters in economics, DC Chapter Congress of Racial Equality (CORE), Ran picket lines retailers, Desegregation created 5,000 jobs, Anti-freeway fight, Hobson v. Hansen lawsuit, Track system, D.C. Statehood Party, Antiwar activities, Vice presidential candidate to Dr. Benjamin Spock 1972, She born in Seattle, Lived China, Stanford University, President Kennedy, Washington, D.C., Met Julius Hobson 1967, National Institute of Public Affairs, Ford Foundation, Hobson v. Hansen case, D.C.'s appointed City Council, Mayor Walter Washington, DC Board of Education, Married in 1969, "The Damned Children", Blackest kids in lowest tracks, Teachers and Hobson v Hansen, Sterling Tucker, Equalization school resources, Civil Service Commission, Babies segregated in hospitals, O.C. Hall, Washington Hospital Center, Black churches, Civil Service Commission, Department of Energy, Always well-dressed, fedora, Excellent cook, Didn't drink, Cleaned the house, Ironed own shirts, Department of Health, Education and Welfare (HEW), Loved opera , Army in Italy, Elected school board at-large, Lost school board reelection, Civil Service Commission (CSC), Federal women's program at CSC, Discrimination against women, Julius "blind spot" , Discrimination against women, federal discrimination lawsuit, African-Americans, other minorities, women, Peace marches, Bermuda, Marriage more acceptable to white, than black, community, Julius and Tom Hayden.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_781f12f7dcc8da1fb61be54f9b530a38" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Hobson, Tina (Part 2)</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2018/2018">2018 February 13</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_f3c05a316e75d93e48b4dfc4d24c8db8"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>An environmental and clean energy activist, Tina spent many years in various government posts in which she promoted civil rights, improved equal opportunities for women in the federal government, and worked with employment and training programs to assist the poor. During her interview for the Lessons of the 60s project, Tina spoke extensively about her late husband, Julius Hobson, the famed D.C. civil rights leader (and later D.C. Council member), whose leadership was most responsible for ending discrimination in hiring in local retail stores and in overturning racially discriminatory practices in the city's public schools.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_fd0d0e0c635a8889f2945034dfc05d12"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Tina Hobson interview: Julius Hobson, Birmingham, Alabama, World War II, Howard University, Masters in economics, DC Chapter Congress of Racial Equality (CORE), Ran picket lines retailers, Desegregation created 5,000 jobs, Anti-freeway fight, Hobson v. Hansen lawsuit, Track system, D.C. Statehood Party, Antiwar activities, Vice presidential candidate to Dr. Benjamin Spock 1972, She born in Seattle, Lived China, Stanford University, President Kennedy, Washington, D.C., Met Julius Hobson 1967, National Institute of Public Affairs, Ford Foundation, Hobson v. Hansen case, D.C.'s appointed City Council, Mayor Walter Washington, DC Board of Education, Married in 1969, "The Damned Children", Blackest kids in lowest tracks, Teachers and Hobson v Hansen, Sterling Tucker, Equalization school resources, Civil Service Commission, Babies segregated in hospitals, O.C. Hall, Washington Hospital Center, Black churches, Civil Service Commission, Department of Energy, Always well-dressed, fedora, Excellent cook, Didn't drink, Cleaned the house, Ironed own shirts, Department of Health, Education and Welfare (HEW), Loved opera , Army in Italy, Elected school board at-large, Lost school board reelection, Civil Service Commission (CSC), Federal women's program at CSC, Discrimination against women, Julius "blind spot" , Discrimination against women, federal discrimination lawsuit, African-Americans, other minorities, women, Peace marches, Bermuda, Marriage more acceptable to white, than black, community, Julius and Tom Hayden.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_311c5fd444f4c51a860d9f8f704c6301" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Huff, Julie</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2016/2016">2016 August 11</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_88cf4395f17b0432021be5860287cf55"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Julie Huff grew up in Birmingham, Alabama and Atlanta, Georgia in the 1950s and 1960s. Exposure to segregation, the civil rights movement in the early 1960s and the anti-war movement led her to a lifetime of activism for civil rights and women's rights and against the vietnam war, beginning in high school and continuing in the Washington, D.C. area following college. She later became a nurse and worked in women's health and public health for over 30 years.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_fca552b12efde98bbd423cb2fefc2c8e"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Julie Huff interview: public health nurse, born and raised in deep south, Birmingham Alabama until age 13, Atlanta Georgia until college, 1950s idyllic childhood, segregated but economically diverse public school, bookish child intellectual, civil rights movement, Bull Conner, sneak out to rallies and hootenanies, campaigned for Lyndon Johnson, Governor's Honors Program – first integrated student program in Georgia – between sophomore and junior years, Macon Georgia, stares, spit, menace, radicalizing experience, TWTWTW – that was the week that was – skit got advisor fired, New College in Sarasota Florida, culture shock, housing co-op conference in DC in senior year, intentional community, sexual harassment from two male friends, clinically depressed, moved to DC – District of Columbia, intentional housing – shared everything – rent food cloths, anti-war activist, women's movement, consciousness raising, imperialism, WITCH – Women's International Terrorist Conspiracy from Hell, United Fruit, guerrilla theater, birth control pills, abortion counseling, Off Our Backs, column – The Garbage and the Flowers, librarian, waitress, pregnant February 1970, not ready for a child, New York only safe place for abortion, DC required psychiatric assessment of threat to mother's health, private hospitals – pro forma process, DC General Hospital refused therapeutic abortions, lead plaintiff in class action lawsuit against DC General, injunction, several court hearings, back-up plan: private doctor at George Washington University, two psychiatric letters, humiliating, attest to wanting to kill herself, dupe of ACLU, felt no shame, support of women's movement, worse today, diaphragm, contraceptive failure, pill caused migraines, Washington Free Clinic, Mary Doe et. al. Plaintiffs vs General Hospital of District of Columbia, judge ruled against March 1970, final victory 1974, William Nussbaum and Carolyn Nickerson - lawyers, women's health, women's theater, Earth Onion Theater Group, workshops for women's empowerment, Black Box poetry magazine, ACLU prison project, nursing school – Catholic University, women's health and public health for over 30 years, Arlington County, lessons – find partnerships with people and organizations, Venceremos Brigade 1971, cut sugarcane, toured Cuba, democracy spring for campaign finance, people's lives on the line, role of draft in anti-war movement, Black Lives matter, gun violence, gun control activism.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_827963252117fff70d23038603f3f7ea" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Kranz, Sharlene</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2015/2015">2015 August 25</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_7e38fb5d1c1d92de6b6c22cb2a060fc1"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>High school civil rights activist who staffed the Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party (MFDP) office in Washington, D.C. during the summer of 1964, when the MFDP challenged the legitimacy of the Mississippi delegation at the Democratic Party convention in Atlantic City. Also, an early member of Jews for Urban Justice. </p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_ea65a31648a1124a864029ad7ab908f8"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Sharlene Kranz interview: Worker bee, middle school, union activities, activist family, SNCC at Howard U.,SNCC Conference 1963, STUDENTS AGAINST DISCRIMINATION, Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, Fannie Lou Hamer, Scherner and Goodwin and Chaney, Rita Scherner, Democratic Convention 1964, Joseph Rauh, Eleanor Holmes, SNCC New York, SNCC Washington, Marion Barry, bus boycott, white members of SNCC, housing, covenants, ACCESS, Charlie Jones, military bases, segregated housing, Maryland and Virginia apartments, 1968 Fair Housing Law, Jews for Urban Justice, anti-ICBM, grape boycott, anti-war.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_3d180ba7e11cb82b83cf29752cb877c6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Kuntzler, Paul</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2016/2016">2016 February 12</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_3f1cdc6733e301cc692da644b07806a3"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Paul Kuntzler has been one of the most influential figures in the Washington, D.C. gay rights movement for well over 50 years. No one, aside from Franklin Kameny, the founder of the D.C. Mattachine Society, has had a bigger impact over the last 5 decades. From his membership on the board of the Mattachine Society at age 19, to the first gay rights protest at the White House in 1965, to his roles in the establishment of the Gay and Lesbian Activists Alliance, the creation of the Getrude Stein Democratic Club, and the development of the gay/lesbian community into one of the city's most potent political forces, Paul has been in the forefront of the movement right on down to the present day. </p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_b9fef8b21cfb9c9d3ecfd15c1809ffe1"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Paul Kuntzler interview: Washington, D.C. Gay Rights Movement, Paul Kuntzler, Franklin Kameny, Mattachine Society, White house first gay protest April 1965, Gay Activists Alliance, Gertrude Stein Democratic Club, Detroit, Grosse Pointe Woods, Michigan, large Catholic family, United Auto Workers, working class family, Detroit News, St. Joan of Arc Grade School, Notre Dame High School, 1952 and 1956 Republican and Democratic conventions, Adlai Stevenson, Sen. Estes Kefauver, John F. Kennedy, Anchorage, Alaska, Detroit Metropolitan Airport, pictured with JFK, Detroit News, Donna Kuntzler, campaigned for JFK, Dennis Reck??? Rudd?, Grosse Pointe Young Democrats, 14th congressional district headquarters, door-to-door, JFK's inauguration, Young Democratic Inaugural Ball, Mayflower Hotel, Lyndon Johnson, Lady Bird Johnson, Bobby Kennedy, Grosse Pointe Young Democrats, Toledo, Ohio, Greyhound Bus, Hollywood, gay people go Toledo, New Year's Eve, 3.2 beer in Ohio at 18, The Scenic (Bar), Toledo, The Pink Elephant (D.C. gay bar), Mayflower Hotel, Harrington Hotel, Carol's (Bar), D.C., Dupont Circle, Copper Skillet, N and Connecticute, Doug Tate, Gabe Price CHEKK, forst gay party, Georgetown Grill , Chicken Hut, Johnny's, first 3 main gay bars in D.C., E.J. McDevitt's card shop, The Homosexual in America (book), Bellevue Stratford Hotel, Doug Tate, Jesse Stern (author), The Sixth Man (book), gay rights movement, Statler Hilton Hotel, Hartman Hall, rooming houses, Scholl's Cafeteria, Washington Post, Union Trust Company, openly expressed racism, Union Trust whites-only hiring, Silver Spring, Md., Paul Levine, Giant (supermarket), Chicken Hut, Howard, Bill Fly, manager, Dr. Franklin Kameny, Mattachine Society, Adams Morgan neighborhood, Earl Aikins (sp?), Mattachine board of directors, Janus Society, Daughters of Bilitis, Barbara Gittings, Golden Gate YMCA, Hal Kall, San Francisco Mattachine Society, Frank Kameny, Court of Appeals brief, homophile literature, Dr. Evelyn Hooker, gays, lesbians prohibited working, federal government, D.C. government, security clearances, American Psychiatric Association, homosexuality mental illness, Bruce Scott, Frank Kameny, Robert Dellinger, Philadelphia, Barbara Gittings, planning conference, ECHO, East Coast Homophile Organization CHEKK, Frank Kameny, All the Way Home (Kuntzler short story), Scott fired, Department of Labor, because gay, Frank Kameny, disorderly conduct, U.S. Navy Map Service, Kameny fired because gay, Edgar Hoover and gays, Mattachine Society, Frank Kameny -- co-founder, Ph.D Harvard-astronomy, Jack Nichols -- co-founder, April 17, 1965, first anti-Vietnam War demonstration (SDS), also first White House gay rights protest, 7 men, 3 women protesters, Jack Nichols, Frank Kameny, Lily Vincennes, Gail Green, Robert Dellinger, ABC television network, Afro American newspaper, picketed State Department, U.S. Civil Service Commission, Secretary of State Dean Rusk, Office of Naval Intelligence, Stephen Brent Miller, Chicken Hut, Stenotype Institute of Washington, House Appropriations Committee, All Souls Unitarian Church, Dean Duncan Howlett, John Kennedy, RKO Keith's Theater, Old Ebbitt Grill, The Children's Hour, Shirley Maclaine, Audrey Hepburn, Lillian Hellman, D.C. Transit, Roy Chalk, Frank Kameny, George Washington University Hospital, Volkswagen, Rehoboth Beach, Delaware, Philadelphia, First Gay rights Picket, Independence Hall, Avenue Restaurant, Richard Davidson, Randy Wicker, John James, LGBT Retirement Home, Philadelphia, PBS, Washington Post, New York Times, Independence Hall, Philadelphia Pops Concert, Philadelphia Mayor Michael Nutter, Mattachine Society, Bill Donovan, Office of Naval Intelligence, Chicken Hut, Central Intelligence Agency, Frank Kameny, Barbara Gittings, "Gay Is Good", ECHO (East Coast Homophile Organizations), Dr. Albert Ellis, APA, Sheraton Wardman Park Hotel, Wardell Pomeroy , Kinsey Institute, American Nazi Party, Rabbi Eugene Lipman, Barbizon Plaza, Lillian Vincennes, Mattachine Society, confrontation tactics, Jim Foster, Alice B. Toklas Gay Democratic Club (San Francisco), 1972 and 1976 Democratic National Conventions, David Carliner, Bruce Scott , National Capital Area Chapter ACLU, Office of Naval Intelligence, Hoover Reporting Company, Don Crawford, Perry Redford, pseudonyms, Mattachine Society, Paul LeMay (alias), Frank Kameny , Bruce Scott, Stonewall, JFK assassination, Vietnam War, anti-war movement/demonstrations, civil rights movement, Martin Luther King Jr., March on Washington for Jobs and Freedom, United Auto Workers, I Have a Dream Speech, General Ulysses S. Grant, Civil War, Georgetownn University, New Hampshire, campaign for Senator Eugene McCarthy, Lyndon Johnson, Indianapolis, Bobby Kennedy, Martin Luther King, Jr., Gay Activist Alliance , Gertrude Stein Democratic Club, Marion Barry, Channing Phillips, Mattachine Society, Rev. Walter Fauntroy, Alan Hoffert, memorandum Frank Kameny for Congress, Richard Davidson, Lynn Burnett, Frank Kameny, Gay Liberation Front, Frank Kameny's campaign, David Carliner, Georgetown University students, Pennsylvania students, Gay Activist Alliance of New York, Safeway groceries, Temple Sinai, Gay Liberation Front, District Building, Alan Hoffert, Tony Jacobowski, Serta Mattress, Paul Newman, Joanne Woodward, gay political influence D.C., the gay community, Gertrude Stein Democratic Club, Marion Barry, Paul Newman, Joanne Woodward, Gay Activist Alliance of New York, Gay Activist Alliance of Washington, D.C., Jim Clark, Joel Martin, Jim Foster, Alice B. Toklas Democratic Club, San Francisco, Gertrude Stein Democratic Club, Gay and Lesbian Activist Alliance, David Goodstein, The Advocate (L.A. gay newspaper), Gay Rights National Lobby, Frank Kameny, Marion Barry, Mayor Walter Washington, Sterling Tucker (D.C. Council chairman), Marion Barry, won due to gay support, Gertrude Stein Democratic Club, Frank Kameny, Gay Rights National Lobby, Human Rights Campaign Fund, The Fund for Fairness, Walter Mondale, Tony Randall, The Plus-One (D.C. bar), University of Virginia (Northern Virginia campus), Stonewall, National Convention Project, first gay rights plank , 1980 Democratic national convention, Melvin Boozer, anti-discrimination laws, gay marriage.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_32a5db8106e57954f9f1d38c7bd0678a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Landau, Saul</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2012/2012">2012 October 19</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_70f9ccb7842f231074855f9fc2114ca5"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>(1936-2013) - Internationally known scholar, author, commentator, and filmmaker who worked for 40 years on social, political, and human rights issues. He produced more than 40 films, and won several awards, including an Emmy. Among his D.C.-produced films was the Edgar Allan Poe Award-winner, "Assassination on Embassy Row," an investigation into the mid-'70s murders in Washington of exiled Chilean Ambassador Orlando Letelier and his Institute for Policy Studies colleague, Ronni Moffitt.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_61205976719af960947f93d1981d7325"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Saul Landau interview: Censorship, Jean Genet, Oakland, Berkeley, 1972 came to D.C., film projects at IPS, CLR James, Who Shot Alexander Hamilton, A Song for Dead Warriors, less activism in D.C. vs Berkeley, The New Radicals with Paul Jacobs – 1966, KQED public radio, Losing Just the Same, Report from Cuba, From Protest to Resistance – on the movement, Mario Savio, Stokeley Carmichael, David Harris, participating in and filming civil rights and anti-war movements, Fidel – 1968, 1969 right-wing Cubans bombed and burned theaters in NY and Los Angeles to block showing of Fidel, work with Congress, Senator Jim Abourezk, Congressman Phil Burton – best organizer in Congress, Congressman Walter Jones, Father Drinan, Congressman Chuck Whalen, Watergate hearings, IPS people worked as staff in Congress, Orlando Letelier, Ronni Moffitt, bomb, Augusto Pinchet, Cointelpro, ran agents into IPS, Karl Hess – Libertarian – IPS fellow, IPS sued FBI and won, wiretapping Marc Raskin's office, film with Robert Wall – former FBI agent, proud of five children, Will the Real Terrorist Stand Up, Sixth Sun: Mayan Uprising in Chiapas, Subcomandante Marcos, 1970s: Washington D.C. a Black city, most visitors never saw real city, Letelier, Tatia Allende.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_bdd6de2eb934f780e8dc80961df098c4" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Lesser, Roger</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2015/2015">2015 October 05</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_227175e24e3616acae60566a21c07a58"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Social worker, antiwar activist, early IPS Fellow.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_f17b93ebd6bb5d13d48e405867633e20"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Roger Lesser interview: American Labor Party, union organizing, FBI, Smith Act, Julius and Ethel Rosenberg, Furniture Workers Union, Dow Chemical, Paul Robeson, IPS (Institute for Policy Studies), Appalachia, Off Our Backs.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_cb002a3377c33c35ee5ec0b0be73f07f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Malcolm Davis Remembered,</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2013/2013">2013 October 10</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_a7124c283ed9514c3d6cbe40b01d9292"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>(1937-2011) - Ecumenical campus chaplain at GWU from 1967 until 1984. Throughout the late 1960s-early 1970s, Mal Davis's campus office served as a gathering and planning spot for civil rights and antiwar activists. Davis personally fought for social justice -- in the South organizing civil rights bus caravans and sit-ins, leading voter registration drives, confronting the Ku Klux Klan; in D.C. helping organize the Poor People's Campaign and its accompanying Resurrection City in 1968, and helping organize anti-war protests during the Vietnam War. He later became renowned for his porcelain pottery. </p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_917b7f5e3961773d0ee41461e0217ce4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Interview participants include Sally Benbasset Tim Frasca Lexi Freeman Richard Lipsitz Esther Siegel George Virkus. All of whom were student activists at George Washington during the late 1960s and early 1970s.</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_429bd68cf01e4fe95665a59c11b299bc"><head>Keywords</head><p>Kerywords provided by the donor for Malcolm Davis interview: Lessons of the Sixties, bio of Mal Davis, George Virkus was a C.O., Timothy Frasca was a curious freshman, Richard Lipsitz participated in the huge demonstrations of the fall of 1969,  Sally Benbasset volunteered at St. Elizabeth's and did abortion counseling, Alexa Freeman moved from anti-war to the Women's movement, Esther Siegel tutored at St. Elizabeth's, religion at George Washington University,  death of Martin Luther King, civil rights,  George Washington University, attitude of the university, attitude of Davis' board, range of activities, Jewish Defense League, Palestine, SDS actions, draft center,  Malcom as a mature voice, SERVE office as a home, active rally and disobedience, compassion, class attendance, class content, 1971 was peak, Nixon's second inauguration, women's movement, exclusivity, People's Union welcomed all, "with us or against us" elsewhere, personal counselor, May Day 1971 anecdotes, arrests, civil disobedience, settlements for illegal arrest, Moonies, Unification Church, informants, Mal didn't criticize people, group house, 1405 21st St,  draft counseling, overnight military guests, pot and acid, marijuana and LSD, prison guard experiment, P Street beach, Mad Dog, parents, community radio, Pacifica Radio, Santiago Chile, AIDs, Labor Union work, abortion counseling, OFF OUR BACKS,  parent cooperative daycare, radical feminism, Institute for Policy Studies, working for Mal, weddings, later life as a potter, the mimeograph machine.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_aeaf68f246013543a0d7b951581e688a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Malone, Joann</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2016/2016">2016 January 15</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_6bc5efee3c43d8eed4743d645c33ceb5"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Joann Malone was a member of the Sisters of Loretto for almost twelve years, her first teaching assignment beginning in Montgomery Alabama in 1963.  The Civil Rights Movement transformed her into an activist for life in efforts to end poverty, war, racism and sexism.  After hearing Thich Nhat Hanh speak in 1968 about the war in Vietnam, she joined the DC-9 in an action in DC against Dow Chemical's production of napalm, nerve gas and defoliants.  Her "claim to fame" is being the first nun in US history to commit five federal felonies, be convicted and face 35 years in prison.  Once the DC area became a permanent home, she continued working with revolutionary groups, organizing unions at area factories and hospitals and teaching Social Studies in DC and MD public high schools for twenty-one years.  She worked at IPS on a prison project, wrote for Off Our Backs, was a member of the DC Unite to Fight Back and of Earth Onion Women's Improvisational Theater. </p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_18b3f05a6e99238f06feb1c37a6c1c38"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Joann Malone interview: Joanne Malone, Radical nun, Sisters of Loretto, Progressive religious order, Mother house in Kentucky, Sister Luke Tobin, Social action in the church, Thomas Merton, Liberation theology, Pedagogy of the Oppressed, Vatican II, Federal Felony charges, Birmingham bombing, Montgomery, AL, Kansas City, MO, Ending racism, 1964-67, 1969 Dow Action, Anti-war movement, Poverty in Kansas City, War images on television, Black Liberators, Police arrests, Baltimore 4, Phil Berrigan , Tich Nat Hanh, Catonsville 9, Civil Disobedience, Dow Chemical Office, D.C. 9, Blood on files, Publish in Times and Washington Post, Link between government and Dow Chemical, Draft action, Women's detention, Fasted while in jail, Started a journal while in jail, Lawyers, Charged with 5 federal felonies, Probation, Feb 3-10 1970, 1973 won in appeal, Pleaded guilty to one misdemeanor, Act according to our conscience, New School phD program, Earth Onion Theater Group, Art and Irene Waskow, IPS, Off Our Backs, Commune in D.C., Study Group, Left the church in 1967, DC Unite to Fight Back, U.S. China People's Friendship Association, Free Terrence Johnson, Georgetown University Hospital Union Organizing, Single Mother, Revolutionary change, One priest sentenced to 9 years, Anti-nuke movement in 1970's, Our children carrying out fights against racism and other important issues, Teaching Peace Studies in Montgomery School System , Montgomery Blair and Wilson High Schools, Student walkout to protest bombing of Iraq, Agent Orange, PTSD, Alcoholism, Opportunities for women, Women's Movement, Police Brutality, Militarization of police, Live Your life, Mindfulness Meditation , Trip to Vietnam with Tich Nat Hanh, Cambodia, Poverty throughout the world, Courage to act, Act for peace, Vietnam Boat People, Need compassion for everyone, Meditation retreats, Lessons for Young People, A vision of peace, Love is the answer.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_4b3f0c37a9522a6ce1b83b6449f4c28f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Margolies, Richard</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2015/2015">2015 March 18</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_6778510153d2189259c0dd95a17b96be"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Richard Margolies was a conscientious objector during the Vietnam War and participant and chronicler of the intentional community movement with its values of sharing and equality that blossomed during the 1960s and 1970s. He later had a long career as a clinical psychologist.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_0e49b780cc3ba104639fe0b949945f43"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Rick Margolies interview: Handbook for Conscientious Objectors, draft card, conscientious objector status and public service, Freedom of Information Act, FBI, Margolies as "dangerous person," Michael Tigar, Selective Service Law Reporter, Judge William Bryant, Resistance Statement, AJ Muste, Carl Bernstein and Washington Post article on "new communities"movement, collective living as way to avoid materialism, working at IPS, "The New Left"published, 60s offered freedom, citizen activism, being part of something bigger than self, "bi-partisan lying" by elected officials enraged young people, Viet Nam War as pulling all movements together, need for humanistic values, understanding role of families in psychology of conflict, work Michael Maccoby.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_b897f6f5c743fb440eb078df5a26c80e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Martel, Erich</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2016/2016">2016 October 28</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_907729a4928c860c4d62999cb92a506f"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Erich Martel came to Washington in 1961 to attend Geogetown University. He participated in social causes, joined the Army, later earned a teaching degree and began teaching at an African-American high school. He was active in teachers' unions. His last 25 years of teaching were at Wilson High School  where his history classes were legendary and often included visits from activists such as Seymour Hersh.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_7a1978d9acfa8c7de57528a16b68e96b"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Erich Martel interview: Erich Martel,  career teacher, Georgetown University, 1961, Young Americans for Freedom, Fr. Richard McSorley, GUCAP, tutoring, civil rights, Walter Draude, trip to Selma, Vietnam War, Cardinal Spellman, the draft, Mme Nhu at Georgetown, Army enlistment, OCS, Street Without Joy, Bernard Fall, Trinity College MAT program, Cardozo High School, Wilson High School, Washington Teachers' Union, 1972 teachers' strike, Socialist Workers' Party, anti-war marches, Julius Hobson, political buttons, unions join anti-war efforts, American Federation of Teachers, experts in the classroom, Seymour Hersh, Lt. William Calley, Edward Alvarez, students interview folks at the Vietnam memorial, school administration shortcomings, falsified records, Adrian Fenty.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_8d07aa9d59db610093f32aab2cd4b71e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Moore, Douglas E.</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2013/2013">2013 April 19</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_81830330b124f030f9bfeee52386baa0"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>(1928-2019) - Civil rights leader, head of D.C. Black United Front; later, member D.C. Council.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_ea2ecb9648993d21300b8600a1fefc13"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Reverend Douglas Moore interview: Reverend Douglas Moore, North Carolina 1950s, Washington D.C. 1960s and 1970s, First D.C. City Council, Hickory, North Carolina, Uncle's fish market, Howard University, Uncle Oscar Barnes and his market, O Street market, North Carolina fish market, mother as "terrorist", only child, Willard Johnson – Uncle, sold watermelon, Uncle John, Eagle Scout, Hickory Daily Record, Howard University School of Religion, Valedictorian-high school, played football, basketball, civil rights movement in North Carolina, tough grandfather, gun bearer for grandfather, double-barreled shotgun, only black newspaper carrier, farther-high school principal, revolutionary valedictory speech, upset city with speech, Mr. Broome-principal, Reverend J.W. Moore (Jack Moore), audience cheering, North Carolina A&amp;T (Agricultural and Technical), 13th, 14th and 15th amendments to the constitution, Elks oratorical contest, father and mother divorced, father high school principal – Ridgeview High School, Grandfather (Peter Johnson) slapped white policeman, grandfather's shotgun, sit-ins N.C. restaurants, "father of the sit-ins" in N.C., Woolworth's, ice cream parlor, white kids upset by sit-ins, grandfather – Methodist preacher, grandfather taught shooting to white folks, grandfather - "Pete Johnson", "a mean mother fucker", stern, unmovable black men, had shotgun, 2 pistols – 2 .38, arrests Royal Ice Cream Shop – sit-ins, plaque – Royal Ice Cream Shop, SCLC – one of founders, met Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr, at Boston University, King told me "stir up the water", ice cream shop – didn't arrest me, Black United Front, racism in D.C., North Carolina College, Marion Barry, reparations, Rev. George Hart, Columbia Baptist Churches, Jesus, I was "arrogant motherfucker", Christian responsibility, Interview (?) Brooks Todd, Methodist Church, Boston University (B.U.), Howard, Annon (?) Walter Chalmers (?), superior religion teachers at B.U., Marion Barry's women/"the skirts", Donald Graham - "a punk", FBI, black activists, white anti-war activists, racist flyer, knew it was a fake, Julius Hobson, "a radical", cooperated with Hobson, anti-freeway fight, never arrested, scared by my speeches (?), Methodist preacher, Black United Front, I?? Shaw, Walter Fauntroy, Yale, Boston University, Gammon (?), elected first City Council, arrested N.C., Royal Ice Cream Parlor, journalist Chuck Stone, Afro-American, statehood movement, Julius Hobson, D.C. Statehood Party, I am a Marxist, I ain't no atheist, arrests North Carolina, Royal Ice Cream Parlor, arrest – guilty, Peter Johnson, .38, sit-ins, movement disintegrated, civil rights activists, made mark on history, Martin Luther King, Jr., Walter Mueller, Boston University, D.C. Board of Trade, land grab, Shaw U., Gammon, interstate bus, no back of the bus, Doris Hughes Moore – wife, Hickory, N.C., life member, National Rifle Association, NRA, Malcolm X, Howard University takeover, "a bougie takeover", Martin Luther King assassination, SCLC, race war – no, no, no, D.C. MLK riots, kids mad, getting guns, Black revolution impossible, no guns, no money, Black Panther Party – lacked guns, no revolution without guns, Chuck Stone, Jim Lowery, Stokely Carmichael, Miriam Makeba, married Carmichael and Makeba, wrote book, "The Buying and Selling of the D.C. Council", Council "bought", Chuck Stone, Absalom Jordon, Yasser Arafat, FBI, Marion Barry, fluent in French, stored guns, son was marine, FBI, Anthony Williams, ran for mayor, Ku Klux Klan, Stokely Carmichael, NRA, Marion Barry, FBI, Treasury Department, armed revolution – crazy, U.S. Army, police brutality, irrational violence, Howard University, sit-ins, national movement, brutality, Howard University sit-ins, Tuskegee, voter registration, Southwest Georgia, SNCC, Deacons of Defense, married 1998.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_6dd7a955279877f2455fe804e63b30bf" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Morgan School,</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2014/2014">2014 March 21</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2b2026058e3104cc2d114649d8c83526"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Panel discussion on the campaign in the late 1960s to establish a community-run school in the Adams Morgan neighborhood of Washington, D.C. Participants were parents, activists, teachers and other school personnel who were involved in that campaign. The panel of Morgan School supporters included Edward G. Jackson Sr., president of the Morgan PTA when this effort started, and later chair of the Morgan Community School Board and an Advisory Neighborhood Commissioner; Irene Elkin, then an Adams Morgan community activist and chair of the Schools Committee of the Adams Morgan Community Council; Marcus Raskin, co-founder of the Institute for Policy Studies; Harrison Owen, then executive director of the Adams Morgan Community Council; and teachers Dorothy L. Artis and Dorothy Chappell. Also participating were school personnel Joan Broadus and Ida Mae Beasley.</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_b786186ab91f1be113a42d584f57f913"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Thomas P. Morgan Community School inteview: Morgan School, overcrowding, Morgan Annex, 17th &amp; Euclid, Bishop Marie Reid, Morgan Community School Board, Kenneth Haskins, Health center, interns, school committee,1966, white families, St. Margaret's Episcopal, Pilgrim Church, Head Start, Friday night dances, Adams Morgan Teen Council, Vera Stevens, Sonora Whitfield, Americanization School, petitions, IPA, Antioch College, team teaching, Superintendent Hansen, plan approved, 1967, Diane Josephson, Haskins Principal, 1968, teaching interns, college classes at Morgan, teaching third grade, school secretary, conflict between traditional teachers and hippie Antioch students, lots of press,., good then bad, teachers' union, petition drive, community control concept, best part: Haskins and the interns, Antioch Summer Institute, sensitivity training, chaos of school opening, Adams Community school 2 years later, Issac and Ruth Long, design of new Reid School, Topper Carew, Mr and Mrs Jackson appreciation.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_af33f7fd3d303e81d0c5ba99d0d34e4e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Murphy, Luci</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2012/2012">2012 October 12</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_2185a0db460059600f86c659643224dd"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Human rights activist and topical/jazz singer who for more than four decades has been the musical voice of progressive social justice movements in the District of Columbia. She graduated WIlson High School the spring of 1968, when Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. and Robert Kennedy were assassinated, and began a life of musical activism at that time. </p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_efbfbb567d191abba83d9c3398366593"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Luci Murphy interview: 5th grade petition, music, St. Stephens and the Incarnation Episcopal Church, Mother Scott, Fr. William Wendt, Banneker Junior High School, colonial status, picket lines downtown, Malcom X, Puerto Rico, Wilson High , School, 1968, riots, party atmosphere, JFK assassination, LBJ, RFK, action mass, guitar mass, coffee houses, , African dance groups, folk music, Cellar Door, Free Arts Program, Topper Carew, Ronnie Karpen, Sophie's Parlor, Gerry Schwin, Howard University, New School of Afro-American Thought, Brown Paper Bag parties, Luci's mother, a song that needs singing, concern for connectiveness, University Neighborhoods Council, 12 year old volunteer, Woodley House, Big Brother Big Sister, field trips for kids, integration was a trick on the black community, black leaders now invisible, March on Washington, St. Stephens, Poor People's March, , Palestinian support, leaders in Pitt's Hotel, Letelier assassination, Luci did memorials, draft counselors, end of Viet Nam war, Radio Hanoi.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_7a2849988d032b3360a67b588b719729" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Nahikian, Marie</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2016/2016">2016 May 11</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_097e07f4e4872ea352e1aef675d5e428"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Activist involved in struggles around fair and affordable housing, civil rights, the anti-war movement and local D.C. politics.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_8613dee5e3f7e42302adb2a4e13ea795"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Marie Nahikian interview: civil rights and journalism activities at University in North Carolina, Arrive in Washington early 1970, neighborhood organizing, Adams-Morgan, Other neighborhood activists , Topper Carew, Milton Kotler, Irene Waskow, IPS, Richard Barnet, Global Reach, Executive Director , Adams-Morgan Organization (AMO), democratic neighborhood projects , fish-farming, Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), science and technology, Karl Hess, IPS, College Editors Conference in 1970 at Shoreham Hotel. , Hog Farm, Conspiracy Trial defendants, other antiwar activists attend, hold Nixon Secretary of Interior Warren Hickel (speaker) accountable for Vietnam War and other misdeeds, Hickel later resigns , Black Panthers, Black Panthers Revolutionary Convention held in Washington DC end of 1970, staff writer for a scrap metal trade association, Huey Newton, Black Panthers, Karl Hess, scrap metal association credit card, disappearing rental car, Harassment by FBI, AMO serves as model for Advisory Neighborhood Commission (ANCs) still operating today, housing issues in Adams-Morgan in mid-70s, Big housing issue: major displacement of families as area gentrifies, gentrification, Other people involved in housing: Dorothy McGhee, Ron Clark of RAP Inc., Atty. Johnny Barnes, 1972 city tenant rights law passed , right of tenants to purchase homes, tenant conversion processes, tenant eviction controls, Marie ran for City Council 1978 but did not win, Became active in homeless issues in mid-70s, Marie had regular "DC Issues" radio show in 70s with former City Council member Johnny Wilson, Marie continues work on housing and homelessness at HUD and in Brooklyn and city of Philadelphia through 2016.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_81afdd651f4a44c233d211d408aa255d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Onion Earth</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2017-01-27/2017-01-27">2017 January 27</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_48bcb07d314a497e85a03e231767ca6b"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Information provided by the donor: Earth Onion was a women's improvisational theater group in Washington, D.C. from 1970 to 1975. It began through the Women's Liberation Movement and worked very closely with many other political groups and movements in the area. It performed extensively around the Washington, D.C. area and toured around the country for about three years.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_cf7943da8156f793191bc7bdba33a2e1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Information provided by the donor: Lynn (Glixon) Ditchfield, Julie Huff and Susie (Solf) Philips describe the creation of the Earth Onion Theater Group, which performed from 1970-75, the experiences of the group, its impact on themselves and others, its connections to the political and cultural movements of the time, reasons for its ending in 1975, and its long-term influence on them in the work each of them did in the following decades.</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_6d511cd0ef41283d4270059c6b63a8a8"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor: <br/>
Women's theater group, Washington D.C., improvisational, 1970-75, Women's Liberation Movement, intentional community, Earth Angel, Earth Onion, free southern theater, women's liberation office turn to being anti male babies, play and dance, no meeting, no dogma and rhetoric, into our bodies, consciousness lowering, political theater, It's All Right to be Woman Theater, Caravan Theater, fringe theater, Woman Potion, Jamming , Earth Onion – peeling the layers, Three national tours, Elsa and the Tutnawald, Liberation, Utopia, perfect community of all women, Fort Bragg, FTA coffee house, political theater, San Francisco Mime Troupe, Bread and Puppet Theater - Goddard, Living theater, Becoming more professional, Learning the craft, Workshops, St. Elizabeth's, National Endowment for the Arts, Creative zone, Our lives, Rape, Abortion, Job interviews, Funny stories, Clothing, Improvisational, Audience real stories, New endings, Personal impact, Woman Potion, No single director, Wrote own pieces, Undocumented women, Workplace theater, Humor, Hard to reach people with theater, Social media, Film, Women's March 2017, Cuban Escambray Theater, People's stories, Trump communities, Welfare, Emilio Medici – Brazil President, Paulo Friere, Agitprop, guerrilla theater, workshops for other group, NLF birthday celebration, anti-war movement, skill building, taught skills, regular people, feminism, adornment, big media, pharmaceuticals, school-age women, sexualization of young women, self esteem, children's theater group, earth onion lessons and skills, healing, nurse, public health, roll play, STDs, workplace theater, teacher, emotionally disturbed youth, incarcerated youth, autism, collective, reasons for end of Earth Onion, communes, anti-war movements, collective health insurance, therapy coverage, live on limited means, camaraderie, inspirational work style, 35th reunion, interviews, importance of arts in social movements, novel about a theater group, arts-based immigration curriculum, gun control, grandchildren, poem on the end of Earth Onion, Carol Weissberg, Joanne Zonas</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_89a98a72fa64494dc472bd225220704a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Raskin, Marcus</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2013/2013">2013 January 07</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_23501006dd5da6d6b5c54cef083a6871"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>(1934-2017) -  Marcus Raskin was a prominent American social critic, political activist, intellectual, author, and philosopher. He was a leading figure in the Vietnam anti-war movement and the co-founder, with former State Department official Richard Barnet, of the progressive think tank, the Institute for Policy Studies (IPS), in Washington, D.C.</p><p>A child prodigy on the piano, Raskin gave up a music career after receiving undergraduate and law degrees at the University of Chicago. Moving to Washington, D.C. in 1958, Raskin served as legislative counsel to a group of liberal congressmen. In 1961, he became assistant on national security affairs and disarmament as a member of the Special Staff of the National Security Council under President Kennedy's national security adviser McGeorge Bundy. In disagreement with the Kennedy administration's Cold War policies, Raskin left his government post to co-found IPS in 1963.</p><p>The Vietnam War became a major area of concentration for Raskin and IPS. With noted scholar Bernard Fall, Raskin co-authored the Vietnam Reader, which was used in teach-ins against the war across the country. In 1967, he co-authored with Arthur Waskow, a colleague at IPS, "A Call to Resist Illegitimate Authority," which urged support for those who resisted the draft and the Vietnam War. The "Call to Resist" was signed by thousands of people, and because of it Raskin and Waskow took part in turning in 1,000 draft cards to the government. In 1968, Raskin was indicted -— along with William Sloane Coffin, Dr. Benjamin Spock, Michael Ferber and Mitchell Goodman—for conspiracy to aid resistance to the draft. The group became known as the "Boston Five." Raskin was acquitted.</p><p>One of Raskin's children is Jamie Raskin, who was elected to the U.S. House of Representatives from Maryland's Eighth Congressional District in 2016 and was reelected in 2018.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_df88535d3fc78792a6a1d85ec4dd758a"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Marcus Raskin interview: Jamie Raskin, Marcus Raskin, Sixties ran 1958-1975, California student march, End of Vietnam War, Martin Luther King Jr., Institute for Policy Studies, Richard (Dick) Barnet, IPS purpose — truth to power, IPS started 1963, Break-ins by government, Assassinations by Pinochet people, Deaths of colleagues, Ronni Moffitt, Worked White House, Special staff National Security Council, McGeorge Bundy, Special White House science group, War in Vietnam, Carl Kaysen, Deputy national security advisor, Falling out with Kaysen over Vietnam, Memorial service for Kaysen, "Conscience of NSC in White House", Dr. (Benjamin) Spock, "Spock Trial", Raised in Milwaukee, Musical talent — absolute pitch, Played piano, Started age 4, Studied at Juilliard, Franz Liszt, Vladimir Horowitz, Toscanini's daughter, Curtis Institute, Curtis Publishing Co., Rosina Lhevinne (teacher), Isabelle Vengerova (teacher ), Mother would open my mail, Brother captain in Air Force, World War II, Pianist Frank Glazer, University of Chicago Law School, Congressman Robert Kastenmeier, Rep. Leonard Wolf, A Call to Resist Illegitimate Authority, Basis for Criminal Information, Anti-Vietnam War Movement, Dr. Spock, Michael Ferber, Rev. William Sloane Coffin, Mitchell Goodman, Boston 5 case, New York Times, Conspiracy to aid and abet draft evasion, ACLU lawyers, Call to Resist, Legitimate authority, Justice and law, Say no to illegitimate authority, Burning draft cards, Turning in draft cards, Coffin, Chaplain at Yale University, Invited youths to burn draft cards, Boston 5 trial, Ferber, Coffin, Spock, Defendants' relationships, Ended up divorced or separated, Raskin acquitted, Devastated others found guilty, Telford Taylor, World War II war crimes prosecutor, Nuremberg prosecutor, In the Name of America (book), Seymour Melman - editor, Meeting - Deputy associate attorney general, Brought 270 draft cards to meeting, Arthur Waskow, Atrocities in Vietnam, In the Name of America, Ads New York Times, Signers, Jean-Paul Sartre, Simone de Beauvoir, Martin Luther King, IPS , Roger Wilkins, Nixon's Enemies List, Richard Barnet, Undercover agents, 58 informers at various IPS events, "J. Edgar Hoover wing" of the Communist Party, Resistance (document), John Cavanagh, 50th anniversary IPS, Mike Tabor, Allen Ginsberg, Ralph Nader, "Unsafe at Any Speed", New York Times, SDS, Jeff Faux, Spin-offs from IPS, Tina Smith, Women's movement, Off Our Backs, Richard Barnet, Gar Alperovitz, Barbara Ehrenreich, Ralph Nader, Roots of War (Barnet book), Alzheimer's (Richard B.), Anne Barnet, Border Crossings (Ann Barnet book), Jamie Raskin, Tommy Raskin.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_131c6e0e60546864f0ce262ba91f23d9" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Riskin, Irv</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2012/2012">2012 December 21</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_2bc96cdbd47da1dc4ea82ca4bd8a9643"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>(1918-2014) - Union organizer, McCarthy-era political witch-hunt victim, and life-long activist for peace and social justice. His Washington area activities included leadership in the Gray Panthers and the Grape Boycott, and as a key Washington Post strike supporter; and mentor to a generation of social justice activists in Washington, D.C. </p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_fe02b6b343d2bcc88970795260b48ddb"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Irv Riskin interview: Fred Solowey (interviewer), Irving Riskin, Red-diaper baby, Born August 18, 1918 Brooklyn, N.Y., father was member Communist Party, opposition to the Czar, father still in Russia 1905, concerned about treatment of Jews, father emigrated, father carpenter, cabinetmaker, IWW -- International Workers of the World, father active Scotsboro Boys case, Sacco-Vanzetti case, Italy invasion of Ethiopia, Great Depression -- father moved evicted people back into homes, Carpenters Union, father gave up his business to keep Communist Party membership, CP at the time barred membership to business owners, Communist teachers at his elementary school, First school to hire black teacher, Brooklyn College -- evening classes -- 2 years, IBEW (International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers), CIO (Congress of Industrial Organizations), AFL (American Federation of Labor), general strike (1937), Local 3 IBEW -- crossed picket lines, troublemaker and activist, Civil Service test for messenger job, Came to Washington, D.C. in 1939 as messenger, New Deal housing agency, Spain - Spanish Civil War, Abraham Lincoln Brigades, National Press Club (NPC), NPC cafeteria workers strike, Wife Suzanne supported strike, Longest strike at time -- 18 months, Cafeteria Workers Union, Communist Party D.C., Handed out leaflet anti-draft, anti-war (late 1930s), Socialist (Workers) Party, Trotskyists, Spanish Civil War, Came under suspicion, New Deal exciting period in D.C., CIO, messengers/clerks had longer work hours, organized messengers, Detroit -- went there 1944, Leon Keyserling, promotion from within policy, Suzanne (Riskin), administrator public housing Detroit 5 years, Detroit office no furniture, Ford Motor Company, Willow Run, Michigan planned community, UAW (United Auto Workers), Reutherites, Ford UAW Local, UAW Local cooperated with CP, Sis Cunningham, cultural program, 1946-1947, Local ejected from CIO, Walter Reuther, resigned administrator job, under Red-baiting pressure, Jimmy Hoffa, UPWA, union organizer, AFL, Teamsters, Hoffa promised not to raid Irv's union, moved to Allentown, Pennsylvania, wife's mother ran grocery/deli business, Riskin salesman for grocery business, Pennsylvania Communist Party, CP organizer for Allentown/Scranton area, FBI agent infiltrated local CP, Infiltrator was best friend for 10 years, Trial of Pennsylvania "Smith Act 11" or "Pennsylvania 6", Overthrowing government , Poisoning supply water in the area, FBI harassment, Allentown, Lost job at grocery/deli, Eddie Becker (camera operator), John Hanrahan (interviewer), Infiltrator later ran for various political offices, Infiltrator was courier for CP, Delivered notes party headquarters, Attended CP meetings, Infiltrator had access to everything in CP district, FBI, Philadelphia, party meeting materials, note of upcoming CP meeting in Philadelphia didn't reach Riskin, Infiltrator delivered CP notes to FBI, Riskin didn't get meeting notice, Riskin didn't attend meeting, Other CP sub-leadership arrested at meeting, Smith Act, Influenced by father re. CP, Influenced by CP members fighting for justice, Influenced by elementary school teachers who were "lefties", Party members outed in press, People crossed street to avoid him, stool pigeons, son Michael Riskin, 3rd grader -- not taken on school trip to fire station, Jewish community in Allentown, Irving Ezekiel Riskin -- full Jewish name, Herman Thomas -- informant's name, Suzanne Riskin, Working on Rosenberg case, House Un-American Activities Committee -- Suzanne called, HUAC, Senate Internal Security Subcommittee -- Irv, Selma Rein, David Rein, Took 5th Amendment, Moved family to Washington, D.C. in 1957, Suzanne relatives in D.C., Allentown comrades abandoned him, Only one gay comrade stood by him in Allentown, D.C. progressive community, grape boycott, D.C. segregation, CIO, Abe Bloom, peace movement, Women Strike for Peace, seasoned party (CP) people, Shul progressive Jewish Sunday School, teachers, members of left community, African American community, Jewish culture, history, Shul building on FBI list, Ruth Pinkson, CP property confiscated by government, IWO (International Workers Order), Maurice Jackson, Hudson Wells, under suspicion from party leadership, Pennsylvania 6 arrest -- I wasn't there, put me under suspicion, son Michael, daughter Karen, better for kids in D.C. -- made friends easily, Quaker summer camp and school, first interracial camp in Virginia, nuclear testing, civil rights movement, grape boycott, anti-Vietnam War, complacency in the 1950s, quite active in grape boycott, boycott house, vice president of Farm Workers union here permanently, worked with them, Ethel Weisser, Farmworkers grape boycott committee set up locally, peace movement, Gray Panthers, CIO, the Helen Miller case, youth movement, Eleanor Roosevelt, Youth Congress, Women Strike for Peace, Committee to Reopen the Rosenberg Case, Giles-Johnson case, Joe Forer, One of founders of Silver Spring Co-op, Bethesda, Md. (where lived), Washington Post pressmen's strike, Rainbow Coalition Montgomery County, Washington Hospital Center strike, Gray Panthers (Montgomery County), Abe Bloom, Anne Gallivan (interviewer), civil rights movement, grape boycott, distributed leaflets, Manuel Vasquez, Gene Boutilier, picketing Montgomery County Giant supermarket, scab grapes, Connecticut Avenue wine retailers, Gallo Wine, De Colores, the Joneses - singers -- Peter Jones and his brother Steve Jones, Peter wrote song about Gallo, Cesar Chavez, Dolores Huerta, AFL-CIO, Ethel Kennedy, Catholic activists, peace demonstrations, 1969 Mobilization, Farmworkers own problems, Paul Pumphrey, migrant workers, Carl Goldman, Gray Panthers, Maggie Kuhn, Vietnam War, mandatory retirement, Social Security , AARP, media ignored Gray Panthers, Montgomery County, county services, Social Security, Gray Panthers died off, Abe Bloom, head of Montgomery County Gray Panthers, 25 years, no new people coming along to Gray Panthers, children of Gray Panthers not involved, CIO unions, union lists of retired people, 1972 - no teaching medical hospital taught geriatric medicine, Maggie Kuhn, John Hanrahan (interviewer), Washington Post strike (Pressman's Union, Local 6), Fred Solowey, strike activist, strike support activities, divergent groups, Communists -- 4,5 variations of communists, couple labor groups, union v.p. asked -- who are the real communists here, publicity committee, Chip Berlet, Socialist Workers Party, Trotsky, Jim Dugan, Alliance for Labor and Community Action, Defense Committee, U.S. attorney's office, grand jury investigation, "conspiracy" to destroy The Washington Post, feeling for the union was so great , strikers understood unionism, Washington Star employee aided strike, Annapolis -- resolution supporting the strike, Maryland support committee, boycott the Post, cancel subscriptions, 2 car caravans supporting strike, pressman Zarbaugh, fundraiser, picketing Katharine Graham's house, favorable response, neighbors took leaflet, strike slogan -- "no grapes, no lettuce, no Post", Montgomery County musicians' union Local, government workers' unions, Carl Goldman, Kaufman Press, cancel subscriptions to the Post, Irv continued to boycott Post until his death, Jules Witcover, Mary McGrory, Washington Star, priest supported strike, "All the President's Men", Kennedy Center premiere, strikers shouting, 500 people protesting inside/outside, Eugene O'Sullivan, 2 strikers served time halfway house, benefit concert , Antioch law students, rally for Brookside miners, "Fighting Irv Riskin", Rainbow Coalition, Nicaraguan Coalition, Henry Wallace campaign, USO in WWII, Unions set up own USO in D.C. in WWII, 50 fairly active Pennsylvania communists.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_2e67e748560d5c5681e88aa0a43074e0" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Robinson, Betty Garman</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2017/2017">2017 June 28</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_3926793ae72e0d3793d8cfdab1c191b6"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Betty Garman Robinson moved to Washington DC in 1965 to help run the SNCC office, then headed by Marion Barry, also new to town as National Chairman of SNCC. A graduate of Skidmore College and an early member of SNCC, Betty was already a dedicated civil rights activist and quickly became a key organizer for various initiatives of the "Free DC Movement" which was headed by Barry. Home Rule for DC was the overriding local civil rights issue in the 60s and 70s for Washingtonians. Later Betty assumed leadership positions in grassroots efforts to end the Vietnam War, including chairing the DC Committee to Defend the Conspiracy during the 1969-70 trial of antiwar leaders in Chicago, and her work in organizing a 1971 conference of Vietnamese, Cambodian and American women in Canada. Betty remains an active participant in the fight for racial justice, working with the anti-racist organization SURJ (Standing Up for Racial Justice) Hands on the Freedom Plow, published in 2010, is a collection of personal accounts by Betty and 51 other women about their experiences working in the civil rights movement.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_a536d366b378af5ed2f17810d44619aa"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Betty Garman Robinson interview: SNCC (Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee) in Washington, DC, Marion Barry, "Free DC" movement, Black Arts movement, Emergency Committee on the Transportation Crisis (ECTC), Anti-war movement, Women's Conference 1971 with Indochinese women, Madame Binh, Vietnamese revolutionary, Chicago Conspiracy Trial, Marxist Study Group, Move to Baltimore in late 1970s, Career in public health and safety, Other names mentioned in this interview: Melvin Deal, Tony Gittins, Topper Carew and the New Thing – all leaders in the DC Black Arts Movement, Hilda Mason – Long-time DC City Council member, local activist and head of DC Statehood Party, who attended 1971 conference and met Madame Binh.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_db00f74c33a328c17999450fc17eac9f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Rooney, Angela</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2013/2013">2013 February 19</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_c9d0a4966df8f1baa970006e57417ecb"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>(1920-2016) - Environmental and neighborhood activist. She was a leading figure in the 1960s and 1970s Emergency Committee on the Transportation Crisis (ECTC) which waged a successful anti-North Central Freeway / 3 Sisters Bridge campaign.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_26b05dd14b82907c7dd94ef75aa27811"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Angela Rooney interview: NORTH CENTRAL FREEWAY, NORTHEAST FREEWAY, THREE SISTERS BRIDGE, 38 MILES OF FREEWAYS PLANNED 10 WERE BUILT, COALITION OF BLACKS AND WHITES, BIOGRAPHY OF ANGELA, WTOP / CBS, LYING, CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY THEATER, BROOKLAND, FREEWAYS, WALTER TOBRINER, (?) DUNCAN, DISTRICT COMMISSIONERS, SAM ABBOTT, TAKOMA PARK, REV. JOHN MOTE, FEDERATION OF CIVIC ASSOCIATIONS, EDWARD SCOTT, REDLINING, SAM ABBOTT, INFILTRATION BY THE FBI, JULIUS HOBSON, MARION BARRY, PETER CRAIG, WASHINGTON POST, BRITISH ACCENT, AMERICAN LUNG ASSOCIATION, AIR POLLUTION, SUBWAY, HIGHWAY TRUST FUND, SLOGANS &amp; MAPS, HERBLOCK, SONG ABOUT FREEWAYS, 1969 CITY COUNCIL MEETING, JOEL BROYHILL, SAM ABBOTT, JOHN HECHINGER, JACK EISEN, THE WASHINGTON POST, WHITE MAN'S ROADS…, KEN BURNS, BEER, THREE SISTERS BRIDGE, ELIZABETH "LIBBY" ROWE, COMMITEE OF 100, PETER CRAIG, BERNIE PRYOR OF BROOKLAND, EDWARD SCOTT, BLACK-WHITE COALITION, 1968 RIOTS, SAM ABBOTT, NATIONAL TRANSPORTATION COALITION, EVACUATION PLANS, NO END FOR THE FREEWAY ISSUE, METROPOLITAN COUNCIL OF GOVERNMENTS, POWER OF TECHNOLOGY, MARION BARRY, JULIUS HOBSON, ONE-MAN-BAND, LEWIS MUMFORD, JANE JACOBS, SAM ABBOTT, "BIGGEST GODDAMN POTHOLE".</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_c515a56d082c982cae7d7624f88bf5ce" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Roth Roberta Spalter and Roger Lesser,</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2016/2016">2016 November 15</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b4cd0350a3ee35d359e669309f1e0ffb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Roberta and Roger discuss some of their experiences in the movements of the 1960s.</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_5a4ec80a2166a486189f3a4fe6bd8079"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Roberta Spalter-Roth and Roger Lesser inteview: Roberta Spalter-Roth, sociologist, Roger Lesser, studying the women's movement, studying the anti-war movement, Off Our Backs, Marilyn Webb, consciousness raising groups, Black Panther Movement, HEW, Federal Employees for a Democratic Society, federal employees demonstration with Dr. Spock, Institute for Policy Studies, IPS, 2016 Presidential election.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_987f8c88b9787aa5b83e3fd0e28131fd" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Rubin, Larry</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2014/2014">2014 April 11</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_0ffc4019a5f9d054d9fe357611b5cc1e"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Larry Rubin is a life-long activist born into a progressive, secular Jewish family. Growing up in the McCarthy years, he attended the 1958 March on Washington and other political events as a teenager. While a student at Antioch in the early 60s he visited the SNCC Albany Project in Southwest Georgia, which was the immediate spur to his involvement in the civil rights movement, claiming "I never thought of not going South—It's what we do." He took his first job in Washington in 1962 as a community organizer at Southeast Neighborhood House. After other organizing stints in Kentucky and Mississippi, Larry returned permanently to Washington, DC, just as the major push for DC voting rights and Home Rule was gaining momentum. Working with SNCC leaders Marion Barry and Ivanhoe Donaldson, he participated in this successful campaign of the mid-to-late 70s. Larry also worked in the labor movement for many years as a lobbyist for United Electrical Workers and served four terms on the Takoma Park (MD) City Council.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_621d2a014f91bf89858bb4ca7ded6c70"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Larry Rubin interview: Philadelphia, McCarthy, Teens Ahead, picketing Woolworth, 1958 March on Washington, Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee (SNCC) Albany Project, Southeast Neighborhood House (SENH) , Barry Farms, Conflict at SENH between systemic change and social work approach, Sharlene Kranz, Julius Hobson, HIlda Mason, Josephine Butler, Walter Washington, DC as Southern city, SNCC Holly Springs Project, Marion Barry, Frank Smith, Ivanhoe Donaldson, Charlie Cobb, Cleve Sellars, Pike County, Kentucky, 1965, Anne and Carl Braden, Southern Conference Education Project (SCEF), Margaret and Al McSurely, "You can't drop out of Antioch", SNCC workers in DC hired by Institute for Policy Studies (IPS), National Students Association (NSA), Central Intelligence Agency (CIA), Bob Avakian, Jack Anderson, Drew Pearson, Home Rule, United Electrical Workers, Bill Higgs, full employment, Friends of SNCC, Reflections on Ivanhoe Donaldson.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_5e872de37ba383c510dc43ffeae44a83" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Schwinn, Gerald</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2012/2012">2012 October 19</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_efd521f233337c44f10ed777ec53c86a"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>With an initial interest in civil rights and nuclear testing, Gerry Schwinn, a Baltimore native, found his way to a conference in Port Huron, Michigan in 1962 that proved to be seminal. The Port Huron Statement launched the Students for a Democratic Society (SDS), a key organization in the development of the anti-war movement and the New Left. Later that same year Gerry experienced the Cuban Missile Crisis up close in the military town of Hampton, Virginia, where the Norfolk Naval Base "almost sank from military activity." Needing a break, he joined the Peace Corps and spent 1963-65 in Nigeria, returning to Washington, DC just as the big anti-Vietnam War marches organized by SDS and other groups were beginning. Most of Gerry's anti-war work was done through the Committee of Returned Volunteers (CRV) founded by returnees of Peace Corps, International Volunteer Service (IVS), American Friends Service Committee (AFSC) among others. Gerry and John McAuliff of AFSC were founding members of this group, which soon came out in opposition to the Vietnam War on the premise that it undermined democratic traditions. CRV made history in 1970 when, during a massive demonstration after the invasion of Cambodia, several members took over the Peace Corps office for 36 hours and displayed a huge Viet Cong flag on the building within sight of the White House. Gerry Schwinn remains a committed activist in Washington, DC. </p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_b855b76f292835a63ff0cc7fd0989082"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Gerry Schwinn interview: Cardozo High School, Peace Corps, Committee of Returned Volunteers (CRV), Home Rule, Incident in segregated Virginia, Cuban Missile Crisis, Viet Cong flag in 1970 demonstration, Trips to Vietnam and Cuba.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_4de1e2732f8938743413bf5fb5f2d209" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Smith, Cliff</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2016/2016">2016 May 27</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_de21bb243bcde5c9de752cbd5a83675d"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Former State Department Foreign Service Officer who was forced out of State due to his increasing opposition to the war in Vietnam and U.S. foreign policy and who became a lifelong activist for democracy.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_5cd56016c7f1b4d57f630b9f95a15605"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Cliff Smith interview: State Department, Patriotic American, Democracy, Anti-war activist, Civil Rights activist, Equal rights, President Kennedy, University of Pennsylvania, Support of Greensboro sit-ins, Foreign Service Officer, Juarez, Mexico, Braceros, Everybody is equal, Iran, Teheran, Anti-war petition, Top secret clearance, Secretary of State, Operations Center in State Department, First anti-war march in April 1967, Pentagon March, 1854 Wyoming Ave, Federal Employees for A Democratic Society, Federal Employees Against the War in Vietnam, Signed Anti-war petition, New York Times article on anti-war petition, First Amendment Right, Resurrection City, Poor People's Campaign, Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo, Reies Tijerina, Tabriz Iran, State Department Open Forum for Young Professionals, Roundtable on Cuba, Peace Corps Volunteers, Draft Counseling, Conscientious Objector status for Peace Corp Volunteers, Moratorium, Anti-war petition in Iran, Left State Department in 1971, Becoming a hippie, Community Book store, Venceremos Brigade, 1854 Wyoming House for Federal Employee Activists, 1972 Arrests, NIMH Demonstration, I.F. Stone, WGTB, Embassy of Atlantis, Marxist Leninist Study Group, WGTB News Collective, Georgeton University, Shutdown WGTB, Fired WGTB staff 1975, Zodiac News Service, reported on AIM Inside BIA, Wounded Knee Live Broadcasts, Allende Overthrow News, Marxist Leninist Study Groups, Communism, Communist Party Marxist Leninist USA, US China People's Friendship Association, Trips to China, Expand Economic Democracy, Part of one movement for democracy, World Council of Churches, Anti-Ballistic Movement, Men re-thinking lives, Women ruling the world, Drugs in 1960's and 1970's, Hash in Iran, Interconnectedness of everything, Living in Washington, DC, Equal rights for women in DC, The value of humor, Cab driver, Tabriz Iran - on the route for hippies in Europe and into Iran.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_6b2f0e056f89e4878e24e07abec2453d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Smith, Frank</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2016/2016">2016 July 25</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_0640b9d21caded98653d9892d5b635ab"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Frank Smith, born in Georgia, was a founding member of the Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee. He came to Washington in the 1960s. He was elected to the Board of Education and the District of Columbia City Council where he served for 16 years. His passion for African-American history led to his work establishing the African-American Civil War Memorial.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_f53f033ddd7b7480d9f2a23f9f4fb534"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Frank Smith interview: Arrived 1968, Institute for Policy Studies, SNCC, New Freedom Party, '62-'68 Mississippi organizer, Ivanhoe Donaldson, Marion Barry, King chance meeting April 1968, Adams-Morgan, SNCC ran the city, John Wilson, Hilda Mason, home rule, Marcus Raskin, Charlotte Bunche Weeks, IPS, Arthur Waskow, School Board, self-help housing, 1971, rent control legislation, First Right to Purchase legislation, changing neighborhood, meetings, Adams-Morgan Organization AMO, affluence, unions, better schools, Julius Hobson, Dunbar for the elites, police violence, Nation of Islam, Black Panthers, lived through a revolution, growing middle class, Museum of African-Americans and the Civil War.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_2b46aa10aaaefcb274a50b9172e00ff3" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Solomon, Norman</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2013/2013">2013 Ocrtober 30</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_46c1b302b3c8b554f58b0f79114d0b2b"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>DC-area high school civil rights and anti-war activist targeted by FBI in the 1960s and early 1970s; later, noted author of numerous anti-war and press criticism books, anti-war filmmaker ("War Made Easy"), founding director of the Institute for Public Accuracy and co-founder of the national group RootsAction.org.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_f975079c247add5cb78609a5ba6acd53"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Norman Solomon interview: Montgomery County Md. high school activism, anti-war and anti-racism activism, "War Made Easy" (book and movie), Institute for Public Accuracy, ExposeFacts.org, Roots Action, FAIR (Fairness and Accuracy in Reporting), Washington D.C., Wilmington DE, USAID (U.S. Agency for International Development), India, Silver Spring Maryland, Calcutta India poverty, Eastern Junior High School, Montgomery Blair High School, Montgomery County Sentinel, Spiro Agnew, FBI file, housing segregation, Summit Hills apartments in Silver Spring, ACCESS (Action Coordinating Committee to End Segregation in the Suburbs), Rep. Carlton Sickles, George Mahoney, Spiro Agnew, ACCESS, FBI file, Adlai Stevenson, Civil rights , McCarthy era, Student Union, Montgomery County Student Alliance, Edgar Hoover, Student rights, military recruiters, anti-war activities, Portland Oregon, FBI, "Wanted: A Humane Education", grape boycott, Farm Workers Union, Brint Dillingham, Debby Barger (Hanrahan) , Compeers, Freedom House, Bethesda Maryland, counterculture, marijuana, police harassment, Vietnam, spray painted antiwar slogans, "revolt for peace", President Richard Nixon, SDS (Students for a Democratic Society), Cathy Wilkerson, Weather Underground, Bill Higgs, Liberation News Service, SDS, Democratic National Convention 1968, Cathy Wilkerson, Montgomery County, Bill Higgs, Free school Park Road, hashish, Steve Miller Band, mental health issues, register with draft board, Draft card, conscientious objector status, 1-A status, California, San Francisco Bay Weekly, Washington Post, Roger Farquhar editor, Montgomery County Sentinel, business page editor, religious page editor, Brint Dillingham, ABM (anti-ballistic missile system), Debby Barger, Washington Free Press, grape boycott, Joe Forer, Ober Law, FBI surveillance, U.S. Department of Health Education and Welfare HEW), Federal Employees for a Democratic Society, Student Alliance, Reed College, Earth Day, Berkeley California, Jackson State, Kent State, Draft lottery, Blair High School, Ramparts Magazine, National Student Association, CIA, Dr. Howard Levy, Carlos Van Leer, White House vigils, Cedar Lane Unitarian Church, Dick Gregory, Gray Panthers, "War Made Easy", Bernard Fall, Gulf of Tonkin, Third Reich, Saddam Hussein, Iraq, Institute for Public Accuracy, Rep. Nick Rahall, U.N. weapons inspectors, Student Alliance, Brint Dillingham, Washington Post, Portland Oregon, obstacles to student activism today, National Security Agency (NSA) surveillance, climate change, Washington Star, Washington Post, Nicholas von Hoffman, March on Pentagon, May Day 1971 arrests, ACLU, General Colin Powell, Lawrence Wilkerson, Democracy Now!, Iraq war, Institute for Public Accuracy, Dick Cheney, Donald Rumsfeld, Scott Ritter, NSA spying, Senator Dianne Feinstein, Baghdad, Nick Rahall, Rep. Richard Gephardt, SDS, Chicago, Democratic National Convention 1968, counter-inaugural 1969, Nicholas von Hoffman, France uprising 1968, "Made Love, Got War", Charles Reich, "The Greening of America", hippie, corporate power , militarism, violent revolution, New Age revolution, working in the system illusion, in the streets, labor unions, Alan Grayson, Dennis Kucinich, Barbara Lee, Richmond California, Chevron, Green Party, Bernie Sanders, Occupy movement.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_d121834938186ce4b20e51d8e7b250a8" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Stockard, Susan</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2017/2017">2017 February 16</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_e7caa2740c0f3aec6fb1e8a14aa51eaa"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Susan Stewart Stockard, now married to Jim, was a student at the first school integrated in Arlington County and the state of Virginia. Her family was part of the activist group that worked with Stockard. </p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_25720184f43642183afe9f01d6ab9e03"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Susan Stewart Stockard interview: James Stockard daughter-in-law, Arlington County Virginia, School integration, Stratford Junior High School 1957-1960, First integrated 1959, Susan's parents, 1959 big event, First day of school, Police and reporters, Susan is interviewed, 5 African American students, Arlington segregated neighborhoods, Arlington segregated churches, Mother attends Howard University, Girls ridicule Susan, No school dances, All-white cheerleaders, A few black athletes, 3 years later integration, Defenders of State Sovereignty sent a letter.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_6a69fcd953c30da2a06079952ff99472" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Stockard Family, James G.</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2017/2017">2017 February 16</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ca1aafff465da41bdea5f781b6a2fd3b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The three adult children of James G. Stockard ( James G. Stockard Jr, Ruth Stockard Flynn, and Janet Stockard de Merode ) discuss their father and what it was like growing up in Arlington Virginia while their father was a civil rights activist. Stockard served on the Arlington County School Board from 1955 to 1968. This was a time of great turmoil over integration. Stockard's was a wise, tolerant, and pro-integration voice.</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_a75871d4a3da4ea887270a8242d1d221"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for James Stockard Family interview: James G. Stockard, leading civil rights leader, Janet Stockard DeMarott 1955-1967, Ruth Stockard Flynn 1950s, James G. Stockard Jr. 1950s, 1956 PTA school committee, Implementing Brown v Board, Election 1955 nasty, Father ran for school committee, Election night, Pro-integration member majority, Virginia bans elected school boards, Harry Byrd, Stockard lobbies for elected board, Southern Baptist, Voting with Jesus and Jefferson, 1961 Baptist church refuses entry to black family, Stockards leave church, Defenders of State Sovereignty…, George Lincoln Rockwell, Nazi Party, Separate seating in county court, Nasty kids, Phone threats, Cross burning, Nazi pamphlet about Stockard, Nadine John Stockard, Odd Arlington school districts, Washington-Lee High School integration.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_fd0e90516a2401663fb2ade1125bbf3b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Tabor, Michael (Jews for Urban Justice)</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2015/2015">2015 August 28</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_f45f3a67efed0fcca067f6ec5e48f546"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>An activist and organizer in the Washington, D.C. area for more than five decades on a wide array of issues, including free speech rights, opposition to the Vietnam War, for racial justice and for sustainable agriculture. In the first interview, Michael describes his work over several years with Jews for Urban Justice, including their work challenging Jewish apartment owners and the Jewish community leadership in perpetuating slum housing, redlining and other housing inequities, and their work with Arthur Waskow organizing the first Freedom Seder.  The second interview covers his civil rights and anti-Vietnam War organizing in the Maryland suburbs, including active involvement in local Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) and Students for a Democratic Society (SDS) chapters, his activism while working at the Department of Health, Education and Welfare (HEW), his work with the Jewish Renewal Movement, and the beginnings of his long-term ownership of Licking Creek Bend Farm and its focus on sustainably grown produce.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_6f1e0640f8549afc31cdfa652a062695"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Michael Tabor - Jews for Urban Justice (JUJ) interview: working class upbringing, mother a bookkeeper, Chelsea Hotel, Brooklyn, Queens, Fort Green, Parsons Junior High School, public school education, SUNY – State University of New York, WASPs – White Angle-Saxon Protestants, Free Speech Movement, underground newspaper, activist grandmother and mother, conservative and orthodox Judaism, Fort Green Jewish Center, HUAC – House Unamerican Activities Committee, censorship, University of Maryland Graduate School, Route 1 segregated in 1963, Uncle Tom's Cabins – Beltsville, CORE – Congress of Racial Equality, SDS – Students for a Democratic Society, activism, sit-ins, segregation, Freedom Summer 1964, ERAP – Education Research Action Program, Joint SDS-CORE project, JUJ – Jews for Urban Justice, federal worker – 1968, discussion groups, ACCESS – Action Coordinating Committee to End Segregation, in the suburbs, restrictive covenants, housing, Jews in real estate, Jewish slumlords, work vs ethics, JUJ – first wave fight against racism in north, Sharlene Kranz, militancy, confrontation, no compromise, Freedom Now, Poor People's Campaign – 1968, 2000 sandwiches, Arthur Waskow, JCC – Jewish Community Center – shower facilities, Arnold Sternberg, Mother's Day Welfare Rights March, Coretta Scott King, Grape Boycott – 1968, Joseph Danzansky, Giant Food, Harold White, Guardian Savings, redlining, Arthur Waskow, consciousness raising group, white skin privilege, riots – 1968, ghetto tour, Camp Moshava, Habonim Dror, Brint Dillingham, George Wiley, Channing Phillips, Freedom Seder, JCRC – Jewish Community Relations Council Urban Affairs Committee, Sharon Rose, reparations, James Forman, guerrilla theater, shmattas for shvartzes – rags for blacks, public housing law – 1966, Jews acting as Christians, new left, exploiting others, Topper Carew, Balfour Brickner, Lincoln Temple, Freedom Seder 1969 800 people, Let all who are hungry come and eat, Baltimore Freedom Seder, George Malzone, middle east, Israel-Palestine, controversy, Jewish social justice group, Arthur Waskow, many similar groups, first national conference, Radnor PA 1970, The Jewish Urban Guerrilla, confrontational, Jews United for Justice, Diaspora Kibbutz – 1971, healthy organic food, 18th and Columbia farmer's market, activist, Jamie Raskin, Bernie Sanders, neocons, speak up against tyranny.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_856239f83f2ce62455511171e8381bce" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Tabor, Michael (Challenging Segregation)</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2018-03-28/2018-03-28">2018 March 28</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_39000d3905f37c6e419effc303227401"><head>Biography</head><p>Biography provided by the donor: <br/>
An activist and organizer in the Washington, D.C. area for more than five decades on a wide array of issues, including free speech rights, opposition to the Vietnam War, for racial justice and for sustainable agriculture</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_9b21626fd63ea24899fa4f5dba0d54cd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Information provided by the donor: Michael Tabor discusses his civil rights and anti-Vietnam War organizing in the Maryland suburbs, including active involvement in local Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) and Students for a Democratic Society (SDS) chapters, his activism while working at the Department of Health, Education and Welfare (HEW), his work with the Jewish Renewal Movement, and the beginnings of his long-term ownership of Licking Creek Bend Farm and its focus on sustainably grown produce.</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_dd30d1b2459cf312e4a8c47845aa95e3"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor: <br/>
Michael Tabor, Mike Tabor, 1960-75, organizer, civil rights, anti-vietnam war movement, grape boycott, first Jewish new-left political group in U.S., Norman Thomas, parents democrats, Army-McCarthy hearings, 1950s fear, low-income public housing – Fort Greene in Brooklyn, working class background, SUNY-Oneonta, underground newspaper, Pete Seeger sang – 1961, University of Maryland, March on Washington – 1963, segregated restaurants, Adelphi – sundown town, CORE – Congress of Racial Equality, voter registration in North Carolina, local SDS chapter, Cedar Heights, Freedom House, SCLC, Martin Luther King Jr., Prince George's County, CORE suit against school segregation, joint CORE/SDS/ERAP project against segregation, ACCESS – Action Coordinating Committee to End Segregation in the Suburbs, Julius Hobson, Jewish slumlords, Bel Air at Bowie, march around the Beltway against segregation, HUAC, Chuck Jones, George Lincoln Rockwell and Nazis, KKK, White Citizens Council chapter, social worker, fired for picketing Human Relations Commission, organizer for April 17 1965 march against the war, James Reeb, SSOC – Southern Students Organizing Committee, Fannie Lou Hamer, Aaron Henry, Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, Democratic Convention – 1964, SNCC – Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee, Bob Moses, John F Kennedy, corporate liberalism, Baker's Dozen organizing project - Columbia Heights, Catholic men's group, Phil Berrigan, Father McSorley, Pentagon sit-in against segregated housing, Robert McNamara, Brint Dillingham, Center for Emergency Support, white skin privilege, Arthur Waskow, Cathy Wilkerson, Tabor a new left socialist/Bookchin anarchist, George Wiley, FEDS – Federal Employees for a Democratic Society, HEW, The Condition of the Federal Employee and How to Change It, Thursday Discussion Group, ACLU support, grape boycott – targeted Giant Food, organizing in Jewish Community, Jews for Urban Justice, street theater, Rabbi Harold White, poured "blood of workers" on grapes, Jews for Urban Justice, Arthur Waskow, Freedom Seder, Community of Micah, Jewish Renewal Movement, Fabrengen, People's Peace Treaty, Madame Binh, peace treaty between Jewish community and Vietnam, raised money for medicine and trees, 1972 study group - communes, worker-run farm, Licking Creek, CAFOs – Concentrated Animal Feeding Operation, nuclear waste dump, farmer's market at 18th and Columbia Rd, apple cider to Florida and organic oranges from Florida to local co-ops like Fields of Plenty and Glut, elect local progressives.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_1c4c9c75f0ff3dba21de4f5ede9cd1da" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Treanor, William</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2017/2017">2017 April 20</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_c749cee0deddb853361e1fef545d9b13"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Bill Treanor has been a Washington, DC fixture since the early 1960s, first as a student activist at Georgetown University, then as an organizer for SCLC, one of the great civil rights organizations of the 60s, later as an elected official to DC's first elected School Board and, finally, as an advocate for youth. A high school dropout himself, Bill served in the US Army before entering Georgetown University in 1963. His civil rights experience included staff work for the 1968 Poor Peoples' Campaign. He is best known for his long time leadership in support of youth services, which included the founding of Runaway House and the publication of Youth Today, a monthly national periodical for people working in the field.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_c02775ef56774d4897b527593a577325"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for William Treanor interview: Jesuit Richard Mc Sorley a major influence at Georgetown, Organizer in South with SCLC (Southern Christian Leadership Conference) , Poor Peoples' Campaign, Resurrection City, National Youth Work Alliance, DC School Board, Marion Barry, Runaway House, Dupont Circle in the 1970s, On leadership, Anti-Freeway Fight, Hosea Williams and Ralph Abernathy- SCLC leaders at Resurrection City, Sammy Abbott and Reggie Booker – leaders in Anti-Freeway Fight, Debbie Shore, Sasha Bruce House, Lori Kaplan, Latin-American Youth Center.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_247aaacd742098aafcc4c798e54fc731" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Tucker, Kitty</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2015/2015" type="inclusive">2015 March 12 and 2015 August 28</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_e18c0acae6b85d59c71125feab14176f"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>(1944-2019) - Environmental, health and anti-nuclear activist who was a leader of the Washington, D.C. Karen Silkwood campaign and a key participant in the Washington, D.C. coalition to impeach President Nixon.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_68fdfcc794fa71b616f5fde920144e25"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Kitty Tucker interview: Kitty Tucker, Karen Silkwood, Richard Nixon, impeachment.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_c9233f994490649bfbab8629d2f0352d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: White, Harold</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2015/2015">2015 March 19</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_c5b7afc8bdc8a16a323032ef3678852d"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>(1932-2015) - Rabbi Harold White was a long-time activist for civil rights, social justice, peace and interfaith dialogue.  Beginning in 1968, he was an active member of Jews for Urban Justice (JUJ), which began by challenging the Jewish community of the Washington area to confront discriminatory housing practices by Jewish landlords. He was an active contributor to the first Freedom Seder in 1968. He was the first rabbi hired full-time by a U.S. Catholic university, spending more than half a century at Georgetown University teaching and counseling and promoting interreligious understanding. He was one of the first in the Washington area to perform interfaith marriages.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_599b72dea239cdd6547c4884aeb74bb6"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Harold White interview: Rabbi Harold White, Mike Tabor, Jews for Urban Justice, radical/revolutionary, Fabrengen, become a rabbi "to save the world", JUJ, rabbi in Ann Arbor 1962-1968, Ann Arbor city council, open housing, Chair, Ann Arbor/Washtenaw Conference on Religion and Race, Chair, Ann Arbor Conference on Religion and Peace, civil rights movement, peace movement, peace marches in Washington, Max Ticktin, Hillel, work with students, JUJ in Washington , little involvement by local rabbis in peace marches, grape boycott, Gidalia Cohen, Giant Food, Joe Danzansky, oshek -Talmudic principle, food substance used for oppression is trayfe, Jewish classes for JUJ, large Victorian house on Q St, prophetic idea of justice, Jeremiah, Talmudic ethics, just war, Jewish mysticism, Kabbala, Abraham Joshua Heschel, Mordechai Kaplan, Shabbat service, May Day 1970, Adin Steinsaltz, safe house for May Day, Guardian Federal Savings, usurious interest, Arthur Waskow, new left orientation, prophetic tradition, shift in JUJ, politics of Israel, Freedom Seder, Channing Phillips, First Black-Jewish seder, Balfour Brickner, personal liberation, Sharlene Kranz, Sharon Rose, Zionism – Jewish national liberation, Arno Renard, Paul Rutke, Eleanor Epstein, Bob &amp; Bonnie Aptekar, Arnold Sternberg, Poor People's Campaign, Balfour Brickner, Eugene Lippman, Theodore Bikel, Rob Agus, transition from JUJ to Fabrengen, Isaac Frank, Georgetown University, Jewish Community Council , "Shmatas for the Shvartzes program", freedom to express his views, limits of pulpit rabbis to speak up, Reform Judaism – prophetic Judaism, Al Vorspan – Reform leader, 1968 riots, burning of Jewish businesses, People's Peace Treaty, Abraham Joshua Heschel, Studied life of Ho Chi Minh, We were backing wrong side, 1966 prison chaplain, Purple Gang, transition from JUJ to Fabrengen, Judaism as a civilization – a religion, a nation and a people, Jewish renewal, spy for Jewish Federation Board in classes, turned Jeremiah into member of Fatah, Jeremiah a radical, David Shneyer, free Georgetown high holiday services, Bet Mishpacha, tribalism vs acceptance, covenant religion, co-director of interfaith project at Georgetown, conducted interfaith marriages, married Ronnie Karpen and Michael Moffit, Marcus Raskin second marriages, Ari Fleischer marriage, Pearl Bailey funeral, Washington Hebrew Congregation, Adat Shalom, not enough passion today for causes, JUJ people filled with passion, redemptive power of collective memory, Jewish United for Justice, Bar Mitzvah at age 83.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_1c8275e6892161714d076d000cac79fc" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interview: Wolfson, Alice</unittitle><unitid>MS2388</unitid><unitdate datechar="Creation" normal="2017/2017">2017 April 11</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_d3415eeaea9aff1366e13cb7d92a367a"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Alice Wolfson is a veteran political activist and a pioneer in the women's health movement. She belonged to DC Women's Liberation, and was a member of "The Daughters of Lilith" collective. Hers was one of the leading voices protesting the lack of female participation in the 1970 Pill Hearings, as well as the deliberate withholding of information regarding oral contraceptives' dangerous side effects. Alice was one of the founders of the National Women's Health Network (NWHN) and organized many other actions during the NWHN's early years, including a sit-in in the office of the Secretary of the Department of Health, Education and Welfare, and the first FDA Protest. Alice served on the NWHN board of directors for several years. She also co-founded the Committee to Defend Reproductive Rights, which fought for and won both California state regulations protecting women against sterilization abuse and court decisions guaranteeing MediCal coverage of abortion. Today, Alice is a lawyer fighting for the rights of disabled individuals who have been discriminated against by their insurance companies.</p><p>Biography provided by the donor.</p></bioghist><odd id="aspace_7ef5e9497fd9476de85adcfb1a5109a2"><head>Keywords</head><p>Keywords provided by the donor for Alice Wolfson interview: Alice Wolfson, women's movement, 1969, group living, women's health movement, birth control pills, abortion issue, DC women's liberation, Daughters of Lilith, side effects of birth control pills, Congressional hearings on birth control pills, long term health effects of the pill, closed hearings on the pill, need for warning on the pill, first patient safety warning in package, abortion was not legal, Guttmacher Institute, pill was welcomed, dalkon shield, DES daughters, anti-imperialist women's collective, Budapest women's meeting, women's voice in the anti-Vietnam War movement, Women's Strike for Peace, Toronto conference with Vietnam women, gay-straight split, Magic Quilt in DC, meeting place for Magic Quilt, Witches, guerilla theater, 1970, Code Pink, AIDS activism, organized own pill hearings, St. Stephen's Church, living in communes, welfare rights, DC General, mortality rates in DC, Etta Horn, estrogen replacement therapy, rise of midwifery, Our Bodies Ourselves, National Organization for Women, Betty Friedan, reproductive health movement, Off Our Backs, women's movement around the country, Children's House in DC, Marxist-Leninist Study Groups.</p></odd></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
