<?xml version='1.0' encoding='LATIN-1'?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collection_level_record" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="https://searcharchives.library.gwu.edu/repositories/2/resources/839">ms2385.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Charles Blaschke Education TURNKEY Papers, <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1964-2018</date> <num>MS2385</num></titleproper>
        <author>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2019</date>
        </p>
        <address>
          <addressline>2130 H Street NW</addressline>
          <addressline>Washington 20052</addressline>
          <addressline>speccoll@gelman.gwu.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-01-11 11:55:03 -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language encodinganalog="language">English</language></langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Charles Blaschke Education TURNKEY Systems Papers</unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Blaschke, Charles L.</persname>
      </origination>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Education Turnkey Systems</corpname>
      </origination>
      <origination label="source">
        <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Hurley, Kathleen (Kathleen Mary)</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>MS2385</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">16.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/2018" type="inclusive">1964-2018</unitdate>
      <physloc id="aspace_fce6cb6871c60e3222180b26b1d378c9">Materials are stored off-site, and will require additional retrieval time.  Please contact the Special Collections Research Center for more information.</physloc>
      <abstract id="aspace_6ea57c3d0afa8e545e09934e1bdf9c1f">Charles Blaschke worked in the Johnson Administration on education policy and later started Education TURNKEY Systems, a consultanting company that provided market research, analysis, planning and funding information about educational technology to more than 1,200 local education agencies, every state education agency and over 800 policy makers. The majority of the collection consists of TURNKEY's reports. The only exception is box UP 1, which contains some background material on Blaschke himself from his time at Harvard and serving in the military.</abstract>
      <langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_065d94554f206d8792847587a5fc6ac9">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>This collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_243d858f715d7d1d86d713dc6934b8e4">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
      <p>To the extent that he/she owns copyright, the donor has assigned the copyright in her works to The George Washington University; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For activities that the researcher determines fall under fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. Please contact Special Collections if the copyright status of the materials you wish to reuse is unclear. Staff will provide additional information. 
For re-use of materials in the collection not created by the donor, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights, determining if the intended re-use falls under fair use, and obtaining approval from the copyright holder if the intended use does not fall under fair use. For such materials, researchers do not need anything further from The George Washington University's Special Collections Research Center.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_5d6cac6748a43d4cecf6edf0a38261b2">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Please cite unpublished materials in the following way:</p>
      <p>Please provide the title and date of item, catalog number (if applicable it will be found written on the folder), name of the collection, name of the repository, and location of the repository. </p>
      <p>Example:
James Oglethorpe to the Trustees, 13 January 1876, RG0001 Series 1, Box 4, Folder 3.  Records of the Board of Trustees, Special Collections Research Center, Gelman Library, The George Washington University, Washington, D.C.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_0611547e6908ef3aa154a53956ae9a42">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_3716d6971f33456e63169c23d3f32df1">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>Charles Blaschke began his career working in the Johnson Administration, In his role as an advisor on education policy, he helped draft Title I, the most ambitious federal education legislation to date when it passed. After leaving the Johnson Administration in 1967, Blaschke founded Education TURNKEY, a private consulation company that provided market research, analysis, planning and funding information about educational technology to more than 1,200 local education agencies, every state education agency and over 800 policy makers.</p>
      <p>Source: Obituary of Charles Blaschke provided by the donor</p>
    </bioghist>
    <processinfo id="aspace_d4e1e4d8bbd83f00bf858724f4d970d4">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>This collection is unprocessed. Box UP 1 contains papers unrelated to Education TURNKEY. The box consists of Charles Blaschke's personal papers from his time at Harvard and serving in the military. The rest of the boxes in the collection contain binders of Education TURNKEY Systems' reports on market research, analysis, planning and funding information about educational technology.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_b2a574b40010fa3d60597e62fd9f62c0">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>There are 11 boxes in the collection. Box 1 contains records created before the founding of Education TURNKEY Systems. These are mostly records of Blaschke's time at Harvard and in the military. Boxes 2 through 11 contains Education TURNKEY Systems' reports on market research, analysis, planning and funding information about educational technology and related policies.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <persname role="fmo" rules="aacr" source="naf">Hurley, Kathleen (Kathleen Mary)</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc/>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
