<?xml version='1.0' encoding='LATIN-1'?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://library.gwu.edu/ead/mvc0061.xml">mvc0061.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Margaret McBride Karns Mount Vernon Seminary papers, <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1888-2000</date> 
 <num>MVC0061.MS</num></titleproper>
        <author>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2011</date>
        </p>
        <address>
          <addressline>2130 H Street NW</addressline>
          <addressline>Washington 20052</addressline>
          <addressline>speccoll@gelman.gwu.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-01-11 11:45:12 -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language encodinganalog="language">English</language></langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Margaret McBride Karns Mount Vernon Seminary papers</unittitle>
      <unitid>MVC0061.MS</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">1 document box and 2 flat boxes</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1888/2000" type="inclusive">1888-2000</unitdate>
      <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1930/1975" type="bulk">1930-1975</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_646671258bb403e3a19456d98ed81a4d">Margaret McBride Karns (1910-2010) was a graduate of Mount Vernon Seminary, a private women's high school, and later college, in Washington, D.C. The George Washington University initially affiliated with Mount Vernon College, and ultimately acquired the college's property and legacy in 1999. This collection contains papers, ephemera, and memorabilia pertaining to the Mount Vernon Seminary and College collected by alumna Margaret McBride Karns, Seminary class of 1931. The bulk of the material is related to the Mount Vernon Seminary, and Karns' association with the school as a student and as an alumna. The materials date from 1888 to 2000, with the bulk dating between 1930 and 1975.</abstract>
      <physloc id="aspace_ea48c66e30b275e8d2fba44dc134ae23">Materials may be stored off-site, and may require additional retrieval time.  Please contact the Special Collections Research Center for more information.</physloc>
      <langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <arrangement id="aspace_6be764dfcde921d1388550670779a00f">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>The papers and ephemera in this collection are filed by subject, and then by rough chronological order. Realia and oversize material are at the end.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_ed304aebd5016a0eb5d4937b16bf1bc2">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>This collection contains papers, ephemera, and memorabilia pertaining to the Mount Vernon Seminary and College collected by alumna Margaret McBride Karns, Seminary class of 1931. The bulk of the material is related to the Mount Vernon Seminary, and Karns' association with the school as a student and as an alumna. The materials date from 1888 to 2000, with the bulk dating between 1930 and 1975.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <prefercite id="aspace_b6a27e511a650899ba949d762d3ce871">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Please cite unpublished materials in the following way:</p>
      <p>Please provide the title and date of item, catalog number (if applicable it will be found written on the folder), name of the collection, name of the repository, and location of the repository. </p>
      <p>Example:
James Oglethorpe to the Trustees, 13 January 1876, RG0001 Series 1, Box 4, Folder 3.  Records of the Board of Trustees, Special Collections Research Center, Gelman Library, The George Washington University, Washington, D.C.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <userestrict id="aspace_675e99a44d802070db4d1231e1e5a1eb">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
      <p>Some material may be copyrighted or restricted. It is the patron's obligation to determine and satisfy copyright or other case restrictions when publishing or otherwise distributing materials found in the collections.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_3756ea186559202cfcd1f96bf508fcce">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>This collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_00cc780c48cd0302d4c3191ba10550a4">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
      <p>Gift of the estate of Margaret McBride Karns, March 15, 2011 (2011.023).</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_7ba52b6b6c8e400ccfc8188acc303f7d">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>Margaret McBride Karns (1910-2010) was a graduate of Mount Vernon Seminary, a private women's high school and later college in Washington, D.C. The George Washington University initially affiliated with Mount Vernon College, and ultimately acquired the college's property and legacy in 1999. </p>
      <p>Ms. Karns was born July 9, 1910 to  Dr. Lewis E. and Emma Lamberton McBride. Mrs. Karns was a graduate of Franklin High School in Franklin, Pennyslvania in 1929. She graduated from Mount Vernon College in 1931, and she graduated from the Special Course for College Women at the Katherine Gibbs School in Boston, Massachusetts. </p>
      <p>Ms. Karns was employed as an executive secretary by Pennzoil Company, Oil City, from 1933 to 1953. She married Frederick P. Karns on November 28, 1953.</p>
      <p>She was a member of the Board of Directors of Franklin Hospital for six years, serving as Secretary of the Board for three years. She was Chairman of Advance Gifts for four years, while a member of Franklin Area United Fund. She was Women's Chairman, Venango County Savings Bond Committee from September 20, 1961 to November 5, 1969.</p>
      <p>Her volunteer work included serving as an American Red Cross volunteer nurse aide during World War II, work with the Hospital Hostess Shop, and work for the eye screening program of Venango County Association for the Blind. Drives for charitable organizations, such as Cerebral Palsy, American Heart Association, American Cancer Society, and United Way also received her volunteer efforts.</p>
      <p>Margaret Karns was a member of the Monday Club of Oil City Pennsylvania and Franklin Pennsylvania, Wednesday Club of Franklin, The Franklin Club, Ladies Auxiliary of Franklin Commandery No. 44; Nursery Chapter No. 25, Order of Eastern Star; St. Hilda's Guild of St. John Episcopal Church, a former and 25-year member of St. John's Altar Guild; Friends of the Library and Franklin Library Association; honorary member of Northwest Health System Corporation, Northwest Medical Center Auxiliary, life member of Venango County Historical Society, Venango Chapter NSDAR, member of DAR Northwestern District Regent's Club, The Retired Officers Association Auxiliary, and Historic Franklin Preservation Association.</p>
      <p>Ms. Karns also gave of her time to the Mount Vernon Seminary Alumni Assocation, serving as a Class Agent for the Class of 1931 during the school's annual fund campaigns. </p>
      <p>As a member of the First Presbyterian Church of Franklin from 1927 to 1954 she served as Deacon and Secretary of the Board of Deacons from 1952 to 1953. After her marriage in The First Presbyterian Church to Frederick P. Karns, she was confirmed in 1954 in St. John Episcopal Church.</p>
      <p>In 1962 she was recipient of Franklin Chamber of Commerce citizenship award, "Woman of the Year."</p>
      <p>She also supported the DeBence Antique Music Museum, Barrow Civic Theatre and Franklin Fine Arts Council.</p>
      <p>She was preceded in death by her parents, her husband in 1984, and a brother Lewis E. McBride Jr in 1981.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <separatedmaterial id="aspace_149627a780b96d6c88382cd30032c3be">
      <head>Separated Materials</head>
      <p>The following materials were separated from this collection and integrated into other Mount Vernon Seminary and College collections:</p>
      <p>Added to the Mount Vernon Seminary and College Alumnae Office records, MVC0043, Series 1:</p>
      <p>-Mount Vernon Seminary and College Bulletins, 1958-1996.</p>
      <p>Added to the Mount Vernon Seminary and College Alumnae Association records, MVC0049</p>
      <p>- Annual Reports of the Mount Vernon Seminary Alumnae Association, 1931-1933.</p>
      <p>- Mount Vernon Seminary and Junior College directories, 1937 and 1951</p>
      <p>- Mount Vernon Seminary Alumnae Roll Calls, 1930-1939.</p>
    </separatedmaterial>
    <odd id="aspace_f7b0590595ac123369400493d72ce558">
      <head>Bib#</head>
      <p>8933875</p>
    </odd>
    <controlaccess>
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Karns, Margaret McBride</persname>
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Mount Vernon College</corpname>
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Mount Vernon Seminary</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_ref8_tdr" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Mount Vernon Seminary Correspondence, Clippings, and Ephemera</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1888/1999" type="inclusive">1888-1999</unitdate>
          <langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
          <container id="aspace_9414253997fa3850ea0aaabfb3953f4d" label="Mixed Materials [32882020115039]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_6b0b7085c48dc52be487f112e95db38a" parent="aspace_9414253997fa3850ea0aaabfb3953f4d" type="Folder">1</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref9_3z7" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Mount Vernon Seminary Exams</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1929/1930" type="inclusive">1929-1930</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_18b3523b2f7447393c80b64d4f0da484" label="Text [32882020115039]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_6e79c5eb7e122aa6c4becb5b30bf9c42" parent="aspace_18b3523b2f7447393c80b64d4f0da484" type="Folder">2</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref10_g2a" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>"The Cupola" yearbook with signatures</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1930/1930" type="inclusive">1930</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_103671bb88832f89ea7016b03688f00c" label="Books [32882020115039]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_c33cdf1f5739693738033ce08d5e486d" parent="aspace_103671bb88832f89ea7016b03688f00c" type="Folder">3</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref11_9a0" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>"The Cupola" yearbook with signatures</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1931/1931" type="inclusive">1931</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_13db1ee2925d111fade2bdcde2a4a70b" label="Books [32882020115039]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_12b732becd31b4b87c8d2f6d6473750a" parent="aspace_13db1ee2925d111fade2bdcde2a4a70b" type="Folder">4</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref13_otf" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Mount Vernon Seminary Alumnae Reunions, Class of 1931</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1989" type="inclusive">1950-1989</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_7742b4441dc1caa51786b8b12fdfe341" label="Mixed Materials [32882020115039]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_a4783b941c39eae2c9edee062497670e" parent="aspace_7742b4441dc1caa51786b8b12fdfe341" type="Folder">5</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref14_d6h" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Mount Vernon Seminary Annual Fund Campaigns</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1975" type="inclusive">1973-1975</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_bbe96ff709a9bc4fb8e11e400124aa26" label="Text [32882020115039]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_737cb6218e33d50232e1e3e3f2314414" parent="aspace_bbe96ff709a9bc4fb8e11e400124aa26" type="Folder">6</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref12_y2u" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Mount Vernon College Centennial Celebration</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1975" type="inclusive">1975</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_cccb1fa4bb2332356b5f12974be9a3ae" label="Mixed Materials [32882020115039]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_ecbf623f91f8e13e9d6aac121ab86cc9" parent="aspace_cccb1fa4bb2332356b5f12974be9a3ae" type="Folder">7</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref15_ksu" level="item">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Mount Vernon Seminary Silver Cup</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1931/1931" type="inclusive">1931</unitdate>
          <physdesc>
            <dimensions id="aspace_bdb168396ec6b6a41e2675d045c83b76">18.5 cm high, 14 cm wide.</dimensions>
          </physdesc>
          <physdesc id="aspace_b3eca6e4127348e72a25e931cc003267">Kantharos-shaped silver cup, engraved with the following:

"Presented to Margaret L. McBride by the faculty of Mount Vernon Seminary for her achievement as student president 1930-1931."</physdesc>
          <container id="aspace_00caa579aa6feacd9a7a5b6de11350d4" label="Realia [32882020115047]" type="flat_box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_6df2a6b40e9cc6207bfb6d5587135697" parent="aspace_00caa579aa6feacd9a7a5b6de11350d4" type="object">1</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref18_m6t" level="item">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Mount Vernon Seminary Diploma</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1931/1931" type="inclusive">May 1931</unitdate>
          <physdesc>
            <dimensions id="aspace_5e5f25a06d358ba2686ac1c3a2357ee2">18" x 15"</dimensions>
          </physdesc>
          <container id="aspace_ad09c7035a625928ad8da8834d06ee6a" label="Text [32882020115310]" type="flat_box">2</container>
        </did>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
