<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://library.gwu.edu/ead/NEA1011.xml"/>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>
          <num>NEA1011.RG</num>
        </titleproper>
        <author>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>2130 H Street NW</addressline>
          <addressline>Washington 20052</addressline>
          <addressline>speccoll@gelman.gwu.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-01-18 12:06:30 -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language encodinganalog="language">English</language></langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="subfonds">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>National Education Association Web Archives Collection (version 2)</unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/entities/providers/cd935c5eb8246d2909202d3efc147de8" rules="aacr" source="naf">National Education Association of the United States</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>NEA1011.RG</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">89.7 Gigabytes</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2015-07-06/2018-11-28" type="inclusive">2015 July 6 through 2018 November 29</unitdate>
      <physloc id="aspace_2f4ace8b976154ed376dafbab83f5bbc">Records are stored on a web-accessible server.</physloc>
      <langmaterial><language langcode="mul">Multiple languages</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_c569177029c686ec91caff277ca9b2de">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>This collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <arrangement id="aspace_dc4feda3098cc47003d1f8e47fa6ecaa">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>Series are arranged in alpabetical order by title.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <bioghist id="aspace_02b3eff9530aeb189a824518d79173ed">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>The National Education Association (NEA) is the largest professional organization and largest labor union in the United States, representing public school teachers and other support personnel, faculty and staffers at colleges and universities, retired educators, and college students preparing to become teachers. In 2010, the NEA had 3.2 million members and is located in Washington, D.C. The group holds a congressional charter under Title 36 of the United States Code granted in 1906. The NEA describes itself as a professional employee organization. The mission of the National Education Association is "to advocate for education professionals and to unite our members and the nation to fulfill the promise of public education to prepare every student to succeed in a diverse and interdependent world." The NEA is a volunteer-based organization that relies upon its members to perform much of the Association's work. The members are supported by staff at the local, state, and national levels with the stated goal of "building great public schools for every student." In 1857, Thomas W. Valentine, president of the New York State Teachers Association, issued a nation-wide invitation to teachers to unite in Philadelphia behind a common voice for America's growing public school system. After the meeting, the National Teachers Association (NTA) was formed with a membership of about 100. Minority educators were allowed to join at the start, but women were not allowed to join until 1866. In 1870, the NTA merged with the American Normal School Association, the National Association of School Superintendents, and the Central College Association renaming itself the National Education Association. For the first 100 years of its existence, the NEA was controlled by administrators, and worked to further the interests of the "education profession" as a whole. In the 1960's, after the first passage of a collective bargaining law for public employees, the NEA adopted union activities in addition to its operations as a professional association. The NEA merged with the American Teachers Association (ATA), formerly the National Association of Teachers in Colored Schools (NATCS) in 1966. In 1998, a proposed merger with the American Federation of Teachers (AFT) failed when it was rejected by NEA's Representative Assembly. Several NEA state affiliates have merged with their AFT counterparts, effectively forming a single association. Over the years, the NEA has been a leader in national education reform and improvement movements. It has worked to improve the education provided to American school children through lobbying and campaigning on the local and national level as well as by promoting strong teacher education programs and continuous professional assessment and development.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <prefercite id="aspace_766aadebd96d32edcf565a6e23b82afb">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Please cite unpublished materials in the following way:</p>
      <p>Please provide the title and date of item, catalog number (if applicable it will be found written on the folder), name of the collection, name of the repository, and location of the repository. </p>
      <p>Example:
James Oglethorpe to the Trustees, 13 January 1876, RG0001 Series 1, Box 4, Folder 3.  Records of the Board of Trustees, Special Collections Research Center, Gelman Library, The George Washington University, Washington, D.C.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_df4661b804e6e4c1b6e1ab82ccafca75">
      <head>Related Materials</head>
      <p>The records of the National Education Association. The collection inventory can be found here: https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/search/finding-aids-by-topic/nea</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_041f2f51122245e6a39589c60672df06">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>This collection consists of snapshots taken from 20 websites operated by or affiliated with the National Education Association and archived. The websites were selected because they are affiliated with the NEA, either operated by the Association or on behalf of NEA leadership. Individual websites have been organized into 7 groups which reflect the purpose or intended audience of the original website.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <userestrict id="aspace_183af7391c55d69a11a88cde8535a47f">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
      <p>To the extent that they own copyright, the National Education Association as donor has licensed their materials to be used for non-commercial research, scholarly, or other educational uses. Copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For activities that the researcher determines fall under fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For re-use of materials in the collection not created by the donor, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights, determining if the intended re-use falls under fair use, and obtaining approval from the copyright holder if the intended use does not fall under fair use. Researchers do not need anything further from The George Washington University Special Collections Research Center. Please contact Special Collections if the copyright status of the materials you wish to reuse is unclear. Staff will provide additional information.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Education -- Finance</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Education</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Education policy</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Gay rights</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Women's rights</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Educational law and legislation</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Employee rights</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Education, Bilingual -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Civil rights</subject>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_24b372d8873d3b08db685852aefa88a5" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Advocacy</unittitle>
          <unitid>Series 1</unitid>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2015-07-06/2018-11-28" type="inclusive">Harvested multiple times between 6 July 2015 and 29 November 2018</unitdate>
          <langmaterial><language langcode="mul">Multiple languages</language>.</langmaterial>
        </did>
        <odd id="aspace_b5925cb0e76f613bf18ede871ef8936e">
          <head>Link to web-based resource</head>
          <p>https://archive-it.org/collections/6009?fc=websiteGroup%3AAdvocacy</p>
        </odd>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_9fbcef558e756fc9898cb822b18cee86">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The collection consists of archived snapshots of websites and web-based resources that provide tools for advocates working on issues of importance to the NEA. Some of these websites are connected to larger campaigns, such as the Priorty Schools Campaign, and others offer stand-alone resources.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_d4930deacf6b2cd30277587c97e158d0" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Caucuses</unittitle>
          <unitid>Series 2</unitid>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2017-10-25/2018-11-28" type="inclusive">Harvested multiple times between 25 October 2017 and 28 November 2018</unitdate>
          <langmaterial><language langcode="mul">Multiple languages</language>.</langmaterial>
        </did>
        <odd id="aspace_4bc3c62eac587dd12b6e7c9d88c28003">
          <head>Link to web-based resource</head>
          <p>https://archive-it.org/collections/6009?fc=websiteGroup%3ACaucus</p>
        </odd>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_fa032fb054307996f9ab2684457156ee">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The collection consists of archived snapshots of websites and web-based resources that are operated by individual NEA caucuses. The websites provide governance information for affiliated caucuses and resources for members.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_4c93d4093b936c3246780fdbed90af59" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Leadership</unittitle>
          <unitid>Series 3</unitid>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2015-07-06/2018-11-29" type="inclusive">Harvested multiple times between 6 July 2015 and 29 November 2018</unitdate>
          <langmaterial><language langcode="mul">Multiple languages</language>.</langmaterial>
        </did>
        <odd id="aspace_70632085a13d423f4f728a1a65d947fa">
          <head>Link to web-based resource</head>
          <p>https://archive-it.org/collections/6009?fc=websiteGroup%3ALeadership</p>
        </odd>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_04574a3c4865bc34ae72dbede3292613">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series consists of archived versions of one website created to serve as a messaging platform for NEA President Lily Eskelsen García.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_4b2b6563b27e7b14cc221dedd16cb85e" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Main Website</unittitle>
          <unitid>Series 4</unitid>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2015-07-06/2018-11-28" type="inclusive">Harvested multiple times between 6 July 2015 and 28 November 2018</unitdate>
          <langmaterial><language langcode="mul">Multiple languages</language>.</langmaterial>
        </did>
        <odd id="aspace_342ceed8088e087349664e0384ee17dd">
          <head>Link to web-based resource</head>
          <p>https://archive-it.org/collections/6009?fc=websiteGroup%3AMain+Website</p>
        </odd>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_3c1edba4ba71030909667ea549df5209">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series contains archived snapshots of the NEA's main website. Provides direct or near direct access to most other NEA websites, blogs and social media, major e-publications, member services, and resources. Major publications available through NEA.org include the annually published Rankings and Estimates of the States, NEA Today, affiliate communication guides, and various journals of higher education.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_27bc6542841129b6fcfa4abf315e0287" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Media</unittitle>
          <unitid>Series 5</unitid>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2015-07-06/2018-11-28" type="inclusive">Harvested multiple times between 6 July 2015 and 28 November 2018 </unitdate>
          <langmaterial><language langcode="mul">Multiple languages</language>.</langmaterial>
        </did>
        <odd id="aspace_b6bc3641b361e8b4420df2c3fd7fca2f">
          <head>Link to web-based resource</head>
          <p>https://archive-it.org/collections/6009?fc=websiteGroup%3AMedia</p>
        </odd>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_40889cde761f5548585b2ffceab279b9">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series contains archived snapshots of the web version of NEA Today, the NEA's primary external and member publication. The articles tend to focus on education policy, educators, and social issues. The articles are generally hyper-linked. Many of those links are to websites not operated by the NEA.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_dc6a9cfc1ac75ff8c0da0ee261635fb0" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Member Benefits</unittitle>
          <unitid>Series 6</unitid>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2015-07-06/2018-11-28" type="inclusive">Harvested multiple times between 6 July 2015 and 28 November 2018</unitdate>
          <langmaterial><language langcode="mul">Multiple languages</language>.</langmaterial>
        </did>
        <odd id="aspace_747678dc81e4d92eac9d3d3bd740ef0a">
          <head>Link to web-based resource</head>
          <p>https://archive-it.org/collections/6009?fc=websiteGroup%3AMember+Benefits</p>
        </odd>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_beea4a2bd689eb95f29bc31b4dbc7864">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series consists of archived snapshots of the website of the NEA's Member Benefits Corporation, a wholly-owned subsidiary of the NEA tasked with delivering a broad range of services and resources to NEA members. The website provides access to resources available to NEA membership. Many of the resources available on the original website can only be accessed through logging in and thus were not archived and are not available as part of this collection.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_26455f38b5653b2cb3f34fb58fb08179" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Professional Development</unittitle>
          <unitid>Series 7</unitid>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2015-07-06/2018-11-28" type="inclusive">Harvested multiple times between 6 July 2015 and 28 November 2018</unitdate>
          <langmaterial><language langcode="mul">Multiple languages</language>.</langmaterial>
        </did>
        <odd id="aspace_ba44425147898cb2530fe82cd8133185">
          <head>Link to web-based resource</head>
          <p>https://archive-it.org/collections/6009?fc=websiteGroup%3AProfessional+Development</p>
        </odd>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_0d69255709c45855c1e3b6073df4488b">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series consists of archived snapshots of websites created and operated by the NEA to provide resources to educators that allow them to continue their education, advance their careers, and take on new roles.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
