<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://library.gwu.edu/ead/ms2085.xml">ms2085.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Robert Ross papers, <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1813-1873</date>
 <num>MS2085</num></titleproper>
        <author>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2005</date>
        </p>
        <address>
          <addressline>2130 H Street NW</addressline>
          <addressline>Washington 20052</addressline>
          <addressline>speccoll@gelman.gwu.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-01-18 11:57:54 -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language encodinganalog="language">English</language></langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Robert Ross papers</unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <persname source="naf">Ross, Robert</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>MS2085</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate datechar="creation">1813-1873</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_b2ced08b9cde894a69d908f3c911c9da">Collection documents aspects of the military career of Major General Robert Ross. An apologia for the decision to burn public buildings in Washington emerges as a sub-theme. The Collection consists of one box. There are nine folders of manuscript materials {arranged in rough chronological order) and eleven folders of newspaper clippings.</abstract>
      <langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <prefercite id="aspace_7f2cbde2e7f7b8e32aee58f604244afa">
      <head>Preferred citation</head>
      <p>Robert Ross papers, Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_dcbd68825f087306a5215ff9a0328dc6">
      <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
      <p>Some records may be restricted.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_275d75a6f40906b74ced9de1f77c693e">
      <head>Restrictions on Use</head>
      <p>Some material may be copyrighted or restricted. It is the patron's obligation to determine and satisfy copyright or other case restrictions when publishing or otherwise distributing materials found in the collections.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <bioghist id="aspace_06c7a5db502dfd482687c51abf85631e">
      <head>Historical or Biographical Note</head>
      <p>Robert Ross (1766 - 1814) was born late in 1766 in Rosstrevor in the North of Ireland. The son of a British military officer, he followed in his father's profession and was commissioned an ensign in 1789. Ross moved up through the ranks, was decorated for his service, and was wounded more than once. His active service included battles in the Napoleonic Wars. In the Spring of 1813 he was granted the command of a brigade by the Duke of Wellington. Although almost fatally wounded early in 1814, Ross was selected for the command of an" expeditionary force against the coast of the United States. This force embarked on 1 June 1814. Its mission was to retaliate upon the Americans. After an engagement with the enemy at Bladensburg, on 24 August Ross moved on to Washington, D. C. His troops captured the city, and Ross then gave the command to burn almost all the public buildings.</p>
      <p>The next target was to be the city of Baltimore. It was while Ross was riding to this new front that he was mortally wounded on 12 September, 1814. His decision to destroy public property and to spare private property in Washington has long been a subject of debate. That controversy is reflected in this collection. Ross was buried in Nova Scotia, but a public monument to him was voted to be placed in St. Paul's Cathedral in London. </p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_c307cd218747552a7e85313cd6f8c1b2">
      <head>Collection Scope and Content</head>
      <p>The items in this collection relate in some way to the military career of Major General Robert Ross. An apologia for the decision to burn public buildings in Washington emerges as a sub-theme. The Collection consists of one box. There are nine folders of manuscript materials {arranged in rough chronological order) and eleven folders of newspaper clippings.</p>
      <p>The first two manuscript letters are signed by Frederick Augustus, Duke of York and Albany (1763 - 1827). The Duke of York was the second son of King George III of England and was the-brother of the Prince Regent (later King George IV). Both these letters are commendations to Ross for his bravery in the battles of Corunna and Vittoria and are dated 1813 and 1814 respectively. (These battles were part of the Penninsula Campaign during the Napoleonic Wars, and Ross was serving under . WelIington at the time). The letters were written at the command of his royal highness, the Prince Regent, on behalf of His Majesty (George III). In 18Q9 the Duke of York had been embarrassed by his involvement in a scandal with Mary Anne Clarke and was forced into a two year retirement. These letters show him back in favour as they are signed "Frederick, Commander in Chief", and they were written at the Horse Guards (located beside Whitehall). It is said that the position which the Duke of York held at the Horse Guards was always very important to him.</p>
      <p>The third manuscript is a letter written by Fitzroy Somerset, as military secretary to the Duke of Wellington, asking Robert Ross to take a brigade from Bordeaux to North America. Wellington had led his troops into battle near Toulouse in April, 1814, the same month that Napoleon abdicated. Almost immediately thereafter, some British troops were redeployed from Europe to Canada and the United States. This letter is dated "Toulouse, May 14, 1814". Somerset went on to fight heroically at Waterloo (where he lost an arm) and much later to gain notoriety as the unfortunate Raglan whose ambiguous orders led to the disastrous "Charge of the Light Brigade" during the Crimean War.</p>
      <p>Three of the remaining manuscripts are simply extractsfrom other sources. One is an account of the proceedings in the House of Commons in the Fall of 1814 when a monument to Boss in St. Paul's Cathedral was proposed. Another is a copy of a letter written by Ross' aide de camp, Duncan MacDougall, to the Times in 1861. This is a defense of Ross' actions in Washington, ancfV the content is important for its first-hand impressions of the capture of that city. The third item is a transcription of a section dealing with Ross in Washington from a French book on warfare: Precis de I'art de la guerre, by Baron Henri Jomini.</p>
      <p>The eleven folders of newspaper clippings are arranged in general subject order. The clippings reflect Ross' military campaign in North America, namely in the Washington, D. C. area. Many are disembodied, and the newspaper titles are hard to identify ' although they appear to be British. There is a moderate amount of duplication. </p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_4f4b69811520bb8113c5fd077904d146">
      <head>Collection Organization</head>
      <p>Organized into two series: Manuscripts and Clippings</p>
    </arrangement>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Peninsular War, 1807-1814</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Napoleonic Wars, 1800-1815</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Military</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Washington (D.C.)</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Great Britain</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">Vitoria, Battle of, Vitoria, Spain, 1813</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">La Coruña, Battle of, La Coruña, Spain, 1809</subject>
      <persname source="naf">Ross, Robert</persname>
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Frederick Augustus, Duke of York and Albany</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_ref11_iju" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Manuscripts</unittitle>
          <unitid>MS2085 Series 1</unitid>
          <unitdate datechar="creation">1813-1873</unitdate>
          <physdesc id="aspace_c78412583c9fe6e3a16163620ce16f34" label="General Physical Description note">0.5 Linear feet</physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_ec319ff1aed4159c9ac2672e29113024">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>This series consists of manuscripts. The first two manuscript letters are signed by Frederick Augustus, Duke of York and Albany (1763 - 1827). The Duke of York was the second son of King George III of England and was the-brother of the Prince Regent (later King George IV). Both these letters are commendations to Ross for his bravery in the battles of Corunna and Vittoria and are dated 1813 and 1814 respectively. (These battles were part of the Penninsula Campaign during the Napoleonic Wars, and Ross was serving under . WelIington at the time). The letters were written at the command of his royal highness, the Prince Regent, on behalf of His Majesty (George III). In 1809 the Duke of York had been embarrassed by his involvement in a scandal with Mary Anne Clarke and was forced into a two year retirement. These letters show him back in favour as they are signed "Frederick, Commander in Chief", and they were written at the Horse Guards (located beside Whitehall). It is said that the position which the Duke of York held at the Horse Guards was always very important to him. The third manuscript is a letter written by Fitzroy Somerset, as military secretary to the Duke of Wellington, asking Robert Ross to take a brigade from Bordeaux to North America. Wellington had led his troops into battle near Toulouse in April, 1814, the same month that Napoleon abdicated. Almost immediately thereafter, some British troops were redeployed from Europe to Canada and the United States. This letter is dated "Toulouse, May 14, 1814". Somerset went on to fight heroically at Waterloo (where he lost an arm) and much later to gain notoriety as the unfortunate Raglan whose ambiguous orders led to the disastrous "Charge of the Light Brigade" during the Crimean War. Three of the remaining manuscripts are simply extractsfrom other sources. One is an account of the proceedings in the House of Commons in the Fall of 1814 when a monument to Boss in St. Paul's Cathedral was proposed. Another is a copy of a letter written by Ross' aide de camp, Duncan MacDougall, to the Times in 1861. This is a defense of Ross' actions in Washington, ancfV the content is important for its first-hand impressions of the capture of that city. The third item is a transcription of a section dealing with Ross in Washington from a French book on warfare: Precis de I'art de la guerre, by Baron Henri Jomini.</p>
          <p>The materials range in date from 1813-1861.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="aspace_ref15_tz0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Frederick, Duke of York. Commander in Chief. LS. 2 pp. Horse Guards</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">09/21/1813</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_22aeeb23bad1020ed19db5cedb645e3e" label="Mixed Materials [32882018317621]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_8716460296ed38e615cf171415cd9ded" parent="aspace_22aeeb23bad1020ed19db5cedb645e3e" type="Folder">1</container>
          </did>
          <odd id="aspace_099663c37ba8105ab759b64c1c8c265b">
            <head>General note</head>
            <p>To Major General Robert Ross. Medal commemoration for service in the Battle of Corunna. Done on command of His Royal Highness, the Prince Regent, on behalf of His Majesty.</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref17_7pn" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Frederick, Duke of York. Commander in Chief. LS. 2 pp. Horse Guards</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">02/28/1814</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_eb9183612585455f636c368d51a6b965" label="Mixed Materials [32882018317621]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_9e13f94e94c640930e7171c6cc114c30" parent="aspace_eb9183612585455f636c368d51a6b965" type="Folder">2</container>
          </did>
          <odd id="aspace_4dc87b3e4ba240b555d00624a2739ecf">
            <head>General note</head>
            <p>To Major General Robert Ross. Medal commemoration for service in the Battle of 'Vittoria. Done on command of His Royal Highness, the Prince Regent, on behalf of His Majesty.</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref19_300" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Somerset, Fitzroy. Military secretary to Duke of Wellington. ALS. 2 pp. Toulouse</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">05/14/1814</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_44943aa4e0ded4ab13b4c266dba12b52" label="Mixed Materials [32882018317621]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_a1e215ae45ac93f530e31d7682b9768f" parent="aspace_44943aa4e0ded4ab13b4c266dba12b52" type="Folder">3</container>
          </did>
          <odd id="aspace_5a4af8e0a211539f8ab39ecdddff09ec">
            <head>General note</head>
            <p>To Major General Ross. Duke of York directed Duke of Wellington to offer Ross the command of a brigade in the expedition about to proceed from Bordeaux to America.</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref21_ve3" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Unknown handwriting. Ms. account of addressess in House of Commons 19 pp. (n.d.).</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">11/14/1814</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_c70f87f705f05ff86bd2f967ad643ecb" label="Mixed Materials [32882018317621]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_02a926c960ea0921cec0223d3c9cf6a5" parent="aspace_c70f87f705f05ff86bd2f967ad643ecb" type="Folder">4</container>
          </did>
          <odd id="aspace_c093b8a58d067492fd8e1b67e22fe128">
            <head>General note</head>
            <p>Extract Of proceedings during which Chancellor of Exchequer praised Ross and conveyed directions from the Prince Regent that a monument in Ross' memory be erected in St. Paul's Cathedral in London.</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref23_kbn" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Gorry, J. Secretary to the Committee. Ms. 2 leaves.</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">02/1815 ca.</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_d7dff352c21618b77f88e9c32fe0ab4e" label="Mixed Materials [32882018317621]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_8404efde09c4c90fd0bdbdacfe0a477b" parent="aspace_d7dff352c21618b77f88e9c32fe0ab4e" type="Folder">5</container>
          </did>
          <odd id="aspace_d566cc2cfa7d369a39f462d15b8b5104">
            <head>General note</head>
            <p>List of subscribers for fund to erect a monument to the memory of the late Major General Ross.</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref25_ot0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Unidentified source. Ms. 3 pp.</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_3b9061598e1a52dc1a628f19316d8206" label="Mixed Materials [32882018317621]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_b81813adf825700f879eb1e979706e34" parent="aspace_3b9061598e1a52dc1a628f19316d8206" type="Folder">6</container>
          </did>
          <odd id="aspace_2e2c98fdb420a1ba4116ff1c274019f1">
            <head>General note</head>
            <p>Includes descriptions of monuments to Major General Ross: one at the family seat in Rosstrevor, the other in St. Paul's Cathedral.</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref27_sh5" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Unidentified source. Letter written about proper spelling of Bladensburg. 2 pp.</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">07/11/1823</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_e52935c90eb77c76933aa56152615d54" label="Mixed Materials [32882018317621]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_17e146bcc9301a466a61aad3a4b9d3fe" parent="aspace_e52935c90eb77c76933aa56152615d54" type="Folder">7</container>
          </did>
          <odd id="aspace_95e4de85ebbebd8a30e7aff6ff310664">
            <head>General note</head>
            <p>Passing reference to proximity of that city to spot where General Ross was killed.</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref29_q5j" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Unknown handwriting. Ms. copy of letter of Duncan MacDougall, former aide to Ross. 13 pp</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">05/1861</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_8afdb1a5f0e27c68da8e9e7eeacdb876" label="Mixed Materials [32882018317621]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_b2febacfc01df8b236877aeb7506f8b1" parent="aspace_8afdb1a5f0e27c68da8e9e7eeacdb876" type="Folder">8</container>
          </did>
          <odd id="aspace_20c81d5e112715dbbfc3a081fda8b9f9">
            <head>General note</head>
            <p>To the Editor of "The Times". Defends conduct of Ross in America in response to article in "The Times". Quotes "National Intel Iigencer""c as confirmation of lack of plunder.</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref31_08s" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Unknown handwriting. Ms. extract from book by Baron Henri Jomini: "Precis de I"Art de la Guerre"</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">1830</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_35cdb9d37ce2586a8b75c635ece14a54" label="Mixed Materials [32882018317621]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_3ddb1eacbb4af5b46e0f2df50a8811ae" parent="aspace_35cdb9d37ce2586a8b75c635ece14a54" type="Folder">9</container>
          </did>
          <odd id="aspace_3a3b4083b929c91afa55ea88dd3a9b1b">
            <head>General note</head>
            <p>1 p. (n.d.) Jomini was a Swiss soldier who left Napoleon in 1814 and became aide to the Russian Emperor. This section of book deals with Ross in Washington.</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref34_296" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Clippings</unittitle>
          <unitid>MS2085 Series 2</unitid>
          <unitdate datechar="creation">1813-1873</unitdate>
          <physdesc id="aspace_3b9a7a5b3aaa51479303a88c6750a275" label="General Physical Description note">0.5 Linear feet</physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_88556bb82bfe878971267cf17971ae79">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>This series consists of eleven folders of newspaper clippings that are arranged in general subject order. The clippings reflect Ross' military campaign in North America, namely in the Washington, D. C. area. Many are disembodied, and the newspaper titles are hard to identify ' although they appear to be British. There is a moderate amount of duplication.</p>
          <p>The materials range in date from 1813-73. </p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="aspace_ref38_zij" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Military campaigns</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">1813</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_fbc90ca5109ce5b0caa0ad7bf1dc87ba" label="Mixed Materials [32882018317621]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_4d96b595d33c42063227a32d902225aa" parent="aspace_fbc90ca5109ce5b0caa0ad7bf1dc87ba" type="Folder">10</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref40_s1r" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Capture of Washington, 1</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_b748560c721ff3723670aaa073883246" label="Mixed Materials [32882018317621]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_0a9b4fa110cf8f3b568fa954ea57d867" parent="aspace_b748560c721ff3723670aaa073883246" type="Folder">11</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref42_2in" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Capture of Washington, 2</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_472a01987afd8b653d55d567c3761690" label="Mixed Materials [32882018317621]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_5de79fc503a3ff691146c05f79c93c9d" parent="aspace_472a01987afd8b653d55d567c3761690" type="Folder">12</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref44_fy8" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Death of Ross, 1</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_cc1e0fe1d039b39e20f7b6564bd7533b" label="Mixed Materials [32882018317621]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_dcdc5ef64985a14dda3324e29be7d25d" parent="aspace_cc1e0fe1d039b39e20f7b6564bd7533b" type="Folder">13</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref46_52i" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Death of Ross, 2</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_277a1be8ea6450757afd46fd5d6f79b8" label="Mixed Materials [32882018317621]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_79dcfbc1cda48b82df64d5a1fc40ace8" parent="aspace_277a1be8ea6450757afd46fd5d6f79b8" type="Folder">14</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref48_1zi" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Death of Ross, 3</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_09d9ad4c02c9acf463d4170cf8e8af0b" label="Mixed Materials [32882018317621]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_377848fd4a689f8ee1b29ca332398b29" parent="aspace_09d9ad4c02c9acf463d4170cf8e8af0b" type="Folder">15</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref50_0us" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Obituaries for Ross</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_7faf9ad8cbb4c44de16232d99bc73870" label="Mixed Materials [32882018317621]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_d968fb60a61ed95d007ff18eebdff38d" parent="aspace_7faf9ad8cbb4c44de16232d99bc73870" type="Folder">16</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref52_0zi" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Tributes to Ross 18 Poems</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_db89f56024cd11ee325fcfc74f1fc989" label="Mixed Materials [32882018317621]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_51b0a76da89fd7f8c1fcf3bcd9e5c24f" parent="aspace_db89f56024cd11ee325fcfc74f1fc989" type="Folder">17</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref54_u5r" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Poems</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_f1e526abde8dc69a1f7ef871b7afd3ea" label="Mixed Materials [32882018317621]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_bec13613375f950cd79bbdcee7afd5e9" parent="aspace_f1e526abde8dc69a1f7ef871b7afd3ea" type="Folder">18</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref56_izd" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Debate over burning of Washington</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_c5e2958510d0d5eb1abb34875764699e" label="Mixed Materials [32882018317621]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_c256f11011a562dcf05b1dd4bfe708d0" parent="aspace_c5e2958510d0d5eb1abb34875764699e" type="Folder">19</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref58_cey" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_667a6254d59b005737b21e8e1c5e16c1" label="Mixed Materials [32882018317621]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_3ce0dc417d6e8459dbb71c36459ae3ba" parent="aspace_667a6254d59b005737b21e8e1c5e16c1" type="Folder">20</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
