<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="https://searcharchives.library.gwu.edu/repositories/2/resources/495">ms2348.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Mark Penn polling data collection, <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1988-2008, 2019</date> <num>MS2348</num></titleproper>
        <author>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2019</date>
        </p>
        <address>
          <addressline>2130 H Street NW</addressline>
          <addressline>Washington 20052</addressline>
          <addressline>speccoll@gelman.gwu.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-01-18 12:03:05 -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language encodinganalog="language">English</language></langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Mark Penn digital polling data collection and oral history</unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <persname authfilenumber="https://lccn.loc.gov/n2007036022" role="dnr" rules="aacr" source="naf">Penn, Mark J</persname>
      </origination>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <persname authfilenumber="https://lccn.loc.gov/n2002090910" source="naf">Cornfield, Michael, 1955 -</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>MS2348</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">33 digital object(s)</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">33 digital files</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1988/2019" type="inclusive">1988-2008, 2019</unitdate>
      <physloc id="aspace_8976bff48a242739a9f275d5e47e1504">Materials are stored off-site, and will require additional retrieval time. Please contact the Special Collections Research Center for more information.</physloc>
      <abstract id="aspace_5d215527f7d458b28ed4d932d9954576">In 1975, Penn and Doug Schoen, founded the polling firm Penn Schoen Berland. Early clients included Ed Koch, Luis Herrera Campins in Venezuela, Menachem Begin for re-election as prime minister of Israel, President Bill Clinton, and British prime minister Tony Blair. Penn was a chief strategist and pollster in the Hillary Clinton 2008 presidential campaign. He has worked for Microsoft and is currently President and Managing Partner of The Stagwell Group, a private equity fund focused on the marketing services industry. This collection contains digital files with subject content of polling data for William Jefferson Clinton's presidency, the 2008 Hillary Clinton presidential campaign, and Labour Party polling as well as speeches, and debate preparation content. The materials cover 1988-2005 with the bulk of the data falling between 1996-2007. In addition, there is an oral history conducted in 2019 by GW professor Dr. Michael Cornfield with Mark Penn.</abstract>
      <langmaterial><language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_ae1cf7d3418dec414789c199f87d2848">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>This collection contains digital files with subject content of polling data for William Jefferson Clinton's presidency, the 2008 Hillary Clinton presidential campaign, and Labour Party polling as well as speeches, and debate preparation content. The materials cover 1988-2005 with the bulk of the data falling between 1996-2007. These twenty-eight original bound volumes and binders of weekly strategy session agendas (polling data, media records, policy discussion) were created by Mark Penn (DNC Pollster who worked with Bill Clinton during his years in office). In addition, is an oral history conducted in 2019 by GW professor Dr. Michael Cornfield with Mark Penn.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <custodhist id="aspace_3a2b8bdd8a3e3194ea26900d35ae1b13">
      <head>Custodial History</head>
      <p>Per the agreement with Mark Penn the bound volumes were provided to GW for digitization and then were returned to Mr. Penn.</p>
    </custodhist>
    <bioghist id="aspace_657eaa5d278fb6b0f61c11e2d28ac18b">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>Mark Penn grew up in Riverdale, NY. He graduated from the elite Horace Mann School in New York City in 1972 and Harvard University in 1976 with a degree political science. In 1975, Penn and Doug Schoen, founded the polling firm Penn Schoen Berland. Early clients included Ed Koch, Luis Herrera Campins in Venezuela, Menachem Begin for re-election as prime minister of Israel,
President Bill Clinton, and British prime minister Tony Blair. Penn was a chief strategist and pollster in the Hillary Clinton 2008 presidential campaign. </p>
      <p>In July 2012, Penn was named Corporate Vice President for Strategic and Special Projects at Microsoft Corporation. In 2015, Penn left Microsoft and created his own company called The Stagwell Group dealing with advertising and public relations. He is currently president and managing partner in this private equity fund focused on the marketing services industry. </p>
    </bioghist>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_3da59e68c29b7284eca31e6a8fa1a198">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>These files are available for research. At this time the pdf copies of the polling data do not meet GW University standards for accessibility compliance and have not been uploaded to the Internet. These files are available for use in our reading room and also researchers may ask for remote access copies by contacting Special Collection staff. The oral history has four parts and for the recordings for which the SCRC has a transcript the recording and transcript have been uploaded to the Internet. For part 3 of there recording please ask to listen in the reading room or for a copy to be provided to you as a remote user.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_27e46bd679defdc80f3a0a6698bb9d29">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
      <p>To the extent that he owns copyright, the donor has licensed his/her materials to be used according to the terms of the Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International
creative commons license. Copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For activities that the researcher determines fall under fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For re-use of materials in the collection not created by the donor, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights, determining if the intended re-use falls under fair use, and obtaining approval from the copyright holder if the intended use does not fall under fair use. Researchers do not need anything further from The George Washington University Special Collections Research Center. Please contact Special Collections if the copyright status of the materials you wish to reuse is unclear. Staff will provide additional information.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <arrangement id="aspace_caf9b23cc5a739ca6456ba90429f8b82">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>Organized in three series: HRC data index [Hillary Clinton polling data], William Jefferson Clinton polling data and Labour Party polling data, and Oral history [Mark Penn and Dr. Michael Cornfield]</p>
    </arrangement>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_9c94d5b0355fc54f2d847fbd771f25ca">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
      <p>Gift of Mark Penn February 27 2018 and September 9 2019 (accession 2019.010)</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_2da75d51abb776eaab3a02164670f180">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Please provide the title and date of item, catalog number (if applicable it will be found written on the folder), name of the collection, name of the repository, and location of the repository. Example: James Oglethorpe to the Trustees, 13 January 1876, RG0001 Series 1, Box 4, Folder 3. Records of the Board of Trustees, Special Collections Research Center, Gelman Library, The George Washington University, Washington, D.C.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85140410" source="lcsh">United States--Politics and government</subject>
      <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh2008002969" source="lcsh">Exit polling (Elections)</subject>
      <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85108738" source="lcsh">Public opinion polls</subject>
      <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85144428" source="lcsh">Voting research</subject>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_c47c7613fbf18dcfe14698b1a8fd6463" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>HRC data index [Hillary Clinton polling data]</unittitle>
          <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
          <unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1992/2008" type="inclusive">1992-2008</unitdate>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict id="aspace_e70889947aa9fae376076463ac5b7344">
          <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
          <p>These files are available for research. At this time the pdf copies of the polling data do not meet GW University standards for accessibility compliance and have not been uploaded to the Internet. These files are available for use in our reading room and also researchers may ask for remote access copies by contacting Special Collection staff.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <arrangement id="aspace_de25aa9ae71121d695d2098444a11a79">
          <head>Arrangement</head>
          <p>Arrangement maintains the original order with color-coded binders and separate bound volumes.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_74ff1f662a35d82c11f215475f0e9c10">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series contains digital files with polling data gathered for Hillary Clinton's 2008 presidential campaign. Some of this data is from previous campaigns and polls and was used as part of the campaign. These materials date from 1988-2008.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="aspace_c5e9ed9585aaf1afcda774500d74df05" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Yellow Binder 1.1: Polling Info (2008 Presidential Election): Iowa Tracker August 2007, National Tracker, Democratic Primary and General Election, July 2007, and Iowa Microtargeting Executive Summary July 2007</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2007/2007" type="inclusive">2007 July - August</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_5464e87a77b1f39b1a7955943e140ac5" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Yellow Binder 1.2: Polling Info (2008 Presidential Election): New Hampshire Tracker June 2007, National Tracker and Book Response June 2007, and South Carolina African American Poll May 2007</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2007/2007" type="inclusive">2007 May - June</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_a00af6f70d34a12dd4b8d060204d0cbb" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Yellow Binder 1.3: Polling Info (2008 Presidential Election): New Hampshire Microtargeting May 2007, National Tracker May 2007, and National Tracker April 2007</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2007/2007" type="inclusive">2007 April - May</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_6b32c92f5fbbd3e1c98b1c1d6515b140" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Yellow Binder 1.4: Polling Info (2008 Presidential Election): Primary State Polling South Caroline April 2007, Primary State Polling California April 2007, Primary State Polling Florida April 2007, Primary State Polling Iowa April 2007, and Primary State Polling Texas April 2007</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2007/2007" type="inclusive">2007 April</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_2f4c55b7c7ea49fe4b5f599aaab290e6" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Yellow Binder 1.5: Polling Info (2008 Presidential Election): National Heath Care Poll March 2007, National Tracker February 2007, and National Iraq Flash Poll February 2007</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2007/2007" type="inclusive">2007 February - March </unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_da96728ed8a6c86b74c2982a9ea4d7f3" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Yellow Binder 1.6: Polling Info (2008 Presidential Election): National Flash Poll February 2007, New Hampshire Benchmark January 2007, and Iowa Mini Flash Poll and Agenda January 2007</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2007/2007" type="inclusive">2007 January - February</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_286592ba98939791bac9c3c48cd1e5a8" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Yellow Binder 2: Polling Info (2008 Presidential Election): HRC National Polls</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2007/2007" type="inclusive">2007 July 31</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_6344f82bf9d0d007211dad128636a2b1" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Yellow Binder 3: Polling Info (2008 Presidential Election): HRC National Polls</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2007/2007" type="inclusive">2007 November</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_373dcfeaf5362de4f82f7487243443b0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Yellow Binder 4: Polling Info (2008 Presidential Election): PSB National Polls (For HRC)</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2007/2007" type="inclusive">2007 January - August</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_41e77aaa280a98019b6e25b4eead89e4" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Purple Binder 1: Misc. Materials (2008 Presidential Election): Hillary Clinton Debate Book</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2007/2008" type="inclusive">Circa 2007-2008</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_10036702e0ff3efa43b4ca99504451aa" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Purple Binder 2: Misc. Materials (2008 Presidential Election): Hillary Clinton Speeches/ Adwork/ Press Conferences</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2007/2008" type="inclusive">Circa 2007-2008</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_8146a7e6d9fd2d30fade5c80b4159378" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Purple Binder 3: Misc. Materials (2008 Presidential Election): Hillary Clinton Strategy Memos</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2007/2008" type="inclusive">Circa 2007-2008</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_0c51858b35250c9ce96a8ab380e41267" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Blue Binder 1: Polling Info (Pre-2008 Presidential Election): 1996 National Exit Polls</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1996/1996" type="inclusive">1996</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_f027b671bfd2d55e1e4eb8d5c23ca370" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Blue Binder 2: Polling Info (Pre-2008 Presidential Election): Misc. Exit polls</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1996/1998" type="inclusive">1996-1998</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_e9a6394985fefffe8c63a1c9edd6f08f" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Blue Binder 3: Polling Info (Pre-2008 Presidential Election): Gore Polling memos</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_8619e210ea5ac4cf1773f7d2cadda6eb" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Red Binder 1: Misc. Materials (Pre-2008 Presidential Election): Democratic Convention Summarys</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1988/1998" type="inclusive">1988-1998</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_f0c54545d5c10f6906f9ddda1a86c7e2" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Red Binder 2: Misc. Materials (Pre-2008 Presidential Election): '92 Presidential Debates Handbook</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1992/1992" type="inclusive">Circa 1992</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_30948dc2accf7be56106de0110ab4297" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Red Binder 3: Misc. Materials (Pre-2008 Presidential Election): "Hillary Clinton Senate Race Bible - Part I: the Old Testament (pre Lazio)"</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_8a67810ae5af993fde0aa689ccfabed2" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Red Binder 4: Misc. Materials (Pre-2008 Presidential Election): William J. Clinton Presidential History Project briefing materials</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_a5d886a0746df47ed5f7d8d8406b3554" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bound volume: Polls of Senator Hillary Clinton</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1999/1999" type="inclusive">1999 April - December</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_31923579128e5f98962b924b0498a18f" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bound volume: Polls of Senator Hillary Clinton</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2000/2000" type="inclusive">2000 January - May</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_d287ae302d3898eefcf20f732f2a26dc" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bound volume: Polls of Senator Hillary Clinton</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2000/2000" type="inclusive">2000 June - August</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_9a0f79a45d7602fc9e06d3570796cf46" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bound volume: Polls of Senator Hillary Clinton</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 1</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2000/2000" type="inclusive">2000 September - November</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_76029c2c8dc5773e34cc78c3288ed616" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>William Jefferson Clinton polling data and Labour Party polling data</unittitle>
          <unitid>MS2348 Series 2</unitid>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1997/2005" type="inclusive">1997-2005</unitdate>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="aspace_eebf1148071d63bdb69693b9406c8371">
          <head>Arrangement</head>
          <p>Arranged chronologically.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_980de81beae5c6cc52287082f3559768">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series contains digital files of bound volumes of William Jefferson Clinton polling data and Labour Party polling data. The materials date from 1997-2005.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="aspace_693b2750a5f8691218b88b7818d96b06">
          <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
          <p>These files are available for research. At this time the pdf copies of the polling data do not meet GW University standards for accessibility compliance and have not been uploaded to the Internet. These files are available for use in our reading room and also researchers may ask for remote access copies by contacting Special Collection staff.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <c id="aspace_7c8112c568efe85535f89210ea53c531" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bound volume: Polls of President William Jefferson Clinton</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 2</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1997/1997" type="inclusive">1997 January - December</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_24307bef1c6739d1f1d4455dad19a21b" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bound volume: Polls of President William Jefferson Clinton</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 2</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1998/1998" type="inclusive">1998 January - May</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_1c2cdbe75eca7e3d246ab8b4cc6cb248" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bound volume: Polls of President William Jefferson Clinton</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 2</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1998/1998" type="inclusive">1998 June - December</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_873e4aa1c81ca892226f44ae6a89435d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bound volume: Polls of President William Jefferson Clinton</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 2</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1999/1999" type="inclusive">1999 January - December</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_da3e2e868494eec48b29675936473d49" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bound volume: Polling: The Labour Party</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS2348 Series 2</unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2004/2005" type="inclusive">2004-2005</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_229fd3ea8adc84188afe516ed1b9bb98" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Oral history  [Mark Penn and Dr. Michael Cornfield]</unittitle>
          <unitid>Series 3</unitid>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019-05-15/2019-05-15">2019 May 15</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_ddb778d611ea714effecf5e127f05e7a">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series contains an oral history conducted by Dr. Michael Cornfield, Associate Professor and Research Director of the Global Center for Political Management, George Washington University with Mark Penn. The interivew took place on May 15, 2019.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <acqinfo id="aspace_4cb2f13a05de2d2813972e4464610532">
          <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
          <p>These recordings and transcripts were provided to the SCRC by Michael Cornfield. The file transfer included transcripts of parts 1, 2, and 4 and recordings of parts 2, 3, 4.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <processinfo id="aspace_e398a686fee734435b4fd698426f7524">
          <head>Processing Information</head>
          <p>The SCRC has asked Michael Cornfield for the recording for part 1 and the transcript for part 3 and will upload that content when provided by Dr. Cornfield.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <accessrestrict id="aspace_e0ece89ec39c9a0e769de3e2f0c55e76">
          <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
          <p>These files are open for use. The oral history has four parts and for the recordings for which the SCRC has a transcript the recording and transcript have been uploaded to the Internet. For part 3 of there recording please ask to listen in the reading room or for a copy to be provided to you as a remote user.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <c id="aspace_fcae8e3d05354e982f84a2d794db28f1" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Recordings</unittitle>
            <unitid>Series 3</unitid>
          </did>
          <c id="aspace_e6568d42c43c7cc0aa6c880129a64e8b" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Mark Penn interview (part 2)</unittitle>
              <unitid>Series 3</unitid>
              <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019-05-15/2019-05-15">2019 May 15</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_5ac6dc9b0aa13c9e92f7cbe956e397e2" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Mark Penn interview (part 3)</unittitle>
              <unitid>Series 3</unitid>
              <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019-05-15/2019-05-15">2019 May 15</unitdate>
            </did>
            <accessrestrict id="aspace_7d7c2cef7add0afeb382f0dbc7375d29">
              <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
              <p>This recording is available for using in the SCRC reading room or by requesting a digital copy from staff. At this time we are unable to upload this recording because we do not have a transcript.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_815ad30493d30f43939b11d3086b82fd" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Mark Penn interview (part 4)</unittitle>
              <unitid>Series 3</unitid>
              <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019-05-15/2019-05-15">2019 May 15</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_eec50166937fa86a273db47492467f92" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Transcriptions</unittitle>
            <unitid>Series 3</unitid>
          </did>
          <c id="aspace_91bee8eb20490de80571168ba74ac934" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Mark Penn interview transcript (part 1)</unittitle>
              <unitid>Series 3</unitid>
              <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019-05-15/2019-05-15">2019 May 15</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_681ce6e69967ff736e23615fa4103407" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Mark Penn interview transcript (part 2)</unittitle>
              <unitid>Series 3</unitid>
              <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019-05-15/2019-05-15">2019 May 15</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_3cbd55cf14ff33a62a62c9aa2d7a9393" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Mark Penn interview transcript (part 4)</unittitle>
              <unitid>Series 3</unitid>
              <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019-05-19/2019-05-19">2019 May 19</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
        </c>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
