<?xml version='1.0' encoding='LATIN-1'?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://library.gwu.edu/ead/rg0100.xml">rg0100.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Preliminary Guide to the Health Services Management and Policy Department records, <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1968-2000</date>
 <num>RG0100</num></titleproper>
        <author>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2007</date>
        </p>
        <address>
          <addressline>2130 H Street NW</addressline>
          <addressline>Washington 20052</addressline>
          <addressline>speccoll@gelman.gwu.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-01-11 11:52:41 -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language encodinganalog="language">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Health Services Management and Policy Department records</unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <corpname rules="aacr" source="local">George Washington University. School of Public Health and Health Services. Dept. of Health Services Management and Policy</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RG0100</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">79.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate datechar="creation">1968-2000</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_2c48dc3df4c60611b53f1dbf2cc2e44b">Materials in this collection include major reports (like theses), grant projects, and training books. They range in date from 1963-73.</abstract>
      <langmaterial><language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <prefercite id="aspace_958fb252e495734b80dc7e8c6945ee4d">
      <head>Preferred citation</head>
      <p>Health Services Management and Policy Department records, Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_2f99202da2b888a6a552185525d908a3">
      <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
      <p>Some records may be restricted.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_b4afecb2b9c8162a5913e9439675ce04">
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>Materials were transferred to the University Archives by the Chair of the Health Services Management and Policy Department.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <userestrict id="aspace_690f3e42bb4dd96e872261f009c1a281">
      <head>Restrictions on Use</head>
      <p>Some material may be copyrighted or restricted. It is the patron's obligation to determine and satisfy copyright or other case restrictions when publishing or otherwise distributing materials found in the collections.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <bioghist id="aspace_9d71d9d2957ee5ad0324000e851e2721">
      <head>Historical or Biographical Note</head>
      <p>The Health Services Management and Policy Department of The George Washington University was originally part of the School Of Business and Public Management. It grew out of the Heath Services Administration program begun in 1959 in the School of Government and Business Administration. It changed its name to Health Services Management and Policy in 1990. Richard Southby was the chairman of the department from 1983-97. The program is designed to prepare individuals for professional careers in managing and planning health services and in the development of health policies. </p>
      <p>The program was absorbed by the School of Public Health and Health Services, which was established within The George Washington University in 1997. SPHHS originally encompassed three departments of Public Health, which had been part of the School of Medicine and Health Sciences; Health Services Management and Policy, which had been part of the School of Business and Public Management; and Exercise Science, which had been part of the Graduate School of Education and Human Development. Now, seven departments form SPHHS: Environmental and Occupational Health, Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Exercise Science, Global Health, Health Policy, Health Services Management and Leadership, and Prevention and Community Health. </p>
      <p>Degree programs offered by SPHHS include three majors toward the Bachelor of Science: athletic training, exercise science, and public health; the Master of Public Health; the Master of Health Services Administration; the Master of Science in the fields of exercise science and health policy; and the Doctor of Public Health. SPHHS cooperates with several other schools within GW in offering joint and dual degree programs. Secondary fields for undergraduates in schools other than SPHHS and graduate certificate programs are offered as well. </p>
      <p> N.B. This history note was written in 2005</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_074ca1f60493eb137d06de549fbd4356">
      <head>Collection Scope and Content</head>
      <p>Materials in this collection include major reports (like theses), grant projects, and training books. They range in date from 1963-73, and were transferred to the University Archives by the Chair of the Health Services Management and Policy Department.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_783073b6c62d033cd762fd5aae92067f">
      <head>Collection Organization</head>
      <p>Organized into three series: Major reports (in lieu of theses) from the Health Care Administration Department/School of Government and Business Administration; Health Services records; and Reports on grant projects, training booklets.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Physical education and training</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Exercise science</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Health policy</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Public health</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Foggy Bottom (Washington, D.C.)</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Washington (D.C.)</geogname>
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">George Washington University. School of Public Health and Health Services</corpname>
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">George Washington University</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_ref10_z6m" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Major reports (in lieu of theses) from the Health Care Administration Department/School of Government and Business Administration</unittitle>
          <unitid>RG0100 Series 1</unitid>
          <unitdate datechar="creation">1968-1973</unitdate>
          <physdesc id="aspace_83db3af7fdf68070a35f0f6279c5f71a" label="General Physical Description note">77.5 Linear feet</physdesc>
          <container id="aspace_72e1233ff8087a907e54ddf4c787d12a" label="Mixed Materials [Series 1 GW: 32882017680276]" type="Box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_9fb263f537e66e0c120bcade3ca01f35">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>This series contains major reports (in lieu of theses) from the Health Care Administration Department/School of Government and Business Administration. They date from 1968 to 1973.</p>
          <p>Formerly ACC#223, 342</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="aspace_ref12_owl" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Alumni Medical - Health Services Management and Policy Program</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">1990-2000</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_d7d2811cdbf6c2a059c4bdfe3c50a3eb" label="Mixed Materials [Series 1 GW: 32882017680276]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_e7655f3e151ae66b43a2fe098b533416" parent="aspace_d7d2811cdbf6c2a059c4bdfe3c50a3eb" type="Folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref13_y45" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Health Service Administration/Health Services Management and Policy</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation">1977 ca.-01/15/1993</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_c4b210ae7ebfb6b6c8c48c65103343e1" label="Mixed Materials [Series 1 GW: 32882017680276]" type="Box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_f37c3ef884e9060cd741d735f5dd1485" parent="aspace_c4b210ae7ebfb6b6c8c48c65103343e1" type="Folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref15_fw3" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Health Services records</unittitle>
          <unitid>RG0100 Series 2</unitid>
          <unitdate datechar="creation">ca. 1977-2000</unitdate>
          <physdesc id="aspace_594fd31004fbd8ab3aa5deebbce778ed" label="General Physical Description note">.25 Linear feet</physdesc>
          <container id="aspace_418bfa10a677eb834f8d67dbf06cc40c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_0f981a7304aff256228f5596c2be8ef0">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>This series includes brochures, minutes, a new course form, a program, a student paper, and a news release. They range in date from approximately 1977 to 2000. They concern the Health Services Administration and the Alumni of the Health Services Management and Policy Program.</p>
          <p>Formerly vertical files</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref18_998" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Reports on grant projects, training booklets</unittitle>
          <unitid>RG0100 Series 3</unitid>
          <physdesc id="aspace_8b0449e39888b429a0dd2154fbb5e689" label="General Physical Description note">1.5 Linear feet</physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_1b822fc345999f6ef5acd9e395a2b456">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>This series contains reports on grant projects and training booklets from the School of Business and Public Management, Department of Health Services Management and Policy.</p>
          <p>Formerly ACC#560</p>
          <p>This series has a container list in electronic form, please ask staff for assistance.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
