<?xml version='1.0' encoding='LATIN-1'?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://library.gwu.edu/ead/map0001.xml">map0001.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Washingtoniana map collection, <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1630-2003</date>
 <num>MAP0001</num></titleproper>
        <author>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2006</date>
        </p>
        <address>
          <addressline>2130 H Street NW</addressline>
          <addressline>Washington 20052</addressline>
          <addressline>speccoll@gelman.gwu.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-01-11 11:32:05 -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language encodinganalog="language">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Washingtoniana map collection</unittitle>
      <unitid>MAP0001</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">50 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate datechar="creation">1630-2003</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_2474582144a0421da1148c63405e1c3b">The Washingtoniana Map Collection is an artificial collection created by the Special Collections Research Center from a variety of sources containing close to 400 maps of Washington, D.C. and its environs, including more detailed maps of particular locales such as Rock Creek Park, Georgetown, the Potomac River, and Alexandria, Virginia. The maps range in date from 1630 through 2004.</abstract>
      <langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <prefercite id="aspace_78c8f69952f9f28ead684357b421fa6d">
      <head>Preferred citation</head>
      <p>Washingtoniana map collection, Special Collections Research Center, Gelman Library, The George Washington University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_b2b4d66a0d84e3b86c6b86a62fdaaa3c">
      <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
      <p>Some records may be restricted.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_a42a6f1139d659b8da8920eb70ebfa7c">
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>These maps have been acquired over time.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <userestrict id="aspace_853d41b4e9e7e0e0ad448b8bc2498d7b">
      <head>Restrictions on Use</head>
      <p>Some material may be copyrighted or restricted. It is the patron's obligation to determine and satisfy copyright or other case restrictions when publishing or otherwise distributing materials found in the collections.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <bioghist id="aspace_1379c3d064c124ba54c85b850b00facd">
      <head>Historical  Note</head>
      <p>The Washingtoniana Map Collection is an artificial collection created by the Special Collections and University Archives from a variety of sources. </p>
      <p>A Southern site for the new country's capital was agreed upon at a dinner between James Madison and Alexander Hamilton, hosted by Thomas Jefferson. The city was designed by Pierre Charles L'Enfant, a Major in the United States Army. The initial plan for the "Federal District" was a diamond, measuring 10 miles (16 km) on each side, totaling 100 square miles (256 km). The actual site on the Potomac River was chosen by President Washington. Washington may have chosen the site for its natural scenery, believing the Potomac would become a great navigable waterway. </p>
      <p>The city was officially named "Washington" on September 9, 1791. Out of modesty, George Washington never referred to it as such, preferring to call it "the Federal City."[specify] Despite choosing the site and living nearby at Mount Vernon, he rarely visited the city.[specify] The federal district was named the District of Columbia because Columbia was a poetic name for the United States used at the time.</p>
      <p>Initially, the District of Columbia included four distinct sections, of which the city of Washington was only one. The others were Alexandria County, Georgetown, and the County of Washington. Georgetown occupied its current boundaries. Alexandria County included parts of the present-day City of Alexandria, as well as the current Arlington County, Virginia. Washington City occupied much of its current area but ended at present-day Rock Creek Park on the west and Florida Avenue and Benning Road on the north. Florida Avenue was then called "Boundary Street." The remainder of the district was Washington County.</p>
      <p>In 179192, Andrew Ellicott and the free African-American Benjamin Banneker surveyed the border of the District with both Maryland and Virginia, placing boundary stones at every mile point; many of these still stand.</p>
      <p>The cornerstone of the White House, the first newly constructed building of the new capital, was laid on October 13, 1792. That was the day after the first solemn celebrations of Columbus Day, marking its 300th anniversary.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_349091f6a115b4df92cd70e9fbe30087">
      <head>Collection Scope and Content</head>
      <p>The Washington, D.C. map collection includes more than 360 maps and other graphic materials documenting Washington, D.C. and the surrounding areas from 1693 through 2005. The collection includes maps documenting such information as street names and their layout, width of avenues, block and ward numbers, and locations of public schools, street railway, and bus lines. This collection is currently unprocessed. Please see staff for assistance.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_91cf90627ad36f8d8e25d7543cd7a9d9">
      <head>Collection Organization</head>
      <p>Organized into one series.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <controlaccess>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Rock Creek Park (Washington, D.C.)</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Potomac River</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Washington (D.C.)</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">Diseases</subject>
      <genreform source="aat">Historical maps</genreform>
      <subject source="lcsh">Parks</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Georgetown (Washington, D.C.)</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">Buses</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Sewerage</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Alexandria (Va.)</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">Bridges</subject>
      <genreform source="aat">Maps</genreform>
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">L'Enfant, Pierre Charles</persname>
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Banneker, Benjamin</persname>
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Ellicott, Andrew</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc/>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
