<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://library.gwu.edu/ead/mvc0016.xml ">mvc0016.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Elsie Foerderer correspondence collection, <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1935-1969</date> 
 <num>MVC0016.MS</num></titleproper>
        <author>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2010</date>
        </p>
        <address>
          <addressline>2130 H Street NW</addressline>
          <addressline>Washington 20052</addressline>
          <addressline>speccoll@gwu.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-05-18 14:45:16 -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language encodinganalog="language">English</language></langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Elsie Foerderer correspondence collection</unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <persname role="wam" rules="aacr" source="local">Foerderer, Elsie </persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>MVC0016.MS</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.25 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">1 slim document box</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1935/1969" type="inclusive">1935-1969</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_8d33a0a366b61bde66e0d05dba959947">Elsie Foerderer graduated from the Mount Vernon Seminary in 1909. She served as President of the Alumnae Association and an Alumna Trustee. She became a regular member of the Board of Trustees in 1936. The collection contains letters from Elsie to George Lloyd, Head of the College Division from 1932 to 1962 and President from 1936 to 1962, and Lloyd's wife, Olwen Lloyd. Olwen Lloyd served as Headmistress from 1938 to 1962.  In addition to these letters the collection has carbon copies of correspondence and telegrams from both Lloyds to Foerderer.  The other major correspondent found in the collection is Peter Pelham, President of Mount Vernon College from 1962 to 1976) These letters within this collection date from 1935-1969.</abstract>
      <physloc id="aspace_a365b75b5446eeaca5ee8b19c15202c8">Materials may be stored off-site, and may require additional retrieval time.  Please contact the Special Collections Research Center for more information.</physloc>
      <physdesc id="aspace_64bb3042b154a4696db9599860d3b284">Many of the letters are on acidic paper and are brittle.</physdesc>
      <langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist id="aspace_c6a4967e688e7fc94c6c8c334162a62e">
      <head>Biographical note</head>
      <p>Elsie Foerderer (b. September 1, 1890- d. June 25, 1969) graduated from the Mount Vernon Seminary in 1909.  In 1928 she became President of the Alumnae Association and an Alumna Trustee. She became a regular member of the Board of Trustees in 1936 and participated in organizing activities for the celebration of the centenary of founder Elizabeth Somers' birth and the memorial for Jean Dean Cole (Headmistress, 1924 – 1938; President, 1923 – 1936).  In 1941 she became Chair of the Board of Trustees and served in that capacity until 1949.  In that period she worked with the Headmaster, George Lloyd, to ensure that the Seminary continued to operate after the requisition in 1942 of the Nebraska Avenue by the Navy.  She participated in finding alternative housing for students and classroom space, at Spring Valley and the Garfinkel's building on Fordham Road, and after the war, was involved in the development of the new campus on Foxhall Road.  Foerderer retired from the Board in 1968, but was appointed honorary Trustee that year.  She died in Bryn Mawr, PA on June 25, 1969.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <prefercite id="aspace_d354070ced6038add272f4b717a34943">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Please cite unpublished materials in the following way:</p>
      <p>Please provide the title and date of item, catalog number (if applicable it will be found written on the folder), name of the collection, name of the repository, and location of the repository. </p>
      <p>Example:
James Oglethorpe to the Trustees, 13 January 1876, RG0001 Series 1, Box 4, Folder 3.  Records of the Board of Trustees, Special Collections Research Center, Gelman Library, The George Washington University, Washington, D.C.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <arrangement id="aspace_4c0c3b715ef14da383a7b0e0853ff50b">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>Arranged chronologically.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_7b9838733761bce472e5e2aade3c3678">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>This collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_07a5abc4f04078e28e688ca010e63878">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
      <p>Some material may be copyrighted or restricted. It is the patron's obligation to determine and satisfy copyright or other case restrictions when publishing or otherwise distributing materials found in the collections.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_a7ef18fb2865bad25247583f696c47e9">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
      <p>The source of this collection and when it came to the Mount Vernon College Archives is unknown.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_c4ca098671ea8309c946c8e7428cffb9">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>This collection contains the typed and handwritten letters to several important administrators at the Mount Vernon College and some of the carbon copy responses to Foerderer.  One of these correspondents was George Lloyd.  Lloyd served as Head of the College Division from 1932 to 1962 and President from 1936 to 1962.  The collection also contains letters to Lloyd's wife, Olwen Lloyd.  She served as Headmistress from 1938 to 1962.  In addition to the letters from Foerderer to the Lloyd's the collection has carbon copies of correspondence and telegrams from both Lloyds to Foerderer.  The other major correspondent found in the collection is Peter Pelham, President of Mount Vernon College from 1962 to 1976) and carbons and handwritten drafts of his correspondence to her.  These letters within this collection date from 1935-1969.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Correspondence</subject>
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">George Washington University. Mount Vernon Campus</corpname>
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Mount Vernon Seminary</corpname>
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Mount Vernon College</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_ref9_c7j" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitid>MVC0016</unitid>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1935/1941" type="inclusive">10/15/1935 – 10/31/1941</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_9833e11316e744067271d94ee509ad27" label="Text [32882014311362]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_f41ec7aaf0f89888ec0d2da1021fd914" parent="aspace_9833e11316e744067271d94ee509ad27" type="Folder">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_a665995f182555a4360496c76aa930fc">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Subjects of the letters include proposals for school building construction and repair, administrative issues including the planning for the Elizabeth Somers' centenary celebrations and the memorial to Jean Dean Cole, enrollments, alumnae relations, school menus, school curriculum changes and sponsoring of refugee children.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref11_d9c" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitid>MVC0016</unitid>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1943" type="inclusive">10/14/1941– 12/04/1943</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_64c66d1885de46055594582f2d3edbf4" label="Text [32882014311362]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_ab605c433578725701b581498bbe16a5" parent="aspace_64c66d1885de46055594582f2d3edbf4" type="Folder">2</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_0b1224bc85bcc5362bd36dcd57f21a8f">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Subjects of the letters include Olwen Lloyd's illness, issues of school administration and negotiations with the Navy following the requisition of the Nebraska Avenue campus and the relocation of the school. Interfiled in the correspondence for 1943 is an undated hand-written letter from a student, Gretchie Tiedeman, and a loose page from a report of expense for school operations.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref13_1tm" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitid>MVC0016</unitid>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1946" type="inclusive">12/10/1943 – 08/26/1946</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_12baf16b5005e6e5da5f57af722f5e25" label="Text [32882014311362]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_f7c19c07b36b3715e33d684628476c81" parent="aspace_12baf16b5005e6e5da5f57af722f5e25" type="Folder">3</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_5fca530d29b57626a8953458e32f8f5d">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Subjects of the letters included George Lloyd's illness, school administration, and plans for acquisition of a new campus site on Foxhall Road and construction there.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref15_iaa" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitid>MVC0016</unitid>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1969" type="inclusive">01/31/1946 – 06/30/1969</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_7ceb13fab01cf282ff16e72145ddd4db" label="Text [32882014311362]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_c04225ed9ed345d135f71ababcaa3635" parent="aspace_7ceb13fab01cf282ff16e72145ddd4db" type="Folder">4</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_815d94ef49db2fbba8d0d62efcb77759">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Subjects of the letters concern school administration, including carbons of an unsent and a sent resignation letter from Lloyd to the Board of Trustees and correspondence between Peter Pelham and Elsie Foerderer. Also included are two handwritten letters sent to Elsie Foerderer from Mount Vernon Seminary alumnae.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
