<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://library.gwu.edu/ead/ms2284.xml">ms2284.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the T. Patrick Washington spoken word poetry flyer and photograph collection, <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1996-2005</date>
 <num>MS2284</num></titleproper>
        <author>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2010</date>
        </p>
        <address>
          <addressline>2130 H Street NW</addressline>
          <addressline>Washington 20052</addressline>
          <addressline>speccoll@gelman.gwu.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/contact" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-01-18 12:01:49 -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language encodinganalog="language">English</language></langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>T. Patrick Washington spoken word poetry flyers and photograph collection</unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <persname role="dnr" rules="aacr" source="local">Washington, T. Patrick</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>MS2284</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 folder(s)</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1996/2005" type="inclusive">1996-2005</unitdate>
      <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1999/2000" type="bulk">1999-2000</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_45c9bd98ad5a9f238e8c504f2996fa83">This collection contains flyers and brochures from spoken word poetry events in washington, D.C. The collection also includes one image of local spoken word poets. The image was taken in the late 1990s. These material dates from 1996-2005. These items were compiled by Washington D.C. spoken word poet, T. Patrick Washington, also know as Black Picasso.</abstract>
      <physloc id="aspace_d9609360e59a134915e1c1c388ae5c40">Materials may be stored off-site, and may require additional retrieval time.  Please contact the Special Collections Research Center for more information.</physloc>
      <langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <arrangement id="aspace_5ede463809f1db307ad7ff9ed8a3cb5c">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>Arranged chronologically.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_151e009673566b9c3355a5fa7e796018">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>This collection contains flyers and brochures from spoken word poetry events in washington, D.C. The collection also includes one image of local spoken word poets. The image was taken in the late 1990s. These material dates from 1996-2005. These items were compiled by Washington D.C. spoken word poet, T. Patrick Washington. The flyers advertise events for groups such as Poem-Cees and Generation 2000, a spoken-word collective, as well as other performers and open-mic events throughout the city.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_c579b42cf75c9a0a16374196021a9635">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>This collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_ea8f5dfefb62a339d6f5e9bf50688a91">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
      <p>Gift of T. Patrick Washington, March 18, 2010 (2010.013).</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_4675e58540a3faff1d515f2f6fa78912">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Please cite unpublished materials in the following way:</p>
      <p>Please provide the title and date of item, catalog number (if applicable it will be found written on the folder), name of the collection, name of the repository, and location of the repository. </p>
      <p>Example:
James Oglethorpe to the Trustees, 13 January 1876, RG0001 Series 1, Box 4, Folder 3.  Records of the Board of Trustees, Special Collections Research Center, Gelman Library, The George Washington University, Washington, D.C.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <bioghist id="aspace_0b64bb64e137695d1609e866d425a344">
      <head>Biography</head>
      <p>Patrick Washington is a D.C. spoken-word poet.  He has been performing spoken-word poetry in the Washington D.C. area since the mid-1990s.  He is known as Black Picasso.  Black Picasso along with Darrell Perry (Naturalaw) and Rhome Anderson (DJ Stylus) form the performance group Poem-Cees.  Poem-Cees came out of Washington's hip-hop community that grew up in the mid-1990s much of it around the cultural and commerical revival of U Street.  It was at this time that two communities coverged poets and spoken-word artists in many open mic opportunities in the city. Poem-Cees is often thought of as a bridge between the structure and mature subject matter of poetry and the groove and energy of hip-hop.</p>
      <p>From Pome-Cees' Myspce page, from April 9, 2010: http://www.myspace.com/poemcees</p>
      <p>Since 1998, POEM-CEES have combined rhyme, prose and community activism to emerge at the cutting edge of the vibrant Washington, DC Arts Movement. Naturalaw-dp &amp; Black Picassos talents were forged in the crucible of the spoken word movement; as founding members of the now defunct Generation 2000 poetry collective, they toured and performed at colleges and universities as well as recorded songs for BET &amp; Emerge magazines nationally distributed Strength of a Woman cd. Invitations to open for such acts as the Roots, the Fugees and the Last Poets led to the addition of DJ Stylus and the band, and thus the lean and mean POEM-CEES unit was formed. The year 2000 brought forth their debut album, I.O.U. Street, a whirlwind tour through the open mic, hip-hop, drum &amp; bass, and funk scenes along DCs historic U Street corridor.</p>
      <p>The Spring 2003 release of Paranoia continued the POEM-CEES tradition of pushing the boundaries of contemporary hip-hop music. Conceived prior to the 9/11 tragedies, Paranoia avoids clichés yet remains amazingly prescient by focusing on the various manifestations of paranoia in our lives. From casual conversations on cold feet in a relationship (SIWBY) to hilariously extreme outbursts &amp; episodes ("Cheatin on Me" &amp; "Fat White Men in Suits") the Paranoia project runs the gamut of emotions, ultimately standing as the rarest of the rare: a well-executed, non-self indulgent concept record that may be digested in segments or as a whole (translation: its a very, very good cd).</p>
      <p>The past six years have seen NatLaw, Pic! &amp; Stylus grow as artists, as people, &amp; as businessmen, having released their 3 Piece/Extra Mambo Series and launched SPP WAXWORKS together with their comrades Storm the Unpredictable &amp; Priest da Nomad. Now 2010 will bring them right back to the forefront with their newest CD release "EVERYTHING YOU'VE ALWAYS WANTED" and their legendary live performances that showcase their strengths - making good music and telling the common story in uncommon ways. </p>
    </bioghist>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Performance poetry</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Hip-hop -- Poetry</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Poetry</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Oral interpretation of poetry</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Poetry -- 21st century</subject>
      <corpname role="mus" rules="aacr" source="naf">Poem-cees (Musical group) -- History</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_ref9_1rk" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>spoken word poetry event flyers</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1996/2005" type="inclusive">1996-2005, undated</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_66e2d86a4275ceacfb1b070d164bbc9a" label="Mixed Materials [32882019751836]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_86adeeb3c1096c087f5a7082af0d5c27" parent="aspace_66e2d86a4275ceacfb1b070d164bbc9a" type="Folder">1</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref10_c9c" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Photograph</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1999/1999" type="inclusive">1999</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_15da87bd373ecdaa83dfa7f3e84f2597" label="Graphic Materials [32882019751836]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_99122fdedcacdf3510c43438e035b6ef" parent="aspace_15da87bd373ecdaa83dfa7f3e84f2597" type="Folder">2</container>
        </did>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
